<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="chapter" n="3">
   <head>Chapter III</head>
   <p>P. D. MCPHERSON, or <q>P. D.</q> as he was better known throughout the ranching country, owner of the O Bar O, was noted for his eccentricities, his scientific experiments with stock and grain, and for the variety and quality of his vocabulary of <q>cusses</q>.</p>
   <p>An ex-professor of an Agricultural College, he had come to <placeName ref="plc:AB1">Alberta</placeName> in the early days, before the trails were blazed. While the railroads were beginning to survey the new country, he had established himself in the foothills of the <placeName>Rocky Mountains</placeName>.</p>
   <p>Beginning with a few head of cattle imported from the East, P. D. had built up his herd until it was famous throughout the cattle world. His experiments in crossing pure-bred grades of cattle in an attempt to produce an animal that would give both the beef of the Hereford and the butterfat and cream of the <pb n="30"/>Holstein, had been followed with unabated interest.<note type="editorial">See Margaret Derry, <title level="m">Masterminding Nature</title>.</note></p>
   <p>He had been equally successful with his horses and other stock. Turning from cattle and stock, P. D. next expended his genius upon the grain. It was a proud and triumphant day for O Bar O when, at the annual <term>Calgary Fair</term>, the old rancher showed a single stalk of wheat, on which were one hundred and fifty kernels.</p>
   <p>His alfalfa and rye fields, in a normally dry and hilly part of the country, were the wonder and amazement of farmers and ranchers.</p>
   <p>The Government, the Railways, the Flour mills and the Agricultural Colleges, sought him out, and made tempting offers to induce him to yield up to them his secrets.</p>
   <p>P. D. stroked his chin, pinched his lower lip, drew his fuzzy eyebrows together, and shook his fine, shaggy old head. He was not yet satisfied that his experiments had reached perfection.</p>
   <p>He'd <q>think it over</q>. He’d <q>see about it some day, maybe</q>, and he <q>wasn’t so damned cussed sure that it would benefit the world to<pb n="31"/> produce cheap wheat at the present time. This way out, gentlemen! This way out!</q></p>
   <p>He was a rude old man, was P. D. McPherson,</p>
   <p>In a way, he was obliged to be so, for otherwise he would have been enormously imposed on. O Bar O was in the heart of the game and fishing country, and was, therefore, the mecca of all aspiring hunters and fishermen, to say nothing of the numerous campers and <term>motor hoboes</term>, who drove in every day upon the land and left their trail of disorder and dirt behind, and quite often small or large forest fires, that were kept under control only by the vigilance of O Bar O.</p>
   <p>The ranch was noted for its hospitality, and no tramp or stranger or rider along the trail had ever been turned from its door. The line, however, had to be drawn somewhere, and it was drawn in so far as the idle tourists, pausing en route to <placeName>Banff</placeName> or <placeName>Lake Louise</placeName> to <q>beat</q> a meal<note type="editorial">I.e. ???</note> or a pleasant day at the ranch, were concerned, or the numerous motor hoboes, who, denied at the ranch house their numerous<pb n="32"/> requests for milk and eggs and gasol<choice><orig>e</orig><reg>i</reg></choice>ene and the privilege of spending the night there, slipped in under the bridge by the river, and set up their camps on the banks of the <placeName>Ghost River</placeName>.</p>
   <p>About the time when his wheat had brought him considerable, but undesired, fame, P. D., holding his lower lip between thumb and forefinger, was looking about for new experimental worlds to conquer. By chance, his motherless son and daughter,<note type="editorial">This is the first mention of the <q>motherless</q> status of Hilda and Sandy.</note> then of the impressionable ages of four and ten respectively, shot under his especial notice, through the medium of a ride down the bannister and resultant noise.</p>
   <p>P. D. studied his offspring appraisingly and thoughtfully, and as he looked into the grimy, glooming young faces, he conceived another one of his remarkable <q>inspirations</q>.</p>
   <p>It was soon after this, that P. D. founded that <q>School of Nature</q>, to which were bidden all of the children of the neighbouring ranch country, and into which his own progeny were unceremoniously dumped.</p>
   <pb n="33"/>
   <p>However, when the curriculum of this Institution of Learning became more fully understood, despite the fame of its founder and president, there were none among the parents of the various children who felt justified in sending them to the O Bar O School of Nature.</p>
   <p>Even the most ignorant among them believed that school existed only mainly for the purpose of teaching the young minds how to shoot with reading, writing, spelling and arithmetic.</p>
   <p>P. D. proposed only the slightest excursion into these elementary subjects. Nature, so he declared, addressing the assembled farmers at a special meeting, was the greatest of all teachers, a book into which one might look, without turning a single leaf, and learn all that was necessary for the knowledge of mankind.<note type="editorial">The School of Nature bears resemblance to the educational systems proposed by various Transcendantalists, like Emerson and Amos Bronson Alcott.</note></p>
   <p>He was convinced, so eloquently proclaimed P. D., that school such as the world knew it, was antiquated in its methods and wholly unnecessary and wrong. To teach the young the secrets and mysteries of nature—that alone<pb n="34"/> was needed to produce a race of supermen and women.<note type="editorial">The figure of the superman or the <q>Ubermensch</q> is ... </note></p>
   <p>One timid little woman arose, and asked what <q>supermen</q> meant, and the huge, rough father of the family of ten replied that it meant <q>men who liked their supper</q>.</p>
   <p>The meeting broke up in a riot—so far as P. D. was concerned, and his neighbours departed with his wrathful imprecations ringing in their ears.</p>
   <p>Not to be daunted by the lack of support afforded him by his neighbours, P. D. set at once to put his theories into practice upon his helpless children.</p>
   <p>It came to pass that the children of P. D. missed the advantages of the ordinary modern schools. Had P. D., in fact, carried out his original curriculum, which he prepared with scientific detail, it is quite possible that the results might have turned out as satisfactorily as his experiments with cattle, pigs, sheep and horses. P. D. reckoned not, however, with the vagaries and impetuosities of youth and human nature. Unlike dumb stock, he had fiery<pb n="35"/> spirits, active imaginations, and saucy tongues to deal with. He was not possessed with even the normal amount of patience desirable in a good teacher. His classes, therefore, were more often than not punctuated by explosive sounds, miraculous expletives, indignant outcries, and the ejection or hurried exit from the room of a smarting, angry-eyed youngster, suffering from the two-fold lash of parental tongue and hand.</p>
   <p>Then when some of his original ideas were just beginning to take substantial root in their young minds and systems, P. D. fell a victim to a new and devastating passion, which was destined to hold him in thrall for the rest of his days.</p>
   <p>Chess was his new mistress, alternately his joy and his bane. Even his children were forgotten in the shuffle of events, and, turned upon their own resources, they grew up like wild young things, loose on a great, free range.</p>
   <p>If, however, the young McPhersons had missed school, they had learned much of which the average child of to-day is more or less igno<pb n="36"/>rant. They knew all of the theories concerned in the formation of this earth of ours, and the living things upon it. They were intimately acquainted with every visible and many invisible stars and planets in the firmament. They had a plausible and a comprehensible explanation for such phenomena as the milky way, the comets, the northern lights, the asteroids and other denizens of the miraculous Alberta sky above them. They knew what the west, the east, the north and the south winds portended. They could calculate to a nicety the distance of a thunderstorm. No mean weather prophets were the children of P. D. McPherson; nor were their diagnosis dependent upon guess-work, or an aching tooth, or rheumatic knee, or even upon intuition or superstition, as in the case of the Indian.</p>
      <p>Woodlore they knew, and the names and habits of the wild things that abounded in the woods of O Bar O. Insects, ants, butterflies, bees, were known by their scientific names. A rainbow, a sunrise, sunset, the morning mist, fog, the night sun of Alberta, the Japanese current that brought the Chinook winds over the Rocky Mountains, that changed the weather from thirty below zero to a tropical warmth in Alberta, the melting clouds in the skies, the night rainbows—all these were not merely beautiful phenomena, but the rest of natural causes, of which the McPherson children able to give an intelligent explanation.<note type="editorial">NOTE HERE ABOUT ANTHROPOLOGY; INDIGENOUS MODES OF KNOWING; SEE COYOTE.</note></p>
   <p>They could ride the range and wield the <term ref="gls:lari1">lariat</term> with the best of the cowpunchers. Hilda could brand, vaccinate, dehorn, and wean cattle. She was one of the best brand readers in the country, and she rode a horse as if she were part of the animal itself. She could leap with the agility of a circus rider upon the slippery back of a running outlaw, and, without bridle or saddle, maintain her place upon a jumping, bucking, kicking, wildly rearing <q>bronc</q>.</p>
   <p>Untamed and wild as the mavericks that, eluding the lariat of the <term>cowpuncher</term>, roamed the range unbranded and unbroken, Hilda and Sandy McPherson came up out of their childhood years, and paused like timid, curious<pb n="38"/> young creatures of the wild upon the perilous edge of maturity.</p>
   <p>Hilda was not without a comprehension of certain things in life that had been denied her. If her heart was untamed, it was not the less hungry and ardent. Though she realized that she had missed something precious and desirable in life, she was possessed with a spartan and sensitive pride. About her ignorance, she had erected a wall of it.<note type="editorial">I.e. she erected a wall of ignorance around her.</note></p>
   <p>It was all very well to ride thus freely over the splendid open spaces and to wend her fearless way through the beckoning woods of the Rocky Mountain foothills. It was fine to be part of a game which every day showed the results of labour well done, and to know that such labour was contributing to the upkeep and value of the world. Yet there were times when a very wistful expression of wonder and longing would come into the girl’s dark eyes,<note type="editorial">This is one of the only times in which a female character in Eaton's novels has <q>dark eyes</q>. [[LONGER NOTE W REFERENCE TO JLC RE: VARIOUS EYE COLOURS]].</note> and the craving for something other than she had known would make her heart burn within her.</p>
   <p>To appease this heart hunger, Hilda sought<pb n="39"/> a medium through the reading matter obtainable at O Bar O; but the reading matter consisted of the Encyclopædia Brittanica, Darwin’s <q>Origin of the Species</q>, several scientific works, and two voluminous works on the subject of chess.</p>
   <p>For a time, the Encyclopædia afforded sufficient material to satisfy at least her curiosity; but presently a new source was tapped. From the bunkhouse came <term ref="gls:dime1">dime novels</term> and the banned newspapers, which P. D. had more than once denounced as <q>filthy truck fit for the intelligence of morons only</q>. Besides these were the <title level="m">Police Gazette</title>, two or three penny dreadfuls, <title level="m">Hearsts</title>’<note type="editorial">[[NOTE ABOUT HEARSTS AND HOW WINNIFRED OFTEN PUBLISHED IN THEM. LINK TO WEA'S HEARST CAT.]]</note>, and several lurid novels of the blood-and-thunder type.<note type="editorial">GLOSS BLOOD AND THUNDER.</note> This precious reading matter, borrowed or <q>swiped</q> by Sandy and Hilda, while the men were on the range, was secretly devoured in hayloft and other secure places of retreat, and made a profound impression upon their eager young minds.</p>
   <pb n="40"/>
</div>
