<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="chapter" n="23">
            <head>Chapter XXIII</head>
            <p><hi rendition="#smallcaps">MIGHTY</hi> panorama of golden hills swelled			
<lb/>like waves on all sides and vanished into cloud<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>like outlines of yet higher hills that zigzagged			
<lb/>across the horizon and merged in the west into			
<lb/>that matchless chain of rugged peaks. Snow			
<lb/>crowned, rosy under the caress of the slowly			
<lb/>sinking sun, bathed in a mystic veil of gilded			
<lb/>splendour, the Canadian Rockies were printed			
<lb/>like an immense masterpiece across the west<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ern sky.</p>
            <p>Hilda rode slowly along, her gaze pinned			
<lb/>upon the hills. Yet of them she was thinking			
<lb/>but vaguely. They were a familiar and well<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>loved presence that had been with them al<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ways. To them she had turned in all her girl<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ish troubles. To them she had whispered her			
<lb/>secrets and her dreams.</p>
            <p>As she rode on and on, her thoughts were			
<lb/>all of those strange evenings in the company			
<lb/>of this man—the too-short, electrical half hour</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 261 ]</fw>
            <pb n="262"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>or so when they would be alone together before</p>
            <p>her father awoke.</p>
            <p>Her reins hung loose over her horse’s neck;			
<lb/>her hands were in the pockets of her hide coat;			
<lb/>her head slightly bent, Hilda gave herself up			
<lb/>to a long, aching, yet singularly glowing day			
<lb/>dream. Daisy made her own trail, idly loping			
<lb/>along above the canyon that skirted the Ghost			
<lb/>River, stopping now and then to nibble at the			
<lb/>sweet grass along the paths.</p>
            <p>The woods were very still and lovely. Wide			
<lb/>searchlights of the remaining sunshine pierced			
<lb/>through the branches of the trees and flickered			
<lb/>in and out of the woods, playing in golden,			
<lb/>dancing gleams upon the green growth.</p>
            <p>Brown and gold, deeply red, burnt yellow,			
<lb/>and green, the trees were freighted with glori<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ous beauty. Masses of the leaves fluttered idly			
<lb/>to the ground, moved by the soft fragrant			
<lb/>breeze and the branches on bush and tree			
<lb/>seemed lazily to shake themselves, as if suc<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>cumbing unwillingly to the slumberous spell			
<lb/>of the quiet Autumn day.</p>
            <p>The flowers beneath the trees still shone,</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 262 ]</fw>
            <pb n="263"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>their radiance but slightly dulled by the touch			
<lb/>of the night frosts, seeming lovelier indeed, as			
<lb/>if veiled by some softening web-like touch.			
<lb/>Scarlet and bright, all through the wooded			
<lb/>growth, the wild-rose berries grew.</p>
            <p>Coveys of partridge and pheasants fluttered			
<lb/>among the bush, peeked up with bright, in<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>quiring eyes at the girl on horse, then hopped			
<lb/>a few paces away, under the thick carpet of			
<lb/>leaves.</p>
            <p>In an open field, swiftly running horses			
<lb/>raced to meet them. Like playful children,			
<lb/>they ran around and in front and on all sides			
<lb/>of Hilda’s mare, thrusting their noses against			
<lb/>hers, and laying their faces across her slender			
<lb/>back, utterly unafraid of the rider, yet timor<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ous and moving at Hilda’s slightest affection<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ate slap or word of reproval when they pressed			
<lb/>too closely.</p>
            <p>She was off again. This time a race across			
<lb/>a wide pasture and into the hills to the west,			
<lb/>turning at the end of a long, wooded climb up —			
<lb/>an almost perpendicular slope, to come out			
<lb/>upon the top of one hill, to climb still higher</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 263 ]</fw>
            <pb n="264"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>to another, into a wide, open space, and again			
<lb/>to a higher hill, till, suddenly, she seemed to be			
<lb/>on the very top of the world.</p>
            <p>Below her, nestling like a small city, the			
<lb/>white and green buildings of the ranch showed.			
<lb/>Very near it seemed, and yet in fact a distance			
<lb/>of two or three miles. From this highest			
<lb/>point, the girl on horse paused to cast a long,			
<lb/>lingering look over the surrounding country			
<lb/>that lay spread below her.</p>
            <p>To the north were dim woods, thick and			
<lb/>dark. An eagle soaring overhead.</p>
            <p>To the east, the wide-spreading pastures			
<lb/>and the long, trailing road to Banff. Dim			
<lb/>forms of cattle and horse observable in the			
<lb/>still lingering light, moving specks upon the			
<lb/>gracious meadows.</p>
            <p>To the south, the lower chain of hills and			
<lb/>the sheep lands. A coyote’s wild moaning call.			
<lb/>A hawk circling toward the ranch house.</p>
            <p>Shining like a jewel in the mellow glow, the			
<lb/>long, sinuous body of the Bow River, rushing			
<lb/>swiftly to make its junction with the more leis<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>urely flowing Ghost, upon whose surface the</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 264 ]</fw>
            <pb n="265"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>logs from the Eaue Claire Lumber Camp were			
<lb/>being borne by the hundreds upon the first lap			
<lb/>of their journey to Calgary.</p>
            <p>In the West, hill upon hill and still farther			
<lb/>hill upon hill, and beyond all, the snow			
<lb/>crowned, inescapable immortal range of			
<lb/>Rocky Mountains, a dream, a miracle, emble<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>matic of eternity and peace.</p>
            <p>It was hard indeed to tear her gaze from			
<lb/>the last lingering gleams of that marvellous			
<lb/>sunset. There was that about it that uplifted			
<lb/>and comforted the aching heart. Hilda sighed			
<lb/>and at last her long gaze was reluctantly with<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>drawn, dropped lower over the hill tops, the			
<lb/>woods, and came to rest, alertly and still, upon			
<lb/>a moving shadow that slipped in and out of			
<lb/>the bush in a direct line with the barbed wire			
<lb/>fencing.</p>
            <p>She rode slowly, leisurely, but her reins			
<lb/>were now in her hands. In all her young life,			
<lb/>Hilda McPherson had known not the mean<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing of the word fear. Anger, pain, pity and			
<lb/>now love, had shaken her soul, but of fear she			
<lb/>knew nothing. That anyone should wish to</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 265 ]</fw>
            <pb n="266"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>harm her, was beyond her comprehension. So			
<lb/>she rode forward quietly, almost indifferently.			
<lb/>Nevertheless, Hilda knew that someone was			
<lb/>trailing her. An O Bar O <q>hand</q> or a neigh<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>bour would have come out into the open.			
<lb/>Whoever was following her was keeping pur<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>posely under the shadow of the bush. Nor			
<lb/>could it be an Indian. Hilda knew the			
<lb/>Stoneys well. An Indian does not molest a			
<lb/>white woman.</p>
            <p>She pondered over the purpose of the man			
<lb/>who was following her. What did he want?			
<lb/>Why did he not come out into the open?			
<lb/>Thieves and rustlers would not have ventured			
<lb/>as near to the ranch house asthis. Their work			
<lb/>was upon the range.</p>
            <p>Hilda’s horse was now climbing down the			
<lb/>other side of the hill slope, directly toward the			
<lb/>ranch. O Bar O was fenced and cross-fenced			
<lb/>with four wires, every field being laid out for			
<lb/>especial stock. In a country like Alberta,			
<lb/>where ranching is done on a large scale, stock			
<lb/>are seldom penned in barn or stable. They			
<lb/>are loose upon the range. Between each field,</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 266 ]</fw>
            <pb n="267"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>antiquated barbed wire gates were kept tightly			
<lb/>closed. These were difficult to open. They			
<lb/>consisted of three or four strands of barbed			
<lb/>wire nailed to light willow fence posts at a			
<lb/>space of about a foot apart. These swung			
<lb/>clear from the ground and when closed			
<lb/>fastened by a loop of the wire to the stout post			
<lb/>at the end of the fencing. They were nasty			
<lb/>things to open, even for the toughened hands			
<lb/>of the cowboy. Hilda. seldom used these			
<lb/>gates. She would go around by the paths that			
<lb/>opened to the main trails where were the great			
<lb/>gates that swung from their own weights and			
<lb/>were made of posts ten feet long. These, how<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ever, were not as desirable for dividing fields,			
<lb/>since they swung too easily and were a temp<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tation to leave open. The old type were pre<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ferred by the ranchers. They kept the cattle			
<lb/>more securely separated.</p>
            <p>This evening, Hilda came over the hill by			
<lb/>the shorter trail, and now she was before the			
<lb/>first of the wire gates.</p>
            <p>The days were getting shorter and already,			
<lb/>though it was scarcely six o’clock, the shadows</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 267 ]</fw>
            <pb n="268"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>were closing in deeply. The rosy skies were			
<lb/>dimming and the pressing shadows crept im<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>perceptibly over the gilded sky.</p>
            <p>Quite suddenly darkness fell. The trail,			
<lb/>however, was close to the gate and her horse			
<lb/>knew the way. Hilda did not dismount.			
<lb/>Leaning from her horse, she grasped the post			
<lb/>and tugged at the tightly wedged ring of wire.</p>
            <p>Her first knowledge of the near presence of			
<lb/>the man who had followed her came when			
<lb/>something thudded down at her horse’s feet.			
<lb/>In the half light of the fading day Hilda saw			
<lb/>that uncoiled rope.</p>
            <p>The lariat!</p>
            <p>Now she understood and a gasp of rage es<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>caped her. The man had attempted to rope			
<lb/>her. The lariat had fallen short! She, Hilda			
<lb/>McPherson, daughter of O Bar O, to be Iari<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ated like a head of stock!</p>
            <p>As she watched the rope slowly being coiled			
<lb/>in, the sickening thought rushed upon her that			
<lb/>presently it would be thrown again, and that			
<lb/>second throw might fall true. Instantly she			
<lb/>was off her horse, had grasped the end of the</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 268 ]</fw>
            <pb n="269"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>lariat, whipped it about the gate post, tied a			
<lb/>tight knot, ducked under the wire of the fence,			
<lb/>and secure in the knowledge that her pursuer			
<lb/>would be held back by the closed gate, unless			
<lb/>he dismounted and took her own means of			
<lb/>passing through, Hilda ran like the wind			
<lb/>straight along the trail to O Bar O, shouting			
<lb/>in her clear, carrying young voice, the Indian			
<lb/>cry:</p>
            <p><q>Hi, yi, yi, yi, yi, yi, yi, yi, yil Eee-yaw<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>aw-aw-aw-aw-aw!</q></p>
            <p>As she called, as she ran, an answering shout			
<lb/>came from the direction of the ranch, still			
<lb/>more than a mile away; but he who had an<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>swered her call for help was even then coming			
<lb/>over the crest of the last hill, and the silhouette			
<lb/>in the twilight of man and horse stopped the			
<lb/>girl short and sent her heart racing like a mad			
<lb/>thing in her breast. He was riding as only one			
<lb/>at O Bar O could ride. Reining up sharply			
<lb/>before Hilda, Cheerio swiftly dismounted and			
<lb/>was at her side.</p>
            <p><q>Hilda! You’ve been thrown!</q></p>
            <p>Oh, how that voice, with its unmistakable</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 269 ]</fw>
            <pb n="270"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>note of deep anxiety in her behalf, made			
<lb/>Hilda’s heart leap. Even in her excitement,			
<lb/>she was conscious of a strangely exultant pang			
<lb/>at the thought that he should have been the one			
<lb/>to have come to her in her need. She could			
<lb/>scarcely speak from the excitement and terror			
<lb/>of her recent experience, and for the tumul<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tuous emotions at the sight of the man she			
<lb/>loved.</p>
            <p><q>Over there—a man! He followed me—Oh			
<lb/>-——has been trailing me through the woods, and			
<lb/>at the gate—the gate—he threw the lariat—			
<lb/>the lariat!</q></p>
            <p>Her voice rose hysterically.</p>
            <p><q>Tt missed us—just touched Daisy. I—I—			
<lb/>tied it to the gate post. Gate’s closed. He			
<lb/>can’t come through on horse. Look! There			
<lb/>he is! There he is! See—see—white chaps!			
<lb/>Look!</q></p>
            <p>She was speaking in little sobbing gasps,			
<lb/>conscicus not of the fact that she was held in			
<lb/>the comforting curve of the man’s strong arm.</p>
            <p>Dimly the vanishing form of horse and man			
<lb/>showed for an instant in the half light and dis-</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 270 ]</fw>
            <pb n="271"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>appeared into the dense woods beyond.			
<lb/>Cheerio made a motion as if to remount and			
<lb/>follow, but Hilda clung to his sleeve.</p>
            <p><q>Oh, don’t leave me. Please don’t leave me.			
<lb/>I’m—I’m—afraid to be alone</q></p>
            <p><q>N-not f-for worlds</q>, he said, <q>but			
<lb/>d-d-dear—</q> ‘Through all her pain she heard			
<lb/>that soft term of endearment, <q>He’s left the			
<lb/>lariat. Couldn’t stop to get it. Come, we'll			
<lb/>getit. It may furnish a clue</q>.</p>
            <p>Back at the gate, they untied the knotted			
<lb/>lariat and Cheerio recoiled it and attached it			
<lb/>to his own saddle.</p>
            <p><q>We'll keep this as a memento. Maybe			
<lb/>there’s a man at O Bar O short a Jariat</q>.</p>
            <p><q>No man at O Bar O would do a coyote’s			
<lb/>trick like that</q>, said Hilda, faintly.</p>
            <p>She had recovered somewhat of her com<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>posure, though she still felt the near influence			
<lb/>of the man walking beside her, leading his			
<lb/>horse with one hand, and holding her arm with			
<lb/>the other. Her own mount had gone free and			
<lb/>would not be recovered till the morning. She</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[271 ]</fw>
            <pb n="272"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>would not follow his suggestion to mount his			
<lb/>horse.</p>
            <p>And so they came down over the hill to<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>gether. Just before they passed into the ranch			
<lb/>yard, Cheerio controlled his fluttering tongue			
<lb/>and stammered something that he had been			
<lb/>trying to say to her all of the way down the			
<lb/>hill.</p>
            <p><q>Hilda, I'm a f-f-f-fortunate d-dog. I’m			
<lb/>jolly glad I w-w-went out to look for you to<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>night</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Were you looking for me, then? Why?</q></p>
            <p><q>C-can’t explain it. S-something m-made			
<lb/>me go. I had to f-find you, Hilda</q>.</p>
            <p>Now they were at the steps of the ranch			
<lb/>house. Hilda went up one step, paused, went			
<lb/>up another and stopped, unable to go further.			
<lb/>Cheerio leaned up and tried to see her face in			
<lb/>the semi-light that was now silvering the land			
<lb/>from the broad moon above. What he saw in			
<lb/>Hilda’s face brought the word bursting to his			
<lb/>lips:</p>
            <p><q>M-my dear old girl!</q> he said. <q>I’m dashed			
<lb/>jolly glad I’m alive</q>.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 272 ]</fw>
            <pb n="273"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>Hilda said in a whisper:</p>
            <p><q>Ah, so am I!</q></p>
            <p>And then she fled—fled in panic-stricken re<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>treat to the house. Blindly she found her way			
<lb/>to her room, and cast herself down upon her			
<lb/>bed. She was trembling with an ecstasy that			
<lb/>stung her by its very sweetness,</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 273]</fw>
            <pb n="274"/>
         </div>