<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
     type="chapter"
     n="2"
     change="#proofed">
   <pb n="20"/>
   <head>Chapter II</head>
   <p><persName rendition="#smallcaps">Sandy</persName> made three somersaults of glee on the turf, and at his last turn-over, his head came into contact with something hard. He rubbed said head, and at the same time observed that which had pained him. It was a large, old-fashioned gold locket, studded with rubies and diamonds.</p>
   <p><said who="#Sandy">Holy Salmon!</said> ejaculated the highly- elated boy. In an instant he had seized the bridle of his horse, and was on him. He went up the hill on a run, and began calling outside the house, while still on horse.</p>
   <p><said who="#Sandy" toWhom="#Hilda">Hilda! I say, Hilda! Come on out! Looka here what <emph>I</emph> found!</said></p>
   <p>A girl, skin bronzed by sun and wind, with chocolate-coloured eyes and hair and a certain free grace of motion and poise, came on to the wide verandah. Sandy had ridden his horse clear to the railing, and now he excitedly held up the trinket in his hand, and<pb n="21"/> then tossed it to Hilda, who caught it neatly in her own. Turning it over, the girl examined to find with admiration and curiosity, and, with feminine intuition, she found the spring and opened the locket. Within, the lovely, pictured face of a woman in low-cut evening dress, looked back from the frame. On the opposite side, a lock of dead-gold hair curled behind the glass.</p>
   <p>Sandy had leaped off his horse, and now was excitedly grasping after the treasure.</p>
   <p><said who="#Hilda" toWhom="#Sandy">Wher’d you find it, Sandy?</said></p>
   <p><said who="#Sandy" toWhom="#Hilda">Down in the lower pasture. Betchu its his girl! Say, Hilda, he’s a scream. You'd oughter’ve been there. He came along the road all dolled up in city clothes, and—look! Oh, my God-frey! Look <seg type="question"><choice><sic>u</sic><corr>a</corr></choice>t<note type="questionForMC">Is "ut" a typo or is it part of the dialect? This spelling of "ut" instead of "at" appears nowhere else in the text, but is in both the Burt and Watt.</note></seg> him, Hilda!</said></p>
   <p>In an ecstasy of derision and delight, Sandy pointed.</p>
   <p>Hand shading his eyes, the stranger was gazing across the wide-spreading panorama of gigantic hills, etched against a sky of sheerest blue, upon which the everlasting sun glowed.<pb n="22"/> <said who="#Cheerio">By George!</said> exclaimed the new <q>hand</q> of the O Bar O, <said who="#Cheerio">what a tophole view! Never saw anything to beat it. Give you my word, it <seg type="stutter">b-b-b</seg>eats <seg type="stutter">S-s</seg>witzerland. When I was tramping along the road, I <seg type="stutter">th-th</seg>ought</said> that was a good one on us at home, ’bout this being the Land of Promise, you know, <seg type="stutter">b-b</seg>ut now, by George! I’m hanged if I don’t think you’re right. A chap cannot look across at a view like that and not feel jolly well uplifted!<note type="editorial">[[Note something about the seemingly excessive use of Britishisms here?]]</note></p>
   <p>There was a ring of men closing in about the new arrival, for it was the noon hour, and Hootmon had hurried them along from bunkhouse and corral. At the stranger’s stream of eloquence to Bully Bill <term>anent</term> the beauties of nature in the foothills of the Rocky Mountains, <soCalled>Pink-eyed Jake</soCalled> swooned away in the arms of Hootmon. A gale of unbridled laughter burst from a dozen throats. The men held their sides and leaned forward the better to scan this new specimen of the human family. Hands on hips, they <soCalled xml:id="ch2_sc1_1" next="#ch2_sc1_2">took his</soCalled><pb n="23"/> <soCalled xml:id="ch2_sc1_2" prev="#ch2_sc1_1">number</soCalled> and pronounced him internally a <lb/>freak of nature.</p>
   <p>To the door of the cook-car, rolled the immense form of Tom Chum Lee, the Chinese cook who dominated the grub-car of O Bar O. With a vast smile of benignant humour directed upon his <soCalled>boys</soCalled>, Lee summoned all hands to chow, by means of a great cow bell, that he waved generously back and forth.<note type="editorial">Note here about Chinese cook characters; he's also in Cattle.</note></p>
   <p>With immense satisfaction and relish, the newcomer was taking in all of the colour and atmosphere of the ranch. The fact that he himself was an object of derisive mirth to the outfit, troubled him not at all.</p>
   <p>A skirt—pink—flirted around the side of the house, and outlined against the blue of the sky, the slim form of a young girl shone on the steps of the ranch house. The Englishman had a glimpse of wide, dark eyes, and a generous red mouth, through which gleamed the whitest of teeth. But it was her voice, with its shrill edge of impudent young mirth that sent the colour to the pinched cheeks of the new<pb n="24"/> hand of O Bar O. There was in it, despite its mockery, a haughty accent of contempt.</p>
   <p><said who="#Hilda" toWhom="#Bill">Who’s <seg type="question">his royal nibs,<note type="questionForMC">Should I gloss this now or in the title? Or both?</note></seg> Bully Bill?</said></p>
   <p>Through the corner of his mouth, the foreman enlightened her:</p>
   <p><said who="#Bill" toWhom="#Hilda">Vodeyveel show.<note type="editorial">I.e. Vaudeville Show.</note> Things gittin’ kind o’ dull at O Bar. Thought Id pull in something to cheer the fellows up a bit, and they’s nothing tickles them more than turnin’ a <term>green</term> <term>tenderfoot</term> Englishman on to them. This one here is a circus. When I asked him what the hello—excuse me, Miss Hilda!—<seg type="question">what the hello he<note type="questionForMC">Is it worth tagging explitives/swearing/etc? (Godfrey, What the hello, et cetera?).</note></seg> was doin’ round here, he ses: <q>Cheerio!</q> Say, if ever there was <q>Kid me</q> writ all over a human bein’, it’s splashed over that there one</said>.</p>
   <p><seg type="question"><said who="#Hilda">Um!</said><note type="questionForMC">Is this Hilda speaking here?</note></seg></p>
   <p>Hilda came down the steps and approached the newcomer. Head slightly on one side, she examined him with evident curiosity and amusement. <soCalled>Paper-collar dudes</soCalled>, as the ranch folk called the city people, came quite often to O Bar O, but this particular specimen seemed somehow especially <term>green</term> and guile<pb n="25"/> less. A wicked dimple flashed out in the right cheek of the girl, though her critical eyes were still cold as she looked the man over from head to foot.</p>
   <p><said who="#Hilda" toWhom="#Cheerio"><seg type="question"><term>Hi-yi!</term><note type="questionForMC">How best to gloss this term? For instance, there's stuff like <ref target="https://www.loc.gov/resource/ihas.100005511.0">this</ref> that looks </note></seg> You! Where do you hail from?</said></p>
   <p>As he looked up at the beautiful, <term>saucy</term> young creature before him, the Englishman was seized with one of his worst spells of stuttering. The impediment in his speech was slight, on ordinary occasions, but when unduly moved, and at psychological moments, when the tongue’s office was the most desired of adjuncts, it generally failed him. Now:</p>
   <p><said who="#Cheerio" toWhom="#Hilda"><seg type="stutter">Bb-b-b-b-b-b-b-b-b-b——</seg></said></p>
   <p>The girl, hands on hips, swayed back and forth with laughter.</p>
   <p><said who="#Hilda" toWhom="#Cheerio">Haven't you a tongue even? What are you doing in this wild country, you poor lost lamb from the fold?</said><note type="editorial"/></p>
   <p>He had recovered his wits, and the use of his tongue. His heels came together with a curiously smart and military click, and his blue eyes looked squarely into the impudent<pb n="26"/> brown ones of the girl, laughing in his face. With complete gravity, he replied:</p>
   <p><said who="#Cheerio" toWhom="#Hilda"><seg type="stutter">J-j</seg>ust came across to the <seg type="stutter">p-p</seg>romised land, to try and make a home for myself and—</said> he paused, smiling sunnily—<said who="#Cheerio" toWhom="#Hilda">and another, you know.</said></p>
   <p><said who="#Hilda" toWhom="#Cheerio">Now wasn’t that the great idea!</said> <term>guyed</term> the girl, with mock seriousness. <said who="#Hilda" toWhom="#Cheerio">And who’s the other one, by the way? Another like your Do tell us.</said></p>
   <p><said who="#Cheerio" toWhom="#Hilda">Her name’s—Nanna, we call her</said>.</p>
   <p><said who="#Hilda" toWhom="#Cheerio">Nanna! Nanna! What a sweet name!</said></p>
   <p>She was still mocking, but suddenly swung the locket on its chain toward him.</p>
   <p><said who="#Hilda" toWhom="#Cheerio">Do you know, I believe we’ve found your long-lost Nanna. I was just admiring her fair, sweet face inside. Catch her!</said></p>
   <p>She tossed it across to him. It dropped on the stones between them. He stooped to pick it up, and anxiously examined it, before turning to look back at the girl with a slightly stern glance.</p>
   <p><said who="#Cheerio" toWhom="#Hilda">Righto!</said> he said. <said who="#Cheerio" toWhom="#Hilda">Thanks for returning her to me</said>.</p>
   <pb n="27"/>
   <p>For some unaccountable reason, the girl’s mood changed. She tossed her head, as the colour flooded her face. Something wild and free in that tossing suggested the motion of a young thoroughbred colt.<note type="editorial">Here, another moment of Hilda's affiliation with animal; note that it's <q>thoroughbred</q> here.</note> Affecting great disdain, and as if looking down at him from a height, she inquired:</p>
   <p><said who="#Hilda" toWhom="#Cheerio">Oh, by the way, what’s your name?</said></p>
   <p>He absently fished in his vest pocket, and this action provoked a fresh gale of laughter from the highly edified hands, in which the girl heartily joined. At the laughter, he looked up, slightly whistled, and said in his friendly way:</p>
   <p><said who="#Cheerio" toWhom="#Hilda">Cheerio!</said></p>
   <p><said who="#Hilda" toWhom="#Cheerio">Cheerio!</said> repeated the girl. <said toWhom="#Cheerio" who="#Hilda">Some name. Boys, allow me—Cheerio, Duke of the O Bar O. Escort his grace to the dining-car, and mind you treat him gentle. And say, boys—</said> she called after them, <said who="#Hilda">doll him up in O Bar O duds. Let’s see what he looks like in reglar clothes</said>.</p>
   <p>Shoved along by the men, <soCalled>his grace</soCalled> was pushed and hustled into the cook-car. Here<pb n="28"/> the odour of the hot food, and the rich soup being slapped into each bowl along the line of plates, almost caused the hungry Englishman to faint. Nevertheless, he kept what he would have termed <soCalled>stiff upper lip</soCalled>,<note type="editorial">Something here?</note> and as the Chinaman passed down between the long bench tables, and filled the bowl before the newcomer, Cheerio, as he was henceforward to be known, controlled the famished longing to fall to upon that thick, delicious soup, and, smiling instead, turned to the man on either side of him, with a cigarette case in his hand:</p>
   <p><said who="#Cheerio">Have one, old man, do. <seg type="stutter">P-p</seg>retty <seg type="stutter">g-g</seg>ood stuff! Got them in France, you know. Believe I’ll have one myself before starting in, you know. Topping—what?</said><note type="editorial">Not sure what's happening here? Adams has a number of entries for "top" stuff, including topping (<quote>removing the crown of a living tree in order to use it for a spar for high-line assembling</quote>, but also <quote>top</quote>, which he simply glosses as <quote>A cowboy's word for best</quote>. So not sure </note></p>
   <pb n="29"/>
</div>
