<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="chapter" n="21">
            <head>Chapter XXI</head>
            <p>Every night, after his dinner, P. D. would			
<lb/>take what he termed a <q>cat-nap</q>.’ Not even			
<lb/>chess interrupted these short dozes on the com<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>fortable couch by the pleasantly-crackling			
<lb/>logs heaped upon the big fireplace.</p>
            <p>There would be an interval, then, when			
<lb/>Cheerio and Hilda would find themselves			
<lb/>practically alone in the living-room. Some<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>times Cheerio would look across expectantly			
<lb/>at Hilda, and she would turn away and stare			
<lb/>with seeming absorption out of the window.			
<lb/>Then he would bring forth his tobacco pouch,			
<lb/>fill and light his pipe and dip down in the			
<lb/>pocket of his old coat and bring up a book.			
<lb/>Hilda’s absorption in the outside view would			
<lb/>undergo a swift change. Against her will, she			
<lb/>found herself watching him furtively. It fas<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>cinated her to see the way in which he would			
<lb/>handle a book, his fingers seeming sensitively			
<lb/>to caress the pages. He always closed the</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 248 ]</fw>
            <pb n="249"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>book reluctantly and would return it carefully			
<lb/>to his pocket as if it were something precious.			
<lb/>She had satisfied her curiosity as to the titles			
<lb/>and the authors of the books he read. She had			
<lb/>never heard the names before, and suffered a			
<lb/>pang that he should be close to matters con<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>cerning which she was totally ignorant. She			
<lb/>tried to comfort and reassure herself. Even			
<lb/>if one had missed school and college, even if			
<lb/>one had been side-tracked all of her life on an			
<lb/>Alberta: ranch, even if a girl’s solitary asso<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ciates and friends, over all the days of her life,			
<lb/>had been merely the rough types peculiar to			
<lb/>the cattle country, Ae had said that a world			
<lb/>might be discovered right within the pages of			
<lb/>a book. There was hope, therefore, for the			
<lb/>unhappy Hilda.</p>
            <p>He had made that remark to no one in par<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ticular one night, as he gently closed the book			
<lb/>in his hand, and reached for the tobacco pouch			
<lb/>in his rough tweed pocket. Then he had filled			
<lb/>his pipe, beamed upon the sleeping P. D., and			
<lb/>with his brown head against the back of the			
<lb/>Morris chair, Cheerio had lapsed into what</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 249 ]</fw>
            <pb n="250"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>seemed to be a brown study in which Hilda			
<lb/>and all the rest of the world appeared to dis<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>appear from his ken.</p>
            <p>Cheerio had a trick of disappearing, as it			
<lb/>was, in this manner—disappearing, mentally.			
<lb/>Always there would then arise something tor<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>turing in the breast of Hilda McPherson. She			
<lb/>had a passionate curiosity to know where the			
<lb/>mind of the dreaming man had leaped in			
<lb/>thought. Across the water—Ah! there was no			
<lb/>doubt of that! Back in that England of his!			
<lb/>Figures rose about him. Hilda had an intui<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tive knowledge of the types of people who			
<lb/>were his familiars on the other side. Always			
<lb/>among them was the smiling woman, whose			
<lb/>hair was gold and whose lazy eyes had a lure			
<lb/>in them that to the downright and unsophisti<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>cated Hilda spelled the last word in fascina<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tion. <q>Nanna</q>! A foolish name for a lady,			
<lb/>thought the girl throbbingly, and yet a love			
<lb/>name. It was undoubtedly that.</p>
            <p>If the motherless girl could but have found			
<lb/>a confidante on whom to pour out all the tor<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>turing doubts and longings of these days,</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 250 ]</fw>
            <pb n="251"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>something of her pain would have been surely			
<lb/>assuaged. Chaotic new emotions were war<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ring within her breast. Her wild young na<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ture found itself incapable of wrestling with			
<lb/>the exquisite impulses that despite her best			
<lb/>efforts she could not control. Hilda told her<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>self that she hated. An alarming voice seemed			
<lb/>to retort from the depths of her heart that that			
<lb/>was but another name for Love. This—Lovel			
<lb/>She could not—would not—dared not believe			
<lb/>it. And yet the simple motion of this man’s			
<lb/>strong white hand, the slight quizzical uplift			
<lb/>of his eyes had the power to cause her to hold			
<lb/>her breath suspended and send the blood rac<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing to her heart.</p>
            <p>Hilda was not subtle enough to search her			
<lb/>soul or that of another. She could not diag<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>nose that which overwhelmed her. In a way			
<lb/>she was like one overtaken, trapped in a spell			
<lb/>from which there was no door through which			
<lb/>she might escape. She had reason for believ<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing him to be unworthy—a man who put to a			
<lb/>crucial test, had failed miserably; one who</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[251 ]</fw>
            <pb n="252"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>had confessed to a flagrant and criminal weak<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ness.</p>
            <p>She had judged him relentlessly, for youth			
<lb/>is cruel, and love and jealousy create a torment			
<lb/>which is hard to bear.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 252]</fw>
            <pb n="253"/>
         </div>