<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="chapter" n="13">
            <head>Chapter XIII</head>
            <p><hi rendition="#smallcaps">HARD</hi> as it is to build up a reputation in a			
<lb/>cattle country, which has its own standards			
<lb/>of criticism as everywhere else in the world,			
<lb/>it is not difficult to lose that reputation. From			
<lb/>tongue to tongue rolled the story of Cheerio’s			
<lb/>weakness and confession at the branding cor<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ral, and that story grew like a rolling snow<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ball in the telling, so that presently it would			
<lb/>appear that he had confessed not merely to the			
<lb/>most arrant cowardice at the front, but gross			
<lb/>treachery to his country and his king.</p>
            <p>Every man at O Bar O was a war veteran.			
<lb/>Few of them, it is true, had seen actual service			
<lb/>at the front. Nevertheless, they had acquired			
<lb/>the point of view of the man in the army who			
<lb/>is quick to suspect and judge one he thinks			
<lb/>has <q>funked</q>. The most jealous and hard			
<lb/>in their judgment were they who were licked			
<lb/>in by the long arm of conscription and who</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[159]</fw>
            <pb n="160"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>had <q>served</q> at the Canadian and English			
<lb/>camps.</p>
            <p>When Cheerio, clean and refreshed by a			
<lb/>dip in the Ghost River, came in late to the			
<lb/>cook-car and cast a friendly glance about him,			
<lb/>not even Hootmon or Pink-Eyed Jake looked</p>
            <p> An ominous silence</p>
            <p>up from their <q>feeding.			
<lb/>greeted him, and the tongues that were buz<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>zing so loudly prior to his entrance were stuck			
<lb/>into cheeks, while meaning glances and winks			
<lb/>went along the benches, as his grey eyes swept			
<lb/>the circle of faces</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Cheerio! Fellows!</q> said Cheerio gently,			
<lb/>and fell to upon his dinner.</p>
            <p>Chum Lee slapped down the soup none too			
<lb/>gently into his bow] and as he did so, the			
<lb/>Chinaman said:</p>
            <p><q>Sloup velly good for men got cold fleet!			
<lb/>Eat him quick!</q></p>
            <p>Bully Bill, his ear inclined to the moving			
<lb/>mouth of Holy Smoke, arose solemnly in his			
<lb/>place at the head of the long table, slouched			
<lb/>down the line of men, came to where Cheerio</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 160 ]</fw>
            <pb n="161"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>was beginning on that hot soup that was good			
<lb/>for <q>cold fleet</q>, and:</p>
            <p><q>Hi youl</q> he growled, <q>pack down your			
<lb/>grub P. D.Q. Then git to hello to the bunk<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>house. Git your traps together. Report at			
<lb/>the house for your pay. You're fired!</q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 161]</fw>
            <pb n="162"/>
         </div>