<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="chapter" n="25">
            <head>Chapter XXV</head>
            <p>As a boy, Cheerio’s inability swiftly to ex<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>plain or defend himself, had resulted in many			
<lb/>unjust punishments. He was not stupid, but			
<lb/>became easily confused, and with the best of			
<lb/>intentions, he bungled into unfortunate situa<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tions. His brother, Reggie, swift-witted and			
<lb/>glib of tongue, was far better equipped to de<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>fend and care for himself than the often be<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>wildered and stammering Cheerio. He had			
<lb/>changed very little, and his love had made			
<lb/>him now almost obtusely blind.</p>
            <p>As he hurried eagerly across the verandah			
<lb/>to meet Hilda who was hastening in her direct			
<lb/>way for that <q>show down</q> which her peace of			
<lb/>mind demanded, Cheerio held out toward her			
<lb/>the intended gift.</p>
            <p>In the bright moonlight, Hilda saw the			
<lb/>locket in his hand, and she stopped short in			
<lb/>her impetuous approach. Speech at that mo<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ment failed her. She felt as if suddenly</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 284 ]</fw>
            <pb n="285"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>choked, struck, and her heart was beating so			
<lb/>riotously that it hurt her physically. A primi<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tive surge of wild, ungovernable rage surged			
<lb/>up within her.</p>
            <p>In a far worse dilemma was the unfortu<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>nate and deluded and misunderstood Cheerio.			
<lb/>At that psychological moment, when he would			
<lb/>have given his life for eloquent speech in			
<lb/>which to tell the girl before him of his love,			
<lb/>he was overtaken with panic and confusion.			
<lb/>The hostile attitude of the girl reduced him to			
<lb/>a state of incoherent stuttering as he continued			
<lb/>foolishly to extend the locket.</p>
            <p><q/><q>W w-w-w-w-w-w-w: </q></p>
            <p>She gave him no help. Her angry,</p>
            <p>wounded stare was pinned condemningly			
<lb/>upon him.</p>
            <p><q>Www-w-w-w-w-w-will you accept this			
<lb/>1-little m-m-m-m—memento of </q></p>
            <p><q>Accept that!</q></p>
            <p>Hilda said <q>That</q> as if referring to some<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>thing loathsome.</p>
            <p><q>What should I want with it?</q></p>
            <p><q>Tt</q> also was spoken as <q>that</q>.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 285 ]</fw>
            <pb n="286"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>Like a tidal wave, the girl’s anger over<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>whelmed her. Hell, which the proverb as<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>sures us, hath no fury like a woman scorned,			
<lb/>raged indeed in the ungoverned breast of the			
<lb/>girl of the ranching country. She was neither			
<lb/>equipped by nature or training with those			
<lb/>feminine defenses that might have shielded			
<lb/>her. She was in a way as uncivilized as the			
<lb/>savage woman who beats her untrue mate. All			
<lb/>she was fiercely conscious of was her raging			
<lb/>indignation at the imagined affront offered			
<lb/>her by Cheerio. He, who but a short time			
<lb/>since she had been deluded enough to believe			
<lb/>actually loved her was now flaunting before			
<lb/>her that hateful locket in which she knew was			
<lb/>the picture of the woman he had come to			
<lb/>Canada to make a home for.</p>
            <p>Her eyes were aflame. Her anger domi<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>nated her entirely.</p>
            <p>Crestfallen and surprised, Cheerio drew			
<lb/>back a pace:</p>
            <p><q>T s-say</q>,’ he persisted stupidly, <q>I only			
<lb/>w-wanted you to have it. It’s a n-nice old			
<lb/>thing, you know, and </q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 286 J</fw>
            <pb n="287"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p><q>How dare you offer me a thing like that?</q>			
<lb/>demanded Hilda, in a level, deadly voice.			
<lb/><q>Flow dare you! How dare you!</q></p>
            <p>Her voice rose. She stamped her foot. Her			
<lb/>hands clinched. It would have relieved her			
<lb/>to hurt him physically. Surprised and de<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>jected, he turned away, but his movement			
<lb/>whetted her anger. Her fiery words pursued			
<lb/>him.</p>
            <p><q>What do you take me for? Do you think			
<lb/>I want your silly old second-hand jewellery?			
<lb/>Why don’t you wrap the precious thing up in			
<lb/>white tissue paper and send it across the sea			
<lb/>to the woman that’s in it?</q></p>
            <p>At that a light of understanding broke over			
<lb/>Cheerio. He moved impetuously toward her:</p>
            <p><q>Hilda, don’t you know that you—you</q></p>
            <p>’</p>
            <p>are ,</p>
            <p>He got no further, for at that moment a loud			
<lb/>cough behind him interrupted him. In their			
<lb/>excitement neither Hilda nor Cheerio had			
<lb/>noted the car ascending the grade to the ranch			
<lb/>and then circling the path. Duncan Mallison			
<lb/>had come up the stairs and across the verandah</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 287 ]</fw>
            <pb n="288"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>and had coughed loudly before either Cheerio			
<lb/>or Hilda were aware of his presence.</p>
            <p><q>Good evening, everybody</q>, said the news<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>paper man. <q>How’s chess?</q></p>
            <p>Cheerio had recovered himself sufficiently			
<lb/>to return the grip of the other’s hand.</p>
            <p><q>Why, hello!</q></p>
            <p>Mallison chuckled.</p>
            <p><q>Didn’t expect to see me back, did you? I'll			
<lb/>tell you just what I’m up for. No—not after</q></p>
            <p>a chess story this time. Do you remember			
<lb/>talking to me about a job on the Blizzard?			
<lb/>Well, Munns—our city editor—thinks he can			
<lb/>make a place for you.</p>
            <p>It was the snapping closed of the door that			
<lb/>apprised them of the departure of Hilda.			
<lb/>Cheerio looked at it thoughtfully, with an ele<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ment of sadness, and perhaps of new resolve.</p>
            <p><q>Took here</q>, he said to his friend. ‘<q>You’ve			
<lb/>come in the n-nick of time, I might say. Fact			
<lb/>is, old man, I—I’d like most awfully a chance			
<lb/>to see to—to—demonstrate m-m-my ability—			
<lb/>t-to do s-something worth while, you know</q>.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 288 ]</fw>
            <pb n="289"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>C-carn’t go on being a beggar, you understand.			
<lb/>G-got to s-s-succeed, don’t you know.</p>
            <p>Mallison did know. He grinned apprecia<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tively.</p>
            <p><q>Then you'll go back with me to Calgary to<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>night</q></p>
            <p><q>Can’t do that very well, old man</q>.</p>
            <p>He thought a moment, and then added			
<lb/>brightly:</p>
            <p><q>To-morrow morning. Put you up for to<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>night, and we'll leave first thing. You see, I’ve			
<lb/>one more game still to do</q>.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 289 ]</fw>
            <pb n="290"/>
         </div>