<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="chapter" n="2">
            <head>Chapter II</head>
            <p><persName rendition="#smallcaps">Sandy</persName> made three somersaults of glee on			
<lb/>the turf, and at his last turn-over, his head			
<lb/>came into contact with something hard. He			
<lb/>rubbed said head, and at the same time ob<pc force="weak">-</pc>	
<lb/>served that which had pained him. It was a			
<lb/>large, old-fashioned gold locket, studded with			
<lb/>rubies and diamonds.</p>
            <p><q>Holy Salmon!</q> ejaculated the highly<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>elated boy. In an instant he had seized the			
<lb/>bridle of his horse, and was on him. He went			
<lb/>up the hill on a run, and began calling out<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>side the house, while still on horse.</p>
            <p><q>Hilda! I say, Hilda! Come on out!			
<lb/>Looka here what I found!</q></p>
            <p>A girl, skin bronzed by sun and wind, with			
<lb/>chocolate-coloured eyes and hair and a cer<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tain free grace of motion and poise, came on			
<lb/>to the wide verandah. Sandy had ridden his			
<lb/>horse clear to the railing, and now he ex<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>citedly held up the trinket in his hand, and</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 20 ]</fw>
            <pb n="21"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>then tossed it to Hilda, who caught it neatly			
<lb/>in her own. Turning it over, the girl ex<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>amined to find with admiration and curiosity,			
<lb/>and, with feminine intuition, she found the			
<lb/>spring and opened the locket. Within, the			
<lb/>lovely, pictured face of a woman in low-cut			
<lb/>evening dress, looked back from the frame.			
<lb/>On the opposite side, a lock of dead-gold hair			
<lb/>curled behind the glass.</p>
            <p>Sandy had leaped off his horse, and now			
<lb/>was excitedly grasping after the treasure.</p>
            <p><q>Wher’d you find it, Sandy?</q></p>
            <p><q>Down in the lower pasture. Betchu its his			
<lb/>girl! Say, Hilda, he’s a scream. You'd			
<lb/>oughter’ve been there. He came along the			
<lb/>road all dolled up in city clothes, and—look!			
<lb/>Oh, my God-frey! Look ut him, Hilda!</q></p>
            <p>In an ecstasy of derision and delight, Sandy			
<lb/>pointed.</p>
            <p>Hand shading his eyes, the stranger was			
<lb/>gazing across the wide-spreading panorama			
<lb/>of gigantic hills, etched against a sky of sheer<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>est blue, upon which the everlasting sun			
<lb/>glowed.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[21 ]</fw>
            <pb n="22"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p><q>By George!</q> exclaimed the new <q>hand</q>			
<lb/>of the O Bar O, <q>what a tophole view!			
<lb/>Never saw anything to beat it. Give you my			
<lb/>word, it b-b-beats S-switzerland. When I			
<lb/>was tramping along the road, I th-thought</q></p>
            <p>that was a good one on us at home, ’bout this			
<lb/>being the Land of Promise, you know, b-but			
<lb/>now, by George! I’m hanged if I don’t think			
<lb/>you’re right. A chap cannot look across at			
<lb/>a view like that and not feel jolly well up<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>lifted!</p>
            <p>There was a ring of men closing in about			
<lb/>the new arrival, for it was the noon hour, and			
<lb/>Hootmon had hurried them along from			
<lb/>bunkhouse and corral. At the stranger’s			
<lb/>stream of eloquence to Bully Bill anent the			
<lb/>beauties of nature in the foothills of the			
<lb/>Rocky Mountains, ‘<q>Pink-eyed Jake</q> swooned			
<lb/>away in the arms of Hootmon. A gale of un<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>bridled laughter burst from a dozen throats.			
<lb/>The men held their sides and leaned forward			
<lb/>the better to scan this new specimen of the			
<lb/>human family. Hands on hips, they <q>took his</q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 22]</fw>
            <pb n="23"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>number and pronounced him internally a</p>
            <p>freak of nature.</p>
            <p>To the door of the cook-car, rolled the im<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>mense form of Tom Chum Lee, the Chinese			
<lb/>cook who dominated the grub-car of O Bar O.			
<lb/>With a vast smile of benignant humour di<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>rected upon his <q>boys</q>, Lee summoned all			
<lb/>hands to chow, by means of a great cow bell,			
<lb/>that he waved generously back and forth.</p>
            <p>With immense satisfaction and relish, the			
<lb/>newcomer was taking in all of the colour and			
<lb/>atmosphere of the ranch. The fact that he			
<lb/>himself was an object of derisive mirth to the			
<lb/>outfit, troubled him not at all.</p>
            <p>A skirt—pink—flirted around the side of			
<lb/>the house, and outlined against the blue of the			
<lb/>sky, the slim form of a young girl shone on			
<lb/>the steps of the ranch house. The Englishman			
<lb/>had a glimpse of wide, dark eyes, and a gen<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>erous red mouth, through which gleamed the			
<lb/>whitest of teeth. But it was her voice, with its			
<lb/>shrill edge of impudent young mirth that sent			
<lb/>the colour to the pinched cheeks of the new</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[23]</fw>
            <pb n="24"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>hand of O Bar O. There was in it, despite its			
<lb/>mockery, a haughty accent of contempt.</p>
            <p><q>Who’s his royal nibs, Bully Bill?</q></p>
            <p>Through the corner of his mouth, the fore<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>man enlightened her:</p>
            <p><q>Vodeyveel show. Things gittin’ kind o’			
<lb/>dull atO Bar. Thought Id pull in something			
<lb/>to cheer the fellows up a bit, and they’s noth<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing tickles them more than turnin’ a green ten<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>derfoot Englishman on to them. This one			
<lb/>here is a circus. When I asked him what the			
<lb/>hello—excuse me, Miss Hilda!—what the			
<lb/>hello he was doin’ round here, he ses:			
<lb/>‘Cheerio!’ Say, if ever there was ‘Kid me’			
<lb/>writ all over a human bein’, it’s splashed over			
<lb/>that there one</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Wm !</q></p>
            <p>Hilda came down the steps and approached</p>
            <p>the newcomer. Head slightly on one side, she			
<lb/>examined him with evident curiosity and			
<lb/>amusement. ‘<q>Paper-collar dudes</q>, as the			
<lb/>ranch folk called the city people, came quite			
<lb/>often to O Bar O, but this particular specimen			
<lb/>seemed somehow especially green and guile-</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 24 ]</fw>
            <pb n="25"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>less. A wicked dimple flashed out in the right			
<lb/>cheek of the girl, though her critical eyes were			
<lb/>still cold as she looked the man over from head</p>
            <p>to foot.</p>
            <p><q>Hi-yil You! Where do you hail from?</q></p>
            <p>As he looked up at the beautiful, saucy			
<lb/>young creature before him, the Englishman			
<lb/>was seized with one of his worst spells of stut<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tering. The impediment in his speech was			
<lb/>slight, on ordinary occasions, but when unduly			
<lb/>moved, and at psychological moments, when			
<lb/>the tongue’s office was the most desired of ad<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>juncts, it generally failed him. Now:</p>
            <p><q>Bb-b-b-b-b-b-b-b-b-b——</q></p>
            <p>The girl, hands on hips, swayed back and			
<lb/>forth with laughter.</p>
            <p><q>Haven't you a tongue even? What are you			
<lb/>doing in this wild country, you poor lost lamb			
<lb/>from the fold?</q></p>
            <p>He had recovered his wits, and the use of			
<lb/>his tongue. His heels came together with a			
<lb/>curiously smart and military click, and his			
<lb/>blue eyes looked squarely into the impudent</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[25 ]</fw>
            <pb n="26"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>brown ones of the girl, laughing in his face.			
<lb/>With complete gravity, he replied:</p>
            <p><q>J-just came across to the p-promised land,			
<lb/>to try and make a home for myself and—</q> he			
<lb/>paused, smiling sunnily—‘‘and another, you			
<lb/>know.</p>
            <p><q>Now wasn’t that the great idea!</q> guyed the			
<lb/>girl, with mock seriousness. ‘And who’s the			
<lb/>other one, by the way? Another like your			
<lb/>Do tell us.</p>
            <p><q>Her name’s—Nanna, we call her</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Nanna! Nanna! What a sweet name!</q></p>
            <p>She was still mocking, but suddenly swung			
<lb/>the locket on its chain toward him.</p>
            <p><q>Do you know, I believe we’ve found your			
<lb/>long-lost Nanna. I was just admiring her fair,			
<lb/>sweet face inside. Catch her!</q></p>
            <p>She tossed it across to him. It dropped on			
<lb/>the stones between them. He stooped to pick			
<lb/>it up, and anxiously examined it, before turn<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing to look back at the girl with a slightly stern			
<lb/>glance.</p>
            <p><q>Righto!</q> he said. <q>Thanks for returning			
<lb/>her to me</q>.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 26 J</fw>
            <pb n="27"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>For some unaccountable reason, the girl’s			
<lb/>mood changed. She tossed her head, as the			
<lb/>colour flooded her face. Something wild and			
<lb/>free in that tossing suggested the motion of a			
<lb/>young thoroughbred colt. Affecting great			
<lb/>disdain, and as if looking down at him from a			
<lb/>height, she inquired:</p>
            <p><q>Oh, by the way, what’s your name?</q></p>
            <p>He absently fished in his vest pocket, and			
<lb/>this action provoked a fresh gale of laughter			
<lb/>from the highly edified hands, in which the			
<lb/>girl heartily joined. At the laughter, he			
<lb/>looked up, slightly whistled, and said in his			
<lb/>friendly way:</p>
            <p><q>Cheerio!</q></p>
            <p><q>Cheerio!</q> repeated the girl. <q>Some name.			
<lb/>Boys, allow me—Cheerio, Duke of the O Bar			
<lb/>O. Escort his grace to the dining-car, and			
<lb/>mind you treat him gentle. And say, boys—</q>			
<lb/>she called after them, <q>doll him up in O Bar O			
<lb/>duds. Let’s see what he looks like in reglar			
<lb/>clothes</q>.</p>
            <p>Shoved along by the men, <q>his grace</q> was			
<lb/>pushed and hustled into the cook-car. Here</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[27]</fw>
            <pb n="28"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>the odour of the hot food, and the rich soup			
<lb/>being slapped into each bowl along the line of			
<lb/>plates, almost caused the hungry Englishman			
<lb/>to faint. Nevertheless, he kept what he would			
<lb/>have termed <q>stiff upper lip</q>, and as the			
<lb/>Chinaman passed down between the long			
<lb/>bench tables, and filled the bowl before the			
<lb/>newcomer, Cheerio, as he was henceforward to			
<lb/>be known, controlled the famished longing to			
<lb/>fall to upon that thick, delicious soup, and,			
<lb/>smiling instead, turned to the man on either			
<lb/>side of him, with a cigarette case in his hand:</p>
            <p><q>Have one, old man, do. P-pretty g-good			
<lb/>stuff! Got them in France, you know. Be<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>lieve I’ll have one myself before starting in,			
<lb/>you know. Topping—what?</q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[28]</fw>
            <pb n="29"/>
         </div>