<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="chapter" n="15">
            <head>Chapter XV</head>
            <p><q>SAN-NDY!</q></p>
            <p>The three on the verandah jumped. That			
<lb/>crisp summons, that peculiar inflection meant			
<lb/>but one thing. Chess! Sandy cast a swift			
<lb/>agonized glance about him, seeking an imme<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>diate mode of escape. He was slipping cat<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>footed and doubled over along the back of the			
<lb/>swinging couch on the verandah, when again			
<lb/>came the imperative summons, this time with			
<lb/>even more deadly significance.</p>
            <p><q>Sandy! In here, sir!</q></p>
            <p><q>Yessir, I’m comin’, sir</q>.</p>
            <p>Now it happened that the foreman of O			
<lb/>Bar O had come especially over to the ranch			
<lb/>house, accompanied by the son and daughter			
<lb/>of P. D. to announce to his employer the dis<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>charge of Cheerio. It was an ironclad rule of			
<lb/>O Bar O that no <q>hand</q> upon the place should			
<lb/>be dismissed without his case first being exam<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ined before the final court of judgment in the</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 169 ]</fw>
            <pb n="170"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>person of P. D. This was merely a formal<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ity, for P. D. was accustomed to O. K. the			
<lb/>acts of his foreman. Nevertheless, it was one			
<lb/>of the customs that could not be ignored.			
<lb/>What is more, a man reported for his final			
<lb/>pay to the supreme boss of the ranch.</p>
            <p>It was also the law at O Bar O that such			
<lb/>discharges and reports should be made after			
<lb/>the working hours in the field. In the present			
<lb/>instance, Bully Bill had harkened to the ad<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>vice of his assistant and discharged Cheerio			
<lb/>at the noon hour. O Bar O, he contended,			
<lb/>could not afford to risk its prestige by having			
<lb/>in its employ for even a few more hours a man			
<lb/>who had acted at the corrals as had the Eng<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>lishman. Therefore, having put his men back			
<lb/>to work at the corrals, Bully Bill had come			
<lb/>to the house to report to his employer.</p>
            <p>That Sandy summons was unmistakable.			
<lb/>The noble and ancient game was about to be			
<lb/>played. It was well-known lese majeste to			
<lb/>interrupt when the game was in progress.			
<lb/>Bully Bill and the young McPhersons looked			
<lb/>at each other in consternation and dismay.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 170 ]</fw>
            <pb n="171"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>Sandy, in his ragged and soiled overalls,			
<lb/>one of the <q>galluses</q> missing and the other			
<lb/>hitched in place with a safety pin, groaned			
<lb/>aloud, then shuffled unwillingly into the house.			
<lb/>Rebellion bristled and stuck out of every inch			
<lb/>of the reluctant and disgusted boy. At that			
<lb/>moment Sandy loathed chess above everything			
<lb/>else on earth. It was a damfool game that			
<lb/>no other boy in the country was forced to			
<lb/>play. Sandy could not see why he should be			
<lb/>singled out as a special victim. Sullenly he			
<lb/>seated himself before the hated board. Blindly			
<lb/>he lifted and moved a black pawn forward			
<lb/>two paces. His father’s eyes snapped through			
<lb/>his glasses.</p>
            <p><q>Since when did it become the custom for			
<lb/>the Black to move before the White?</q> he			
<lb/>demanded fiercely.</p>
            <p>Sandy coughed and replaced the pawn. His			
<lb/>father took the first move with his white pawn.</p>
            <p>Now when Sandy McPherson entered thus			
<lb/>unwillingly into the ranch house he passed			
<lb/>not alone into the place. Close upon his heels,			
<lb/>silently and unseen by the absorbed master of</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[171 ]</fw>
            <pb n="172"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>the house, followed the yellow dog, Viper.			
<lb/>He slunk in fact along behind chairs and			
<lb/>tables, for well Viper knew he was on for<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>bidden and hostile territory. Reaching the			
<lb/>great, overstuffed sofa that stood in soft luxury			
<lb/>before the big stone fireplace, Viper leaped			
<lb/>soundlessly aboard, and a moment later was			
<lb/>snuggled well down among the numerous sofa			
<lb/>pillows and cushions that were the creations			
<lb/>of Hilda’s feminine hands.</p>
            <p>P. D. McPherson had his scientific opinion			
<lb/>touching upon the subject of dogs. To a lim<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ited extent, he had experimented upon the			
<lb/>canine race, but he had not given the subject			
<lb/>the thought or the work bestowed on his other			
<lb/>subjects, as he considered animals of this sort			
<lb/>were placed on earth more for the purpose			
<lb/>of ornament and companionship rather than			
<lb/>for utilization by the human race, as in the			
<lb/>case of horses, cattle, pigs, etc. O Bar O pos<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>sessed some excellent examples of P. D.’s ex<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>periments. He had produced some quite re<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>markable cattle dogs, a cross between collie			
<lb/>and coyote in looks and trained so that they</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 172 ]</fw>
            <pb n="173"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>were almost as efficient in the work of cutting			
<lb/>out and rounding-up cattle as the cowboys.			
<lb/>These dogs had been duly exhibited at the			
<lb/>Calgary Fair but the judgment upon them			
<lb/>had so aroused the wrath of the indignant P. D.			
<lb/>that after a speech that became almost a classic			
<lb/>in its way, because of the variety and quality			
<lb/>of its extraordinary words, P. D. departed			
<lb/>from the fair ground with his <q>thoroughbred			
<lb/>mongrels</q> as the <q>blank, blank, blank fool			
<lb/>judges</q> had joshingly named them. P. D. was			
<lb/>not finished with his dog experiments <q>‘by a			
<lb/>damn sight</q>. However, his subjects at this			
<lb/>time were held in excellent quarters pending			
<lb/>the time when P. D. would renew work upon			
<lb/>them. Occasionally, said dogs were brought			
<lb/>forth for the inspection of their creator, but			
<lb/>even they, good products and even servants			
<lb/>of O Bar O, knew better than to intrude into			
<lb/>his private residences.</p>
            <p>Of Viper’s existence at the present stage in			
<lb/>his career, P. D. was totally ignorant. He			
<lb/>supposed, in fact, that this miserable little			
<lb/>specimen of the mongrel race had been duly</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 173 ]</fw>
            <pb n="174"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>executed, for such had been his stern orders,			
<lb/>when at an inconvenient time Viper had first</p>
            <p>thrust himself upon the notice of his master’s			
<lb/>father.</p>
            <p>P. D. knew not that such execution was			
<lb/>stayed through the weakness of the execu<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tioner, who had hearkened to the heartrend<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing pleas for clemency and mercy that had			
<lb/>poured in a torrent from Sandy, supported by			
<lb/>the pitying Hilda. Sandy had pledged him<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>self moreover to see that his dog was kept out			
<lb/>of sight and sound of his parent.</p>
            <p>Of all his possessions, Sandy valued Viper			
<lb/>the most. Ever since the day when he had			
<lb/>traded a whole sack of purloined sugar for			
<lb/>the ugly little yellow puppy, Sandy had loved			
<lb/>his dog. He had <q>raised</q> him <q>by hand</q>,			
<lb/>in the beginning actually wrapping the puppy			
<lb/>up in a towel and forcing him to suckle from			
<lb/>a baby bottle acquired at the trading-post			
<lb/>especially for that purpose. All that that dog			
<lb/>was or would be, he owed to Sandy McPher<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>son. Sandy considered him <q>a perfect gen<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tleman</q> in many ways, one who could <q>put</q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 174]</fw>
            <pb n="175"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>it all over those pampered kennel fellows.			
<lb/>Viper could bark <q>Thank you</q> for a bone as			
<lb/>intelligibly as if he had uttered the words; he			
<lb/>could wipe his mouth, blow his nose, suppress			
<lb/>a yawn with an uplifted paw, and weep feel<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ingly. He could dance a jig, turn somersaults,			
<lb/>balance a ball on his nose, and he could laugh			
<lb/>as realistically as a hyena. Not only was he			
<lb/>possessed of these valuable talents, but Viper			
<lb/>had demonstrated his value by services to the			
<lb/>ranch which only his master fully appreciated.			
<lb/>The barns, when Viper was at hand, were			
<lb/>kept free of cats and poultry and other stock			
<lb/>that had no right to be there, and Sandy’s			
<lb/>job of bringing home the milk cows in the			
<lb/>morning and evening was successfully trans<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ferred to Viper. Sandy had merely to say:			
<lb/><q>Gawn! Git ’em in</q>, and the little dog			
<lb/>would be off like a flash, through the barn<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>yard, out into the pasture, and up the hill to			
<lb/>where cattle were grazing. He would pick			
<lb/>out from among them the ten head of milk			
<lb/>stock, snap at their heels till they were formed</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[175 ]</fw>
            <pb n="176"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>into a separate bunch, and drive them down			
<lb/>to the milk sheds.</p>
            <p>Viper’s continued existence at O Bar O,			
<lb/>therefore, was most desired by his master. By			
<lb/>some miracle, due largely to P. D.’s absorp-</p>
            <p>tion in his own important affairs, the little			
<lb/>dog had escaped the notice or especial obser<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>vation of Sandy’s father. Once he had indeed			
<lb/>looked absently at the dog as he passed at the			
<lb/>heels of Sandy, and he had actually remarked			
<lb/>at that time on the <q>Indian dogs</q> that were			
<lb/>about the place, and that should be kept			
<lb/>toward the camps.</p>
            <p>In the hurry and rush of events of this es<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>pecial day, Viper was forgotten, and the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>cited Sandy had omitted to lock him up in			
<lb/>the barn, as was his custom, when he went			
<lb/>to the house.</p>
            <p>So far as P. D. was concerned, Viper was			
<lb/>a dead dog. Very much alive in fact, how<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ever, was Sandy’s dog, as curled up on that			
<lb/>couch of luxury he bit and snapped at elusive			
<lb/>fleas that are no respectors of places and things			
<lb/>and thrive on a dog’s back whether he be lying</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 176 ]</fw>
            <pb n="177"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>upon a bed of straw or sand or, as in the pres<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ent instance, curled up on an overstuffed sofa.</p>
            <p>Meanwhile, as Sandy made his unwilling			
<lb/>moves, and while Viper disappeared into the			
<lb/>land of oblivion through the medium of dog			
<lb/>sleep, a whispered council of war was held			
<lb/>on the front verandah.</p>
            <p><q>Go in and speak to him now. The game			
<lb/>may run on till midnight. You know Dad!			
<lb/>If, by any chance, Sandy puts up a good fight			
<lb/>and prolongs the game, he’ll have it to do			
<lb/>all over again and again until Dad beats him			
<lb/>hard, and if Sandy plays a poor game, then			
<lb/>he’ll be as sore no one’ll be able to go near			
<lb/>him and he’ll make me take his place. So			
<lb/>there you are. You may as well take the bull			
<lb/>by the horns right now, and hop to it</q>.</p>
            <p>The woman tempted and the man did fall.</p>
            <p>The foreman of O Bar O, endeavouring to			
<lb/>put firmness and resolution into his softened			
<lb/>step, took his courage into his hands and en<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tered the forbidden presence of the chess			
<lb/>players. Hat in hand, nervously twisting it			
<lb/>about, tobacco shifted respectfully into one</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[177]</fw>
            <pb n="178"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>cheek, this big, lanky gawk of a man cleared			
<lb/>his throat apologetically. Only a slight			
<lb/>twitch of one bushy eyebrow betrayed the fact			
<lb/>of P. D.’s irritated knowledge of the presence			
<lb/>of intruders.</p>
            <p><q>Dad!</q> Hilda’s voice trembled slightly.			
<lb/>She appreciated the gravity of interrupting			
<lb/>her father’s game, but Hilda was in that ex<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>alted mood of the hero who sacrifices his own			
<lb/>upon the altar of necessity and duty. What			
<lb/>had occurred at the corrals was a climax to			
<lb/>her own judgment and condemnation of the			
<lb/>prisoner before the bar.</p>
            <p>P. D. affected not to hear that <q>Dad!</q> On			
<lb/>the contrary, he elaborately raised his hand,			
<lb/>paused it over a knight, lifted the knight and			
<lb/>set it from a black to a red square. Dangerous			
<lb/>and violent consequences, Hilda knew, were			
<lb/>more than likely to follow should she persist.			
<lb/>A matter of life and death concerned not the			
<lb/>chess monomaniac when a game was in prog<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ress. Not till the old gambler could shout the			
<lb/>final:</p>
            <p><q>Check to your king, sir! Game!</q> should</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[178]</fw>
            <pb n="179"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>man, woman, child, or dog dare to address			
<lb/>the players.</p>
            <p><q>Dad!</q></p>
            <p>P. D.’s hand, which had just left the afore<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>mentioned Knight, made a curious motion.			
<lb/>It closed up into a fist that shot into the palm			
<lb/>of his left hand. Up flashed bright old eyes,			
<lb/>glaring fiercely through double-lensed glasses.			
<lb/>Up lifted the shaggy old head, jerked			
<lb/>amazedly from one to the other of the dis<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>comfited pair before him.</p>
            <p><q>What's this? What’sthise Business hours			
<lb/>changed, heh? Who the </q></p>
            <p>Bully Bill cleared his throat elaborately and			
<lb/>lustered a clumsy step forward.</p>
            <p><q>Just come over to the house to tell you			
<lb/>I’ve fired his royal nibs, sir, and he'll be over			
<lb/>for his pay</q>.</p>
            <p><q>You've what?</q></p>
            <p><q>Fired </q></p>
            <p>Half arising from his feet, P. D. emitted			
<lb/>a long, blood-curdling, blistering string of			
<lb/>original curses that caused even his hardened			
<lb/>foreman to blench. That raised voite, those</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 179]</fw>
            <pb n="180"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>unmistakable words of wrath penetrated			
<lb/>‘ across the room and into the cocked ear of			
<lb/>Sandy’s sleeping dog. Full and exciting as			
<lb/>the owner of Viper made all of his days, the			
<lb/>exhausted animal never failed, when opportu<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>nity offered, to secure such rest as fate might			
<lb/>allow him from the wild career through which			
<lb/>his master daily whirled him. Nevertheless			
<lb/>that raised and testy voice, for all Viper knew,			
<lb/>might be directed against the one he loved			
<lb/>best on earth.</p>
            <p>Viper turned a moist nose mournfully to			
<lb/>the ceiling, and ere the last of the scorching			
<lb/>words of P. D. McPherson had left his lips,			
<lb/>a low moan of exquisite sympathy and pain			
<lb/>came from the direction of the overstuffed			
<lb/>couch. Instantly the red, alarmed flush of			
<lb/>guilt and terror flooded the freckled face of			
<lb/>the owner of the dog, as wriggling around to			
<lb/>escape that raised hand of his furious parent,			
<lb/>Sandy added chaos to confusion by upsetting			
<lb/>the sacred chess board.</p>
            <p>There was a roar from the outraged chess			
<lb/>player, a whining protest from the boy, duck-</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 180 ]</fw>
            <pb n="181"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>ing out of his way, and at that critical moment,			
<lb/>Viper sprang to the defence of his master.			
<lb/>Planting himself before P. D. McPherson,			
<lb/>the little dog barked furiously and menacingly,			
<lb/>and then fled before the foot kicked out for			
<lb/>dire punishment. Pandemonium broke loose			
<lb/>in that lately quiet room, dedicated to the			
<lb/>scientific, silent game of chess.</p>
            <p><q>Who let that dog in?</q> roared the enraged			
<lb/>ranchman.</p>
            <p><q>He come in himself</q>, averred Sandy, quail<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing and trembling before his father’s terrible			
<lb/>glance, and casting a swift, furtive look about			
<lb/>him for an easy means of exit.</p>
            <p><q>Get him out! Get him out! Get him out!</q>			
<lb/>shouted P. D., and, seizing a golf club, he			
<lb/>jabbed at the swiftly disappearing animal.			
<lb/>For awhile, dog and boy cavorted through			
<lb/>the room, the one racing to safe places under			
<lb/>sofas and behind chairs and piano, and the			
<lb/>other coaxing, pleading, threatening, till at			
<lb/>last, crawling cravenly along the floor on his			
<lb/>stomach, Viper gave himself up to justice.</p>
            <p><q>Hand him over to me</q>, demanded P. D.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 181 ]</fw>
            <pb n="182"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p><q>Wh-what’re you goin’ to do to him?</q>			
<lb/>quavered the boy, an eye on the niblick in			
<lb/>P. D.’s hand, and holding his treasured pos<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>session protectingly to his ragged breast.</p>
            <p><q>Never mind what I’m going to do. You			
<lb/>hand that dog to me, do you hear me, and do			
<lb/>it G— D— quick!</q></p>
            <p><q>Here he is then</q>, whimpered Sandy, and			
<lb/>set the dog at his father’s feet.</p>
            <p>There was a flash, a streak across the room,			
<lb/>and the dog had disappeared into some corner			
<lb/>of the great ranch house. The boy, with a			
<lb/>single glance at his father’s purpling face,			
<lb/>took to his heels as if his life were imperilled			
<lb/>and followed in the steps of his dog.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">{ 182 ]</fw>
            <pb n="183"/>
         </div>