<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="chapter" n="11">
            <head>Chapter XI</head>
            <p><hi rendition="#smallcaps">THERE</hi> were eighteen hundred head of			
<lb/>calves to be vaccinated, branded, dehorned and			
<lb/>weaned. Over the widespreading hills and			
<lb/>meadows the cattle poured in a long unbroken			
<lb/>stream, bellowing and calling as they moved.			
<lb/>The round-up included the mothers, eighteen			
<lb/>hundred head of white-faced Herefords.			
<lb/>These, sensing danger to their young, came un<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>willingly, moaning and stopping stolidly to			
<lb/>bawl their unceasing protests or to call per<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>emptorily to their straying offspring. Some<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>times a mother would make a break for free<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>dom and a rider would have his hands full			
<lb/>driving her out of the dense brush where the			
<lb/>fugitive might find a temporary asylum.</p>
            <p>At the corrals they were driving long posts			
<lb/>four feet deep into the earth. Close by the			
<lb/>posts a soft coal fire spat and blazed. <q>Doc</q>			
<lb/>Murray, veterinary surgeon, on an upturned			
<lb/>wooden box, sleeves rolled to elbow and pipe</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 132]</fw>
            <pb n="133"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>in the corner of his mouth, squatted, directing			
<lb/>the preparations, Everything was done ship<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>shape at O Bar O.</p>
            <p>For some time, oblivious to the taunts and			
<lb/>jeers cast at him, Cheerio, returned from the			
<lb/>round-up, had been standing by his horse’s			
<lb/>head gazing up the hill in a brown study of			
<lb/>rapture. The sight of that army sweeping in			
<lb/>from all directions over the hills and from the			
<lb/>woods, to meet in the lower pastures and auto<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>matically form in to that symmetrical file, fas<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>cinated him beyond words. Even the riders,			
<lb/>loosely seated on their horses, their bright			
<lb/>handkerchiefs blowing free in the breeze,			
<lb/>whirling lariat and long cattle whips, flanking			
<lb/>and following the herd, seemed pleasing ‘to			
<lb/>the eye of the Englishman.</p>
            <p>Though the day of the chap-clad, large<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>hatted type of cowboy is said to have passed			
<lb/>in the Western States, in Alberta he is still a	<!--Alberta as an odd, or perhaps skewed, mimesis of the cowboy mythos-->
<lb/>thriving, living reality. In this <q>last of the			
<lb/>big lands</q>,			
<lb/>hundreds of thousands of acres, their guar<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>dians appear to have somewhat of that ro-</p>
            <p>[ 133 ]</p>
            <p>where the cattle still range over</p>
            <pb n="134"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>mantic element about them which has made			
<lb/>the cowboy famous in story and in song. He			
<lb/>wears the fur and leather chaps, the buckskin			
<lb/>shirts and coats, the Indian beaded gauntlets			
<lb/>and the wide felt hats not wholly because they			
<lb/>are good to look at, but because of their sterl<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing qualities for utilitarian purposes. The			
<lb/>chaps are indispensable for the trail, the fur			
<lb/>ones for warmth and general protection and			
<lb/>the leather ones for the brush. The great			
<lb/>hats, which the Indians also use in Alberta,			
<lb/>serve the double purposes of protection from			
<lb/>a too-ardent sun and as great drinking vessels			
<lb/>during a long ride. The hide shirts are both			
<lb/>wind and sun proof and the beadwork sewn			
<lb/>on with gut thread serve as excellent places			
<lb/>for the scratching of matches. Cheerio him<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>self had by now a full cowboy outfit, chaps,			
<lb/>hide shirt, wide hat, flowing tie, but he never			
<lb/>tired of looking appreciatively at the other fel<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>lows in similar garb. Now, with eyes slightly			
<lb/>screwed to get the right angle upon them, he			
<lb/>planned a canvas that was some day to hang in			
<lb/>a place of great honour.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 134 ]</fw>
            <pb n="135"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>The morning’s work had been exhilarating.			
<lb/>To him had been assigned some of the most			
<lb/>difficult riding tasks of the round-up. He had			
<lb/>been dispatched into the bush on the east side			
<lb/>of the Ghost River to gather in forty-seven			
<lb/>strays that had taken refuge in the bog lands			
<lb/>and had drawn with them their young into this			
<lb/>insecure and dubious protection from the			
<lb/>riders.</p>
            <p>Cheerio had ridden through woods so dense			
<lb/>that his horse could barely squeeze between			
<lb/>the bushes and the trees. He had been obliged			
<lb/>to draw his feet out of the stirrups and ride			
<lb/>cross-legged in his saddle. Sometimes he was			
<lb/>forced to dismount and lead his horse over			
<lb/>trails so narrow that the animal had balked			
<lb/>and hesitated to pass until led. Rattling a			
<lb/>tin bell made of an empty tomato can with a			
<lb/>couple of rocks in it, Cheerio wended his way			
<lb/>through the deep woods. This loudly-clank<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing contraption served to rouse and frighten			
<lb/>the hidden cattle out into the open, but several			
<lb/>of them retreated and plunged farther into the</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[135]</fw>
            <pb n="136"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>bush that bordered hidden pools of succulent			
<lb/>mud and quicksand.</p>
            <p>The branches of the thick trees had snapped			
<lb/>against his face as he rode and his chin and			
<lb/>cheeks were scratched where the wide hat had			
<lb/>failed to afford sufficient protection. The			
<lb/>sleeves of his rough riding shirt were literally			
<lb/>torn to shreds and even the bright magenta			
<lb/>chaps that were his especial pride and care			
<lb/>came out of that brush ragged, soiled and full			
<lb/>of dead leaves, brush and mud.</p>
            <p>He had been delayed at a slough whose sur<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>face of dark green growth gave no intimation			
<lb/>of the muddy quicksands beneath. Stuck hard			
<lb/>in the mud of this pool a terrified heifer was			
<lb/>slowly sinking, while her bawling calf was			
<lb/>restrained from following its mother only			
<lb/>through the quick action of Cheerio, who			
<lb/>drove the distracted little creature a consider<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>able distance into the woods ere he returned to			
<lb/>its mother.</p>
            <p>It is one thing to throw the lariat in an open			
<lb/>space and to land it upon the horns or the back			
<lb/>feet of a fleeing animal. It is another</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 136 ]</fw>
            <pb n="137"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>thing to swing a lariat in a thickly-wooded			
<lb/>bush where the noose is more likely than not			
<lb/>to land securely in the branch or the crotch of			
<lb/>a tree, resisting all tugs and jerks to leave its			
<lb/>secure hold. Cheerio, inexpert with the lariat,			
<lb/>gave up all thought of rescuing the animal in			
<lb/>that way. Instead, his quick wits worked to			
<lb/>devise a more ingenious method of pulling the			
<lb/>heifer from the slough, where she would have			
<lb/>perished without help.</p>
            <p>Along the edges of the woods were fallen			
<lb/>willow trees and bushes that the Indians had			
<lb/>cleaved for future fence posts. Cheerio			
<lb/>hauled a quantity of these over to the slough,			
<lb/>and shoving and piling them in criss-cross sec<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tions, he made a sort of ford to within about			
<lb/>fifteen feet of the mired cow. His horse was			
<lb/>tied by its halter rope to a tree. With one end			
<lb/>of the lariat firmly attached to the pommel of			
<lb/>his saddle which had been cinched on to the			
<lb/>animal very tightly and the other end about			
<lb/>his own waist, Cheerio crossed this ford to<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ward the animal. He now let out the lariat			
<lb/>and coiled its end for the toss. It landed easily</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 137]</fw>
            <pb n="138"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>upon the horns of the animal. Holding to the			
<lb/>rope, now drawn taut, Cheerio made his way			
<lb/>back over the ford. Unfastening his horse, he			
<lb/>mounted. Now began the hard part of the			
<lb/>work. His horse rode out a few feet and the			
<lb/>sudden pull upon the horns of the cow brought			
<lb/>her to her feet. She stumbled and swayed but			
<lb/>the rope held her up. A pause for rest for			
<lb/>horse and heifer, and then another and harder			
<lb/>and longer pull and tug. The cow, half<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>strangled in the mud, nevertheless was drawn			
<lb/>along by the stout lariat rope. She slid along			
<lb/>the slippery floor of the slough and not till her			
<lb/>feet touched sod was she able to give even a			
<lb/>feeble aid to the now heavily-panting mare.</p>
            <p>Once on solid ground, Cheerio burst into a			
<lb/>cheer such as an excited boy might have given,			
<lb/>and he called soothingly to the desperately<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>frightened heifer.</p>
            <p><q>You're doing fine, old girl! There you go!			
<lb/>Ripping!</q> And to the mare:</p>
            <p><q>Good for you, Sally-Ann! You’re a top<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>notcher, old girl!</q></p>
            <p>There was an interval to give the exhausted</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 138 ]</fw>
            <pb n="139"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>animals an opportunity for a rest and then			
<lb/>they were on the bush trail again, the heifer			
<lb/>going slowly ahead, thoroughly tamed and de<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>jected, yet rasing her head with monotonous			
<lb/>regularity to call and moan her long loud cry			
<lb/>for her young.</p>
            <p>As Cheerio came out into the open range			
<lb/>certain words recurred to his mind and he re<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>peated them aloud with elation and pride:</p>
            <p><q>They’s the makings of a damn fine cowboy			
<lb/>in you</q>, had said the foreman of O Bar O.</p>
            <p>He was whooping and hurrahing internally			
<lb/>for himself and he felt as proud of his achieve<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ment as if he had won a hard pitched battle.			
<lb/>In fact, if one reckoned success in the terms			
<lb/>of dollars and of cents, then Cheerio had			
<lb/>saved for O Bar O the considerable sum of			
<lb/>$1500, which was the value of the pure-bred			
<lb/>heifer rescued from the slough. Moreover,			
<lb/>Cheerio had brought from the bush the full			
<lb/>quota of missing cows and their offspring.			
<lb/>When at last he joined up with that steadily<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>growing line pouring down from all parts of			
<lb/>the woods and the ranges, to join in the lower</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 139]</fw>
            <pb n="140"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>meadows, he was whistling and jubilantly			
<lb/>keeping time to his music with the clanking			
<lb/><q>bell</q>, and when he came within sight of his			
<lb/><q>mates</q> he waved his hat above his head, and			
<lb/>rode gleefully down among them, shouting			
<lb/>and boasting of his day’s work. He counted			
<lb/>his cows with triumph before the doubting			
<lb/><q>Thomases</q> who had predicted that the ten<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>derfoot would come out of that dense wood			
<lb/>with half a heifer’s horn and a calf’s foot.</p>
            <p>They rode westward under a sky bright			
<lb/>blue, while facing them, wrapped about in a			
<lb/>haze of soft mauve, the snow-crowned peaks			
<lb/>of the Rocky Mountains towered before them			
<lb/>like adream. The glow of a late summer day			
<lb/>was tinting all of the horizon and rested in			
<lb/>slumberous splendour upon the widespreading			
<lb/>bosom of pastures and meadows and fair un<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>dulating sloping hills. Almost in silence, as			
<lb/>if unconsciously subdued by the beauty of the			
<lb/>day, came the O Bar O outfit, riding ahead,			
<lb/>behind, and flanking the two sides of that mar<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>vellous army of cattle.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 140 ]</fw>
            <pb n="141"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>Small wonder that the Englishman’s heart			
<lb/>beat high and that his blood seemed to race in			
<lb/>his veins with an electrical fervour that comes			
<lb/>from sheer joy and satisfaction with life. If			
<lb/>anyone had asked him whether he regretted			
<lb/>the life he had deliberately sacrificed for this			
<lb/>wild <q>adventure</q> in Western Canada, he			
<lb/>would have shouted with all the vehemence			
<lb/>and it may be some of the typical profanity of			
<lb/>O Bar O:</p>
            <p><q>Not by a blistering pipeful! This is the			
<lb/>life! It’s r-ripping! It’s—Jake!</q></p>
            <p>But now they were at the corrals. Finished			
<lb/>the exhilarating riding of the range, done the			
<lb/>pretty work of cutting out the cattle and draw<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing the herd into that line while one by one			
<lb/>they were passed through the gates that opened			
<lb/>into especial pastures assigned for the mothers,			
<lb/>while the calves that were to be operated upon			
<lb/>were <q>cut out</q> and driven into the corrals.</p>
            <p>Slowly Cheerio tore his gaze from the fas<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>cinating spectacle of that moving stream of			
<lb/>cattle and turned towards the corral. He saw,			
<lb/>first of all, a giant structure, a platform on</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[141 ]</fw>
            <pb n="142"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>which was a gallowslike contrivance. Already			
<lb/>a bawling calf had been driven up the incline			
<lb/>and its head had been gripped by the closing			
<lb/>gates around itsneck. The Squeezegate! The			
<lb/>dehorning shears were being sharpened over			
<lb/>the grindstone and the whirring of the wheel,			
<lb/>the grating of the steel hissed into the moaning			
<lb/>cries of the trapped calves in the corrals.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 142]</fw>
            <pb n="143"/>
         </div>