<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="chapter" n="8">
            <head>Chapter VIII</head>
            <p><hi rendition="#smallcaps">SITTING</hi> in the sunlight on the wide steps			
<lb/>of the ranch house, chin cupped in her hands,			
<lb/>her glance far off across the mountain tops,			
<lb/>her thoughts wandering over the seas that			
<lb/>stretched between the Dominion of Canada			
<lb/>and the Mother-land, Hilda McPherson came			
<lb/>out of her deep reverie to find the object of			
<lb/>her thoughts standing before her. He had a			
<lb/>book in his hand and with the sunny, engag<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing almost boyish smile that was characteristic			
<lb/>of him he was tendering it to the girl on the			
<lb/>steps.</p>
            <p>For some days Cheerio’s discourse on masto<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>dons, dinosaurs and the various species of			
<lb/>the prehistoric days had been extremely vague			
<lb/>and unsatisfactory to his disciple. Matters			
<lb/>reached a climax upon this especial Sunday,			
<lb/>when he had wandered from the matter of a			
<lb/>fossil skeleton recently discovered on the Red			
<lb/>Deer River, said to be one hundred and sixty</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[85]</fw>
            <pb n="86"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>feet long and at least seventy feet tall, with a			
<lb/>sudden question that brought a snort of dis<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>gust from the intensely-interested Sandy.</p>
            <p><q>What’s she got to do with the Mezzozoic			
<lb/>ager</q> he exploded.</p>
            <p>(Note: Cheerio had digressed from the ab<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>sorbing matter of the age of the Red Deer			
<lb/>dinosaurs, to ask suddenly whether Hilda			
<lb/>was likely to be riding with a certain bachelor			
<lb/>rancher whose bronco was tied to the front			
<lb/>of the ranch house when the reluctant Cheerio			
<lb/>and Sandy had ridden away that morning.)</p>
            <p><q>I s-s-suppose</q>, stuttered Cheerio, <q>that			
<lb/>your s-s-sister w-w-will probably be riding			
<lb/>with her caller at the r-r-ranch</q>.</p>
            <p>Sandy’s reply was neither enlightening nor			
<lb/>respectful. He glimpsed his friend with the			
<lb/>shrewd unflattering scrutiny of a wise one, and			
<lb/>presently:</p>
            <p><q>Say, you don’t mean to tell me that you’re			
<lb/>gettin’ stuck on her too!</q></p>
            <p>That was a disturbing question, and more<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>over a revealing one. It plainly disclosed to			
<lb/>the upset Cheerio that there were others</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 86]</fw>
            <pb n="87"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p><q>stuck on</q> Hilda. In fact, Sandy left no			
<lb/>room for doubt as to that.</p>
            <p><q>Holy Hens!</q> went on Hilda’s brother.			
<lb/><q>Half the guys in this country’s got a case on			
<lb/>herf I don’t know what they see in her.			
<lb/>Should think you’d have more common sense</q></p>
            <p>than to pile along in too.</p>
            <p><q>Hilda’s eyes</q>, said the Englishman softly,			
<lb/><q>are as b-brown as loamy soil. They’re like			
<lb/>the dark earth, warm and rich and full of			
<lb/>promise</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Oh, my God—frey!</q> groaned Sandy and			
<lb/>rolled clear down the grassy slope on which			
<lb/>they had been sitting to the more intelligent			
<lb/>and sane company of Viper, a yellow and un<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>lovely cur who was, however, the private and			
<lb/>personal property of Sandy. Viper was at			
<lb/>that moment <q>snooping</q> above a gopher hole.			
<lb/>One intelligent eye and ear cocked up warily,			
<lb/>signalled with canine telepathy to his master			
<lb/>and pal the warning:</p>
            <p><q>Careful! She’s under there! Don’t let on			
<lb/>you and me are above her. I’ll get her for			
<lb/>you. You'll have another tail for your col-</q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[87]</fw>
            <pb n="88"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>lection. Don’t forget there’s a gymkhanna			
<lb/>over at the Minnehaha ranch next month and			
<lb/>the prize for the most gopher tails is five			
<lb/>plunks.</p>
            <p>To this unspoken but perfectly comprehen<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>sible message, Sandy replied:</p>
            <p><q>Betchu we get his tail, Viper! Betchu I			
<lb/>take the prize this year! I got seventy-five			
<lb/>now. Make it seventy-six, Viper, and I’ll give			
<lb/>you eight bones for dinner to-night</q>.</p>
            <p>Cheerio, meanwhile, ruminating painfully			
<lb/>upon Sandy’s revelation, and also upon that			
<lb/>bronco tied to front of the ranch house, and			
<lb/>its good-looking owner who was inside, un<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>able to endure the picture his mind conjured			
<lb/>of Hilda riding off with her caller into their			
<lb/>own (his and Hilda’s) especial sun glow,			
<lb/>jumped in a hurry upon Jim Crow’s back, and			
<lb/>with the best of intentions sped back to			
<lb/>O Bar O.</p>
            <p>It was Sunday afternoon, and such of the			
<lb/>ranch hands as were not off on some courting			
<lb/>or hunting or fishing or riding expedition,			
<lb/>were stretched out on the various cots that</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 88 ]</fw>
            <pb n="89"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>lined the long bunkhouse taking their weekly			
<lb/>siesta. Cheerio himself was accustomed to			
<lb/>spend his Sundays in his cave studio, but in			
<lb/>these latter days—since in fact Hilda had			
<lb/>ceased to ride with them in the evenings—even			
<lb/>the painting had lost its charm for him. He			
<lb/>spent his Sundays in the near vicinity of the			
<lb/>ranch house, his hopeful eyes pinned upon that			
<lb/>wide verandah on to which the girl now so			
<lb/>seldom came.</p>
            <p>Occasionally, as on this Sunday, Sandy			
<lb/>would induce him into short excursions from			
<lb/>the ranch, but Cheerio was restless and unset<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tled now, and far from being the satisfactory			
<lb/>companion and oracle upon whom Sandy had			
<lb/>depended.</p>
            <p>Now as Cheerio paused at the bunkhouse,			
<lb/>he turned over in his mind such small treas<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ures as he possessed. He had a most ardent			
<lb/>desire to endow Hilda with one or all of his			
<lb/>possessions. He was obsessed with a longing			
<lb/>to lay his hands upon certain treasures of a			
<lb/>great house that should have been his own.			
<lb/>His possessions at the ranch were modest</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 89 ]</fw>
            <pb n="90"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>enough. His wages had been spent mainly			
<lb/>for paint and books. He surveyed the crude,			
<lb/>but adequate, book-case he had built himself,			
<lb/>and scanned the volumes laid upon the shelves.			
<lb/>After all, one could offer no finer gift than a			
<lb/>book. He chose carefully, with a thought			
<lb/>rather for what might appeal especially to a			
<lb/>girl of Hilda’s type than his own preferences.</p>
            <p>As he came around the side of the house, he			
<lb/>perceived that the bronco was gone. A mo<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>mentary heartshake over the thought that			
<lb/>Hilda might have gone with it, and then a			
<lb/>great thumping of that sensitive organ as he			
<lb/>saw the girl upon the steps. She was sitting in			
<lb/>the sunlight, staring out before her in a day			
<lb/>dream. Something in the mute droop of the			
<lb/>expressive young mouth and the slight shadow			
<lb/>cast by the lashes against her cheek gave Hilda			
<lb/>a look of singular sadness and depression and			
<lb/>sent her caller impetuously hurrying toward			
<lb/>her. He had come, in fact, directly in front			
<lb/>of her, before the eyes were lifted and Hilda			
<lb/>looked back at him. Slowly the colour swept			
<lb/>like the dawn over her young face, as he ex-</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[90]</fw>
            <pb n="91"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>tended the book, stammering and blushing in			
<lb/>his boyish way.</p>
            <p><q>M-m-m-miss Hilda, I r-r-recommend this			
<lb/>f-for b-b-both pleasure and information. It’s			
<lb/>p-p-part of one’s education to read Dumas</q>.</p>
            <p>Education! The word was inflammatory.			
<lb/>It was an affront to her pride. He was			
<lb/>rubbing in the fact of her appalling ignorance.			
<lb/>‘That was her own affair—her own misfortune.			
<lb/>Hilda sprang to her feet, up in arms, on the			
<lb/>defensive and the offensive. While the aston<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ished Cheerio still extended the book—a silent			
<lb/>peace offering—Hilda’s dark head tossed up,			
<lb/>in that characteristic motion, while her foot			
<lb/>stamped the ground.</p>
            <p><q>I don’t care for that kind of rot, thank you.			
<lb/>My dad’s right. It’s better to be real people			
<lb/>in the world rather than fake folk in a book</q>.</p>
            <p>Again the head toss and the blaze of angry			
<lb/>wide eyes; then, swift as a fawn, Hilda sped			
<lb/>across the verandah and the ranch house door			
<lb/>banged hard.</p>
            <p>Thus might have ended the Dumas incident,			
<lb/>but on the following day, when the men were</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[91]</fw>
            <pb n="92"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>all out on the range, she who had spurned			
<lb/><q>The Three Musketeers</q> slipped out of the			
<lb/>ranch house, over to the grove of trees to the			
<lb/>east and running behind the shelter of these,			
<lb/>so that Chum Lee should not see her as she			
<lb/>passed, made her way swiftly to the bunkhouse.</p>
            <p>Bunkhouses in a ranching country are not			
<lb/>savoury or attractive places as a general rule.			
<lb/>This of the O Bar O was <q>not too bad</q> as the			
<lb/>expression goes in Alberta. It had the virtue			
<lb/>at all events of being clean, thanks to the as<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>siduous care of Chum Lee. Moreover, shift<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>less and dirty fellows found a short job at			
<lb/>O Bar O. Hats and caps, hide shirts, buck<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>skin breeks, chaps and coats were all, there<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>fore, neatly hung along the wall on the row of			
<lb/>deer horns, while under these were piled on			
<lb/>the long shelf the puttees, boots and other gear			
<lb/>of the riders.</p>
            <p>The bunkhouse was lavishly decorated, the			
<lb/>entire walls being covered with pictures cut			
<lb/>from magazines or newspapers or from other			
<lb/>sources and pasted or tacked upon the wall.			
<lb/>Ladies in skin tights of rounded and ample</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[92]</fw>
            <pb n="93"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>curves, in poses calculated to attract the at<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tention of the opposite sex, ravishing beauties,			
<lb/>all more or less with that stage smile in which			
<lb/>all of the dental equipment of their owners,			
<lb/>alluringly displayed, beamed down above the			
<lb/>beds of the riders of O Bar O. Hilda had seen			
<lb/>these often before and they had no especial in<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>terest for her. Her glance travelled instead to			
<lb/>the long table on which was piled the treas<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ured possessions of the men, correspondence			
<lb/>boxes, tobacco, pipes, jack-knives, quirts,			
<lb/>gloves, letters and photographs of friends and			
<lb/>relatives. Nothing on that table would likely			
<lb/>belong to him. Nothing suggested Cheerio.			
<lb/>Her eye went slowly down the row of beds till			
<lb/>it came to rest upon that one pulled out from			
<lb/>the wall till the head was thrust directly un<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>der the widely opened window, by the side of			
<lb/>which stood the crude book-case and stand.			
<lb/>She paused only a moment and then swiftly			
<lb/>crossed to the Englishman’s bed.</p>
            <p>Three of the shelves were filled tightly with			
<lb/>books and the bottom one held a writing folio			
<lb/>and sketch tablet. This Hilda seized upon,</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[93]</fw>
            <pb n="94"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>but stopped before opening it, while the colour			
<lb/>receded from her cheeks. Within that folio,			
<lb/>perhaps, would be found some clue, some			
<lb/>letter from the woman he loved. Yes, Hilda			
<lb/>faced the fact that Cheerio loved the woman			
<lb/>whose pictured face was in the locket, and for			
<lb/>whom he had come to Canada to make a home.			
<lb/>As she held the folio in her hand, she felt a			
<lb/>passionate impulse of shame that fought her			
<lb/>natural curiosity, and caused her to put the			
<lb/>thing back upon the shelf. No! She had not			
<lb/>come to the bunkhouse to spy into a man’s cor<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>respondence. It was only that she suffered			
<lb/>from an unconquerable hunger merely again			
<lb/>to see the other woman’s face; to study it, to			
<lb/>compare it with her own—Oh! to destroy it!			
<lb/>But no, no—she would not stoop so low as to			
<lb/>look at something which he did not wish her			
<lb/>to see.</p>
            <p>The book was a different matter. He had			
<lb/>offered it to her. It was therefore really her			
<lb/>own. Thus argued Hilda within herself. A			
<lb/>quick search along the shelves and she had			
<lb/>picked out the volume she sought. It was</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 94 ]</fw>
            <pb n="95"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>marked number one in the row of books by			
<lb/>Alexandre Dumas. Thrusting it under her			
<lb/>cape, Hilda hurried to the door, and once			
<lb/>again like a scared child who has been stealing			
<lb/>apples, she slipped behind the sheltering			
<lb/>bushes, came from behind them into the open			
<lb/>and sped across the yard to the house.</p>
            <p>All of that morning, Hilda McPherson was			
<lb/>dead to the world. Lying on the great			
<lb/>fragrant heap in the hay loft, she lost herself			
<lb/>in the meshes of one of the most entrancing ro<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>mances that has ever been penned by the hand			
<lb/>of man. She emerged from her retreat at the			
<lb/>dinner hour, brought back to earth by the ar<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>rival of the <q>hands</q> in the barn below. It			
<lb/>was haying time and the men came in from the			
<lb/>fields for their noon meal. Certain of the			
<lb/>horses were changed and relieved and brought</p>
            <p>to the stables for especial feeding. Hiding			
<lb/>her precious book under a pile of hay in a			
<lb/>corner of the loft, Hilda descended, and still			
<lb/>under the spell of the book she had been read<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing all morning, made her way to the house.			
<lb/>It so happened, that in her absorption, she</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[95]</fw>
            <pb n="96"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>had paid little attention to Sandy’s dog, who			
<lb/>leaped up at her as she passed, capered around			
<lb/>her, sought to lick her hands and otherwise in<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>gratiate himself. Absently Hilda ordered him			
<lb/>down.</p>
            <p><q>That will do, Viper! Now cut it out!			
<lb/>Get away! Get away! Shoooo-o-o! Bad			
<lb/>dog! Down!</q></p>
            <p>Duly admonished, spirits but slightly			
<lb/>dampened, Viper repaired to the barn, where			
<lb/>for a spell, with his tongue hanging out and			
<lb/>panting from recent long runs across the land</p>
            <p>after his master on horse, he endeavoured to			
<lb/>attract the attention of such hands as were still			
<lb/>in the barn by an occasional yelp and a moan			
<lb/>of protest when at last the doors were shut			
<lb/>upon him.</p>
            <p>For a little while Viper rested in one of the			
<lb/>stalls; then being young and of an active dis<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>position he arose and stretched himself and			
<lb/>looked about him for diversion. In the nat<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ural course of events, having tired of chasing			
<lb/>the various hens from the stalls and vainly			
<lb/>snapping at persistent fleas, he sniffed along</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[967</fw>
            <pb n="97"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>the trail over which his young mistress (he re<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>garded her as such) had passed. In due time,			
<lb/>therefore, Viper arrived in the loft. Also in			
<lb/>the natural course of events, he nosed around			
<lb/>and dug under the hay, disclosing the hidden			
<lb/>book. He carried this treasure below in his			
<lb/>mouth, and was having quite a jolly time with			
<lb/>it, growling and barking and shaking it and			
<lb/>alternatively letting it go and then pouncing			
<lb/>upon it, when he was interrupted by a well<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>known and much-beloved and sometimes			
<lb/>feared whistle. Joyously, proudly, trium<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>phantly Viper brought his find to his master,			
<lb/>and with the pride of a new mother, laid it at			
<lb/>Sandy’s feet. Wagging his tail furiously and			
<lb/>emitting short, sharp yelps which spoke as elo<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>quently as mere words the dog’s demand for			
<lb/>well-earned praise, he was rewarded from			
<lb/>various pockets of Sandy’s overalls. The			
<lb/>prizes consisted of bones and other edibles			
<lb/><q>swiped</q> from the kitchen through which			
<lb/>Sandy had passed like a streak en route to join			
<lb/>his dog in the barn.</p>
            <p>Sandy now <q>deine appraisingly over the</q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">97 |</fw>
            <pb n="98"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>printed lines of that now ragged volume.			
<lb/>Presently his attention was drawn to one living			
<lb/>line that flashed from the page with the swift			
<lb/>play of the sword of D’Artagnan. Sandy’s			
<lb/>mouth gaped, and his gaze grew intent. Pres<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ently, still reading, he retired from the barn,			
<lb/>and, followed by Viper, climbed aboard a			
<lb/>huge hay wagon that stood beneath the open			
<lb/>window of the big loft.</p>
            <p>All of that afternoon Hilda McPherson			
<lb/>searched in vain for <q>The Three Musketeers</q>.			
<lb/>The mystery of its disappearance from the			
<lb/>loft tormented her, for she had reached a por<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tion of the tale that had to be finished. What			
<lb/>had become of Porthos when—Hilda felt that			
<lb/>she had to know the sequel of that especial			
<lb/>episode <q>or bust</q> with unsatisfied curiosity.			
<lb/>The story had seized upon her imagination.</p>
            <p>The blazing sunlight of the July afternoon			
<lb/>was softening and the mellow tone that would			
<lb/>presently settle into the misty gleam of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>luctantly-ending day was beginning to tint the			
<lb/>land, when Hilda looked forth from the hay</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 98]</fw>
            <pb n="99"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>loft window and perceived something directly			
<lb/>below her that was brick red in colour. It			
<lb/>stuck out from a loaded hay wagon. His dog			
<lb/>curled beside him, half buried in the deep			
<lb/>hay, book propped before him, Sandy, as his			
<lb/>sister had done, had dropped out of this world			
<lb/>of ours and was soaring into realms of another			
<lb/>time.</p>
            <p>Hilda’s eyes widened with amazement and			
<lb/>righteous indignation. A moment of pause			
<lb/>only, poised on the window sill of the loft.			
<lb/>Then down she dropped squarely into the lap			
<lb/>of the great hay wagon. There was the			
<lb/>smothered sound of murmuring and scram<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>bling under the hay; the delighted bark of the			
<lb/>entertained dog, uncertain whether this was a			
<lb/>contest or a game, and then two heads, plenti<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>fully besprinkled with straw and hay arose to			
<lb/>the surface and two wrathful, angry faces			
<lb/>glared across at each other.</p>
            <p><q>That’s mine!</q></p>
            <p><q>Tt ain't!</q></p>
            <p><q>Tt is, I say. I had it first</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Don’t care if you did. Viper found it</q>.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[99]</fw>
            <pb n="100"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p><q>That cur stole it. [hid it in the loft. You			
<lb/>give it up to me, do you hear me?</q></p>
            <p><q>Yeeh, don’t you see me givin’ it up. My			
<lb/>dog found it for me, and finding’s keepings,			
<lb/>seer</q></p>
            <p><q>Sandy, you give me that book, or you’ll be			
<lb/>sorry. It’s mine</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Prove it then</q>.</p>
            <p>A tussle, a tug, a tremendous pull; back and			
<lb/>forth, a fierce wrestle; a scramble and sprawl			
<lb/>over the hay; a whoop of triumph from Hilda			
<lb/>as on the edge of the wagon, with Sandy tem<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>porarily restrained by the hay under which			
<lb/>she had buried him, she paused a second ere			
<lb/>she dropped to the ground almost into the			
<lb/>arms of the highly-edified Cheerio.</p>
            <p>Sandy at last freed from his prison of hay			
<lb/>was upon her tracks, and with a blood-curd<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ling yell of vengeance he leaped to the ground			
<lb/>beside her.</p>
            <p><q>You gimme that book!</q></p>
            <p>At the sight of Cheerio, Hilda’s clasp of			
<lb/>the book had relaxed and it was therefore a			
<lb/>cinch for the attacking Sandy to seize and re-</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 100 ]</fw>
            <pb n="101"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>gain possession of the disputed treasure. From			
<lb/>the boy to the girl the quizzical glance of the			
<lb/>Englishman turned.</p>
            <p><q>I s-say, old man, b-believe that’s m-my			
<lb/>book, d’you know</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Then she mus’ve swiped it, ’cause Viper			
<lb/>found it in the hay loft and that’s where she			
<lb/>always hides to read, so Dad won’t ketch her</q>.</p>
            <p>Hilda had turned first white and then rosily			
<lb/>red. She felt that her face was scorching and			
<lb/>smarting tears bit at her eyelids waiting to			
<lb/>drop. One indeed did roll down the round			
<lb/>sun-burnt cheek and splashed visibly upon her			
<lb/>hand right before the now thoroughly con<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>cerned Cheerio. His face stiffened sternly as			
<lb/>he looked at Sandy, and reaching over he re<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>covered his book. Quietly he extended it to			
<lb/>Hilda. Sandy thereupon pressed his claim in			
<lb/>loud and emphatic language.</p>
            <p><q>That ain’t fair. She’s just turnin’ on her			
<lb/>old water-works so’s to make you give her the			
<lb/>book. It ain’t fair. I’m just up to that part			
<lb/>where Porthos and——</q></p>
            <p>Hilda made no motion to take the book.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 101 ]</fw>
            <pb n="102"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>Two more tears rolled to join their first com<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>panion. Hilda could no more have stayed			
<lb/>the course of those flowing tears than she			
<lb/>could have dammed up the ocean with her			
<lb/>little hand. She was forced to stand there,			
<lb/>openly crying, before the man she had so often			
<lb/>assured herself that she hated. Far from			
<lb/><q>gloating over</q> her humiliation as she			
<lb/>imagined he was doing, Cheerio, as he looked			
<lb/>at the weeping girl, was himself consumed			
<lb/>with the most tender of emotions. He longed			
<lb/>to take her into his arms and to comfort and</p>
            <p>reassure her.</p>
            <p><q>Tell you what Tll do</q>, said Cheerio,			
<lb/>gently. <q>I’ll read the story to you both. What			
<lb/>do you say? An hour or two every evening			
<lb/>while the light lasts. Wh-when we’re through			
<lb/>with this one, w-we’'ll tackle others. There’s			
<lb/>three sequels to this, and we’ll read them all.			
<lb/>Then we'll go at the ‘Count of Monte Christo.’			
<lb/>Th-that’s a remarkable yarn!</q></p>
            <p><q>Three sequels! My aunt’s old hat!</q> yelled			
<lb/>the delighted Sandy, tossing his ragged head			
<lb/>gear into the air. <q>Gee whillikins!</q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 102 ]</fw>
            <pb n="103"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>But Cheerio was looking at Hilda, intently,			
<lb/>appealingly. Her face had lighted, and a			
<lb/>strange shyness seemed to come over it, reluct<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>antly, sweetly. The long lashes quivered. She			
<lb/>looked into the beaming face bent eagerly to<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ward her own, and for the first time since they			
<lb/>had met, right through her tears that still per<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>sisted strangely enough in dropping, she			
<lb/>smiled at Cheerio.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 103 ]</fw>
            <pb n="104"/>
         </div>