<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="chapter" n="20">
            <head>Chapter XX</head>
            <p><hi rendition="#smallcaps">THE</hi> shooting season was at hand. At fre<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>quent intervals along the fence lines of			
<lb/>O Bar O, big square slabs of white enamelled			
<lb/>wood were nailed to fence posts, bearing in			
<lb/>great black letters the legend:</p>
            <p>TRESPASSING FORBIDDEN			
<lb/>Punished to fullest extent of law.			
<lb/>BEWARE THE DOGS			
<lb/>P. D. MCPHERSON, Owner.</p>
            <p>These daunted not the more persistent and			
<lb/>intrepid of the hunters, who slipped into this			
<lb/>game paradise through the medium of the			
<lb/>gate under the Ghost River Bridge on the			
<lb/>Banff Highway. Pitching camp near the			
<lb/>road, they penetrated up the great canyon and			
<lb/>into the luring woods of the forbidden			
<lb/>country.</p>
            <p>Duncan Mallison, whose vacation was			
<lb/>drawing to a close, resented any intrusion upon</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 238 ]</fw>
            <pb n="239"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>his privacy. He had begun almost to regard			
<lb/>the place as his own private and personal pre<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>serve. Trespassers irritated and interrupted			
<lb/>him. Reluctantly, he made a final shoot of			
<lb/>Hungarian partridge and prairie chicken—			
<lb/>enough to go the rounds of the newspaper			
<lb/>office—packed his camping outfit, and pre<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>pared to depart from the vicinity of O Bar O.</p>
            <p>He had a moderately good feature story, but			
<lb/>had been obliged to do a lot of padding,			
<lb/>elaborating and exaggerating on the amount			
<lb/>of gambling done and the odds on P. D. He			
<lb/>was not satisfied with his <q>story</q>. He just			
<lb/><q>sniffed the edges</q> of a story big enough to			
<lb/>syndicate in a dozen or more papers over the			
<lb/>country and perhaps find a place also across			
<lb/>the line. His nose for news and his inherent			
<lb/>sense of romance scented another kind of story			
<lb/>atO Bar O. This Englishman—whatever his			
<lb/>name was (of course, Cheerio was merely a			
<lb/>nickname) interested the reporter. It was			
<lb/>plain that he was no ordinary ranch hand.			
<lb/>Who, then, was he, and what was he doing			
<lb/>working on a ranch?</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 239 ]</fw>
            <pb n="240"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p><q>Younger son</q>, and, for that matter, older			
<lb/>sons, were not uncommon in the Alberta			
<lb/>ranching country. It was in fact, an ideal			
<lb/>place, for the disposal of ne’er-do-wells, and			
<lb/>if they had the <q>stuff</q> in them to make real			
<lb/>men of them. The reporter had come into			
<lb/>contact with a great many of these quite lik<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>able chaps from the old country, especially			
<lb/>upon those periodical occasions when remit<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tances from home were due, they came to town			
<lb/>to spend a monthly allowance in a single night,			
<lb/>or several days of unadulterated spreeing.			
<lb/>They were not noted especially for their love			
<lb/>of work, though there was good stuff in most			
<lb/>of them as was proved when the war broke			
<lb/>out and a large percentage of the men who			
<lb/>marched from Alberta were of English birth.</p>
            <p>This Cheerio fellow was somehow different.			
<lb/>Mallison could not exactly place him. He			
<lb/>worked. In point of fact, Cheerio was re<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>puted to be one of the best workers atO Bar O			
<lb/>and really earned his modest $50 a month.			
<lb/>Nevertheless, the newspaper man recognised			
<lb/>him at once as a man of education and breed-</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 240 ]</fw>
            <pb n="241"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>ing. Mallison had heard the story of the			
<lb/>branding, and of the confession that had fol<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>lowed. Sandy was prone to exaggeration, and			
<lb/>the reporter, sifting the facts in the case, was</p>
            <p>disposed to question whether this incident			
<lb/>should be regarded seriously. From Cheerio			
<lb/>himself he learned scarcely nothing. Several			
<lb/>times intent upon acquiring a real interview			
<lb/>with the man, he was exasperated to discover			
<lb/>after Cheerio had left him that Cheerio, on the			
<lb/>contrary, had interviewed him. He was ex<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tremely interested, apparently, in newspaper			
<lb/>work, and asked the reporter many questions			
<lb/>concerning the sort of papers supported by the			
<lb/>City of Calgary, and also what opportunity			
<lb/>there might be for a man to get a berth on one			
<lb/>of these as a caricaturist or newspaper artist.</p>
            <p>Ruminating over the matter, the reporter			
<lb/>lay flat upon the ground on his back, hands			
<lb/>under the back of his head, staring straight up			
<lb/>at the interlacing branches of a giant spruce			
<lb/>tree, through which the sunlight glistened and			
<lb/>danced. Presently his reverie was disturbed.			
<lb/>There was the flurry and flutter of wings and</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 241 ]</fw>
            <pb n="242"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>up out of the bush there arose a couple of			
<lb/>grouse—wavered above his head a moment,			
<lb/>then dropped down behind the somewhat fan<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tastic rock that jutted out above the river.</p>
            <p><q>Doggone those hunters!</q></p>
            <p>They were a distinct menace in the woods			
<lb/>of O BarO. They shot at anything and every<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>thing.</p>
            <p>The bushes at the back of the reporter were			
<lb/>violently agitated, and a fat red face presently			
<lb/>was thrust cautiously through. A man carry<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing a shot-gun, and dressed in knickers and			
<lb/>khaki hunting coat with numerous little shell			
<lb/>pockets, trod through the bush. Reporter and			
<lb/>hunter scowled at each other. Here was no			
<lb/>entente cordiale.</p>
            <p><q>Did you see where my birds dropped?</q></p>
            <p><q>Did you see those trespass signs along the			
<lb/>road?</q> was the reply.</p>
            <p><q>Did you see them yourself?</q> retorted the			
<lb/>other.</p>
            <p><q>You bet I did, and I’m here to see that			
<lb/>others see them, too</q>.</p>
            <p>Turning back his coat, Mallison revealed a</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 242 ]</fw>
            <pb n="243"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>bright star pinned to his vest. Now, that star			
<lb/>represented the fact that the reporter had cer<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tain rights at fires and other places where the			
<lb/>press is permitted to be represented ; but to the			
<lb/>hunter it looked fearfully like the star that a			
<lb/>game warden might carry. He essayed a con<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ciliating laugh, while backing hastily toward			
<lb/>the exit at the bridge outside of which his			
<lb/>Studebaker was parked. He got into it in a			
<lb/>great hurry.</p>
            <p>Grinning, Mallison sat up, his eye upon the			
<lb/>out-jutting rock where the grouse had fallen.			
<lb/>Lazily he stretched himself; leisurely he			
<lb/>climbed up the cliff to the rock and lightly he			
<lb/>dropped down in Cheerio’s cave.</p>
            <p>He swung around in a circle, blinking his			
<lb/>eyes and emitting a long, amazed whistle.</p>
            <p>For the next half hour he was a very busy			
<lb/>reporter. Aladdin’s cave could have afforded			
<lb/>him no more satisfaction or interest.</p>
            <p>The Indian pictures were ranged along a			
<lb/>shelf in the natural gallery that stretched			
<lb/>under the rock for a space of about thirty feet.			
<lb/>It was amply lighted and completely shel-</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 243 ]</fw>
            <pb n="244"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>tered. As Mallison went down the line of			
<lb/>pictures he realized that here was indeed a rare			
<lb/>find.</p>
            <p>Colour had been splashed prodigally upon			
<lb/>the canvasses. Maroon, lemon, magenta, scar<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>let, vivid purple, cerise, blues, flame colour.			
<lb/>Indian colours! Indian faces! Here was			
<lb/>more than a mere tribe of Indians. The artist			
<lb/>had stamped indelibly upon the canvas a reve<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>lation of the history of a passing race. He			
<lb/>had painted the Iliad of the Indian race.</p>
            <p>Here was an ancient chief, grave, stern as			
<lb/>a judge, with the dignity of a king and a			
<lb/>pride that all the squalor and poverty and			
<lb/>starvation of a long, hard life, the repression			
<lb/>and tyranny at the hands of successive Indian			
<lb/>agents and parasites upon his race, had been			
<lb/>unable to quench.</p>
            <p>Here, the infinitely old and wrinkled, tooth<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>less, witch-like great-great-grandmother of the			
<lb/>tribe, a crone who mumbled prophetic warn<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ings to which the lightest-hearted paid super<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>stitious heed. And here the blind Medicine			
<lb/>Man.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 244 ]</fw>
            <pb n="245"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>Smiling, wheedling, begging, the pleas<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>antly-plump shining-faced squaws. The			
<lb/>Braves, young and old, variously clad, some			
<lb/>clinging to the garb of their ancestors, or wear<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing the holiday dress, gaudy Hudson’s Bay			
<lb/>blankets and rugs and headdresses of eagle or			
<lb/>turkey feathers; others in the half cowboy,			
<lb/>half Indian clothes, and others again poorly			
<lb/>attired in the mockery of the white man’s			
<lb/>clothes.</p>
            <p>Thin faces, deep and hungry-eyed, with			
<lb/>that. subdued look that tells not so much of the			
<lb/>conquering hand of the white man as of the in<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>sidious effects of the great white plague.</p>
            <p>Tragic faces of half-breeds, pawns of an un<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>desired fate. Something of smouldering wild<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ness, something of sadness, something of in<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tense longing and wistfulness looked from the			
<lb/>strange eyes of the breeds, legally white and			
<lb/>permitted the <q>privilege</q> of the franchise,			
<lb/>subject to conscription and taxation, yet			
<lb/>doomed to live among their red kindred.</p>
            <p>Beauty peered from the half-lifted ragged			
<lb/>magenta shawl of an Indian Madonna, upon</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 245 ]</fw>
            <pb n="246"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>whose back the tiny blonde head of a blue<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>eyed papoose told a story more eloquent than			
<lb/>words.</p>
            <p>This, then, was the <q>find</q> of the newspaper			
<lb/>man. Of the pictures, he selected six. He had			
<lb/>no compunction about helping himself. It			
<lb/>was part of his trade, and he had discovered			
<lb/>the cave. What is more, he cherished the en<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>thusiastic ambition of making the unknown			
<lb/>artist famous. There were people in Calgary			
<lb/>who would appreciate what this man had done.			
<lb/>Mallison intended to show his find to these			
<lb/>connoisseurs.</p>
            <p>From the Indian pictures, he turned to the			
<lb/>portfolio of sketches. Several of Sandy and			
<lb/>the ranch hands, one of Bully Bill, with the			
<lb/>quid of tobacco in his cheek, a characteristic			
<lb/>bit of old P. D., one of Viper at the heels of			
<lb/>the milk cows, a stream of cattle pouring over			
<lb/>the hill, and—Hilda! One hundred and			
<lb/>eighteen sketches of Hilda McPherson. Now			
<lb/>the reporter understood, and he chuckled with			
<lb/>sympathy. He did not blame the man. He			
<lb/>had seen Hilda!</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 246 ]</fw>
            <pb n="247"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>From the portfolio, Mallison selected two			
<lb/>or three sketches of P. D., one of Sandy, three			
<lb/>of Hilda, and a single photograph of Cheerio,			
<lb/>taken evidently in France, and in uniform.			
<lb/>He was easily recognizable. There was no			
<lb/>mistaking that boyish and friendly smile, that			
<lb/>seemed somehow to irradiate and make singu<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>larly interesting the essentially sensitive fea<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tures of the young Englishman.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 247 J</fw>
            <pb n="248"/>
         </div>