<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="chapter" n="5">
            <head>Chapter V</head>
            <p><hi rendition="#smallcaps">ONE</hi> there was at O Bar O who could not be			
<lb/>reconciled to Cheerio. Hilda intuitively rec<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ognized the fact that this stranger on the ranch			
<lb/>belonged to that <q>upper world</q> of which she			
<lb/>knew vaguely through the medium of news<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>papers and tawdry literature emanating from			
<lb/>the bunkhouse. Even the Encyclopedia had			
<lb/>furnished the girl with information concern<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing kings and princes, lords and dukes, and			
<lb/>earls that abounded in diverse places in the			
<lb/>old world. <q>Bloody parasites</q>, her father had			
<lb/>named them, <q>living for generations off the			
<lb/>blood and sweat and toil of the poor, blind			
<lb/>underdogs who had not the intelligence or the			
<lb/>‘sand’ to unseat them from power</q>.</p>
            <p>Her fiery young nature was up in arms at the			
<lb/>thought of <q>that Englishman’s patronage</q>.			
<lb/>No doubt, thought the proud, hot-headed and			
<lb/>ignorant girl, <q>he looks down on us as poor			
<lb/>Rubes. Well, we’ll show him a thing or two</q>,</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[55]</fw>
            <pb n="56"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>and she urged the men on to torment and make			
<lb/>uneasy the life of Cheerio.</p>
            <p>Thorny and suspicious, with her free head			
<lb/>toss, so characteristic of her young, wild na<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ture, her eyes intensely dark, fixed above his			
<lb/>head, or surveying him as from an amused			
<lb/>and contemptuous height, Hilda left no op<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>portunity neglected to show her scorn and			
<lb/>contempt for the newcomer. She could not			
<lb/>herself have diagnosed the reason for her hos<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tility.</p>
            <p>Sandy, on the other hand, had slowly but			
<lb/>completely capitulated to the man whose first			
<lb/>appearance had so amused him. In Alberta,			
<lb/>daylight lingers, in the summer time, till as			
<lb/>late as ten o’clock at night. When the day’s			
<lb/>work was done, Sandy and his new friend,			
<lb/>would depart from the ranch on a hunt that			
<lb/>was new to the cattle country. They hunted,			
<lb/>in fact, for fossils, whitened, hardened bones			
<lb/>of the original denizens of the land that had			
<lb/>existed before the Rocky Mountains had			
<lb/>sprung into being by some gigantic convulsion			
<lb/>of nature.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 56]</fw>
            <pb n="57"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>Zoology was a subject that exercised an un<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>canny fascination over the mind of the red<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>haired boy. P. D. had scarcely begun the			
<lb/>instruction of this alluring subject when chess			
<lb/>diverted him, much to the disappointment and			
<lb/>aggravation of his son. Cheerio, however,			
<lb/>proved a mine of information in this particu<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>lar field. He had actually once been a mem<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ber of an archeological expedition to Thibet,			
<lb/>from whose bowels the bones of the oldest man			
<lb/>in the world had been dug. Sandy could have			
<lb/>sat by the hour listening to the tales of that			
<lb/>expedition and its remarkable contribution to			
<lb/>science. It was an even more enthralling ex<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>perience for the youngster, therefore, to per<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>sonally explore the wild canyons above the			
<lb/>Ghost River, and, with bated excitement, |			
<lb/>himself assist in picking out on the gigantic			
<lb/>rocks what Cheerio definitely proved were			
<lb/>bones of a dinosaur. These immense rep<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tiles of prehistoric days were quite common			
<lb/>to the Red Deer district, but the new <q>hand</q>			
<lb/>of the O Bar O had proven that they were to			
<lb/>be found also along the Ghost River canyons.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[57]</fw>
            <pb n="58"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>Many atime, sitting on the bank of			
<lb/>the river, waiting for the wary trout to			
<lb/>bite, the slowly-drawling, seldom-stammering			
<lb/>Cheerio, pictured to the bulging-eyed, open<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>mouthed youngster, the giant reptiles and			
<lb/>mountainous mammals of prehistoric days.			
<lb/>He even drew life-like pictures upon scraps			
<lb/>of paper, which Sandy carefully cherished			
<lb/>and consigned to his treasure drawer. Sandy,			
<lb/>at such times, came as near to touching com<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>plete satisfaction with life as was possible.</p>
            <p>His defection, in favour of Cheerio, how<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ever, was a bitter pill for his sister to swal<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>low. Argue and squabble, wrangle and fight			
<lb/>as the young McPherson’s had done all of			
<lb/>their lives, for they were of a healthy, pugna<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>cious disposition, they nevertheless had al<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ways been first-rate chums, and in a way, a			
<lb/>defensive and offensive alliance to which no			
<lb/>outsider had been permitted more than a			
<lb/>look-in. Now <q>that Englishman</q> had come			
<lb/>between them, according to Hilda. Sandy			
<lb/>evidently preferred his society to that of his			
<lb/>own and only sister. Thus, bitter Hilda.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 58]</fw>
            <pb n="59"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>Sandy upbraided, reproached and sneered at,			
<lb/>grouchily allowed that she could come along			
<lb/>too if she wanted to and <q>didn’t interfere or			
<lb/>talk too much</q>. Girls, he brutally averred,			
<lb/>were a doggone, darned old nuisance, and al<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ways in the way when something real was be<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing done. They were well enough as orna<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ments, said Sandy, but the female of the spe<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>cies was not meant for practical purposes and			
<lb/>they ought to know and keep their place, and			
<lb/>if they wouldn’t do it, why they’d be made to.			
<lb/>This was adding insult to injury. It proved			
<lb/>beyond question that someone had _ been			
<lb/><q>setting her brother against her</q>, and Hilda			
<lb/>knew who that someone was. Sandy knew			
<lb/>absolutely nothing about the <q>female of the			
<lb/>species</q>—that, by the way, was a brand new			
<lb/>expression to the young McPhersons—and			
<lb/>Hilda proposed to <q>teach him a thing or two</q>			
<lb/>about her much maligned sex. Also she			
<lb/>would <q>spite that Englishman</q> who had in<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>fluenced her brother against her, by imposing			
<lb/>her unwanted society upon the explorers.			
<lb/>Each evening, therefore, Hilda was on</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[59]</fw>
            <pb n="60"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>hand, and she arose before dawn of a Sunday			
<lb/>morning—a time when all hands on the ranch			
<lb/>were accustomed to sleep in late—to ride out			
<lb/>with them under the grey-gold skies, with the			
<lb/>air fresh and sparkling, and such a stillness			
<lb/>on all sides that one felt loth to break it by			
<lb/>even a murmur.</p>
            <p>She rode somewhat behind the <q>bone en<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>thusiasts</q>, disdaining to ride abreast with			
<lb/>them, or to join in the unintelligible conversa<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tion that presently would begin. No brush			
<lb/>was too thick to hold back this girl of the			
<lb/>ranching country; no trail too intricate or			
<lb/>tortuous. Foot wide ledges, over precipices			
<lb/>three and four hundred feet above the river			
<lb/>daunted her not. Hilda held her careless			
<lb/>. seat on the back of her surefooted and fleet			
<lb/>young Indian pony, and if the path crumbled			
<lb/>away in places too perilous for even a foothill			
<lb/>horse to pass, Hilda dismounted and led him,			
<lb/>breaking a trail herself through dense timber			
<lb/>land.</p>
            <p>True, bones, whether of prehistoric man or			
<lb/>mammal, had no actual interest for the living</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 60 ]</fw>
            <pb n="61"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>girl. Sandy’s passion for such things indeed			
<lb/>puzzled and troubled her, inasmuch as she			
<lb/>was unable to share it with him. It was			
<lb/>strangely sweet and pleasant, none the less, to			
<lb/>ride out in the quiet dawn or in the evening			
<lb/>when the skies were bronzed and reddened by			
<lb/>the still lingering sun. With every day, they			
<lb/>found new trails, new byways, new depres<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>sions in the wild woods of O Bar O.</p>
            <p>On these excursions Sandy monopolized			
<lb/>the conversation and, in a measure, Hilda			
<lb/>was ignored. Cheerio’s concern in her behalf			
<lb/>when first they had penetrated into difficult</p>
            <p>woods and his offer to lead her horse had met			
<lb/>with haughty and bitter rebuff. Hilda, in-</p>
            <p>deed, rudely suggested that she was better			
<lb/>able to care for herself than he was. Also she			
<lb/>said:</p>
            <p><q>Don’t bother about me. Ride on with			
<lb/>Sandy. I like to ride alone, and I don’t care			
<lb/>for conversation when I ride</q>.</p>
            <p>Sandy more than made up for his sister’s			
<lb/>conversational deficiency. He was a human			
<lb/>interrogation point, and his hunger for’</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[61]</fw>
            <pb n="62"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>knowledge in matters anent man and beast of			
<lb/>ancient days was unquenchable.</p>
            <p>Hilda, riding a few paces behind, would			
<lb/>listen to the endless questions popped by the			
<lb/>eager boy, and secretly marvel at the always			
<lb/>comprehensible replies of his companion.			
<lb/>Sometimes she was tempted to join in the dis<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>cussions; but her opinions were never solici<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ted by her brother or Cheerio. As the two			
<lb/>rode on, apparently oblivious of her very ex<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>istence, Hilda was torn with mixed emotions.			
<lb/>She had scornfully advised Cheerio not to			
<lb/>bother her; nevertheless, she was indignant			
<lb/>at thus being ignored. <q>I might just as well			
<lb/>be an old pack pony</q>, she thought wrathfully.			
<lb/><q>T don’t know why I come along anyway.			
<lb/>However, I’m not going to turn back for that			
<lb/>Englishman. Not if I know it</q>.</p>
            <p>Cheerio, on the other hand, was not insen<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>sible to that small, uplifted chin and the dis<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>dainful glance of the dark eyes that seemed to			
<lb/>harden when they glanced in his direction.			
<lb/>He was not versed in the ways of a woman,			
<lb/>or it may be that Hilda’s treatment of him</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 62 ]</fw>
            <pb n="63"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>would not have wounded him so sorely.			
<lb/>Cheerio was not stupid; but he was singularly			
<lb/>dense in certain matters. He pondered much			
<lb/>over the matter of how he could possibly have			
<lb/>offended the girl, and the thought that she			
<lb/>very evidently disliked him was hard to bear.			
<lb/>That cut deep.</p>
            <p>Many a night, pipe in mouth, upon the			
<lb/>steps of the bunkhouse, Cheerio would de<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>bate the matter within himself. Why did			
<lb/>Hilda dislike him? What was there about			
<lb/>him that should arouse her especial scorn and			
<lb/>contempt? Why should her eyes harden and			
<lb/>her whole personality seem to stiffen at his			
<lb/>approach? Almost it seemed as if the girl			
<lb/>armoured herself against him. He could find			
<lb/>no answer to his questions, and his troubled			
<lb/>meditations would end with the dumping of			
<lb/>his pipe, as he shook his head again in the			
<lb/>puzzle of womanhood, and ruefully turned in</p>
            <p>for the night. Sometimes he would lie awake			
<lb/>for hours, and wholly against his will the vis<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ion of her small, dark face, with its scarlet</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 63 ]</fw>
            <pb n="64"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>lips and deep brown eyes accompanied him			
<lb/>into the world of sleep.</p>
            <p>About this time, he began to draw sketches			
<lb/>of Hilda. He made them at odd moments; at			
<lb/>the noon hour, when he scratched them on the			
<lb/>backs of envelopes, slips of paper, a bit of			
<lb/>cardboard torn from a box. Presently parcels			
<lb/>were brought by an Indian on horseback from			
<lb/>the Morley Trading Store, and after that			
<lb/>Cheerio began to paint the face of the girl			
<lb/>whom he believed hated him. It is true that			
<lb/>his model sat not for him. Yet she was drawn			
<lb/>from life, for his memory drew her back as			
<lb/>faithfully as though they were standing face			
<lb/>to face. This was all secret work, done in			
<lb/>secret places, and packed away in the locked			
<lb/>portfolio, which was in that battered grip.			
<lb/>Drawing and painting in this way was not at			
<lb/>all satisfactory to the artist, who felt that he			
<lb/>was not doing Hilda justice. His need of a			
<lb/>place, where he might work, undisturbed, was			
<lb/>keenly felt by him. Cheerio, as before men<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tioned, was the one <q>hand</q> at the ranch who			
<lb/>daily visited the Ghost River for bathing</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 64 ]</fw>
            <pb n="65"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>purposes. He would arise an hour before the			
<lb/>other men and was off on horse to the river,			
<lb/>returning fresh and clean for breakfast and			
<lb/>the long day’s work. His explorations with			
<lb/>Sandy and these daily expeditions to the			
<lb/>river had made him very well acquainted			
<lb/>with the Ghost River canyon. One day,			
<lb/>scanning thoughtfully the rockbound river,			
<lb/>he perceived what appeared to be a declivity			
<lb/>in the side of a giant rock that jutted out sev<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>eral feet above the river. Out of curiosity,			
<lb/>Cheerio climbed up the cliff, and discovered			
<lb/>a small cave, part of which was so cleft that			
<lb/>the light poured through. His first thought			
<lb/>was of Sandy, and the fun the boy would			
<lb/>have exploring through what was evidently a			
<lb/>considerable tunnel. His next thought was			
<lb/>that on account of the nature of the earth, this			
<lb/>might prove a dangerous and hazardous un<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>dertaking for an adventurous youngster. Sud<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>denly an inspiration flashed over Cheerio.			
<lb/>Here was the ideal studio. Not in the tunnel,			
<lb/>on whose ledge he could very well keep his			
<lb/>work, but in that round natural chamber near</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 65 ]</fw>
            <pb n="66"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>the opening, when the north light was hus<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>banded. It did not take him long to bring			
<lb/>his drawing and painting paraphernalia to			
<lb/>his <q>studio</q>, and after a few days he fashioned			
<lb/>a rude sort of easel for himself. Here on a			
<lb/>Sunday Cheerio worked, and during that day			
<lb/>of rest the ranch saw him not. He would			
<lb/>carry his lunch with him, and depart for the			
<lb/>day, much to the bewilderment of Hilda and			
<lb/>the disappointment of Sandy, unwilling to			
<lb/>abandon the Sunday morning exploration			
<lb/>trips. The cave was so situated that his			
<lb/>privacy was complete, and anyone coming			
<lb/>along the top of the canyon or even down the			
<lb/>river itself could not have seen the man in the			
<lb/>cave a few feet above, quietly smoking and			
<lb/>drawing those impressionistic pictures of the			
<lb/>ranch, the Indians, the cowboys, P.D., the			
<lb/>overall-clad Sandy and Hilda. Hilda on			
<lb/>horse, flying like the wind at the head of the			
<lb/>cowboys; Hilda, loping slowly along the			
<lb/>trail, with her head dropped in a day dream,			
<lb/>that brought somehow a singularly wistful			
<lb/>and touching expression of longing to the</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[66]</fw>
            <pb n="67"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>lovely young face; Hilda with hand on hip,			
<lb/>head tossed up, defiant, impudent, fascinat<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing; Hilda’s head, with its crown of choco<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>late-coloured hair and the darker eyes, the			
<lb/>curiously dusky red that seemed burned by			
<lb/>the sun into her cheeks, and the lips that were			
<lb/>so vividly alive and scarlet.</p>
            <p>Of all his subjects, she alone he drew from			
<lb/>memory. He had found no difficulty in in<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ducing his other subjects to <q>pose</q> for him.			
<lb/>Even P. D. with old pipe twisted in the			
<lb/>corner of his mouth had made no demur when			
<lb/>Cheerio, pad and pencil in hand, seated on			
<lb/>the steps of the ranch-house rapidly sketched			
<lb/>his employer. The Indians were a never<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>failing source of inspiration to the artist. The			
<lb/>chubby babies, the child mothers, the tawny			
<lb/>braves, the ragged, old, shuffling women;			
<lb/>Indian colours—magentas, yellows, orange,			
<lb/>scarlet, cerise. ‘They furnished subjects for			
<lb/>the artist that made his paintings seem			
<lb/>fairly to blaze with light, and later were to win			
<lb/>for him well-deserved fame and monetary re<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ward. Cheerio would take these miniature</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 67 ]</fw>
            <pb n="68"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>sketches to his studio, and there enlarge them.			
<lb/>Hilda, however, whom above all things in the			
<lb/>world, he desired to paint, somehow eluded			
<lb/>him. No matter how lifelike or well-drawn			
<lb/>his pictures of this girl, they never wholly sat<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>isfied him. Indeed it was not one of his draw<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ings, but a little kodak picture of her, ac<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>quired from Sandy, that found its way into			
<lb/>the ancient locket, where previously had been			
<lb/>the picture of the woman with the long sleepy			
<lb/>eyes and dead-gold hair.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 68 ]</fw>
            <pb n="69"/>
         </div>