<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="chapter" n="26">
   <head>Chapter XXVI</head>
   <p>P. D. was taking his <q>cat-nap</q> that evening in his <q>office</q>, a room that opened off from the dining-room, where the old rancher kept his account books and other papers connected with the running of his business. He was enjoying a sweet sleep, in which he dreamed of three white pawns checking a black King. The three pawns were his. The King was Cheerio’s. Something unpleasant and having nothing to do with the soothing picture he was enjoying, awoke him. He blinked fiercely, cleared his throat, sat up in the big chair, and glared disapprovingly at his daughter who had precipitated herself almost into his lap.</p>
   <p><q>What is the meaning of this? Is it, then, 8.30?</q></p>
   <p><q>No, Dad. You've quarter of an hour still</q>.</p>
   <p><q>Then what in thunderation do you mean by waking me for, then? Get away! Get away!</q></p>
   <pb n="291"/>
   <p>I don’t like to be pawed over in this manner.</p>
   <p><q>Dad, I want to talk to you about something. IJ—I must talk to you</q>.</p>
   <p><q>When you wish to talk to me, you will choose an hour when I have the leisure to hear you</q>.</p>
   <p><q>Dad, you won’t let me speak to you through the day. You always say you're calculating something, and now you simply must listen to me. It’s vitally important that you should. You must!</q></p>
   <p><q>Must, hehr</q></p>
   <p><q>Please, Dad!</q></p>
   <p><q>Well, well, what is it? Speak up. Speak up</q>.</p>
   <p>He took his watch out, glanced at it, scowled, paid no attention to what his daughter was saying until the word <q>chess</q> escaped her, when his glance fixed her.</p>
   <p><q>What's that?</q></p>
   <p><q>I said if you’d only defend your King instead of everlastingly attacking, don’t you see, you'd stand a better chance. I’ve noticed on</q><pb n="292"/> two or three occasions that he’s left great openings where I’m sure you could</p>
   <p><q>Are you trying to teach your father the game of chess?</q></p>
   <p><q>Oh, no, Dad, but you know, two heads are better than one. I’ve heard you say so</q>.</p>
   <p><q>Two mature heads——</q></p>
   <p><q>Mine’s mature. I’m eighteen, and I think, </q></p>
   <p><q>You're not supposed to think. You're not equipped for thinking. Women have a con-</q></p>
   <p>stitutional brain impediment that absolutely prevents them coherently or rationally ———</p>
   <p><q>Dad, look here. Don’t you know that it’s November 2oth? The cattle are still on the range and everybody in the country is talking about us. They think we’ve gone plumb crazy. And why? Just because he wants to go on and on beating you and——_</q></p>
   <p><q>What's this? What’s this? A discourse of depreciation of a prized employee of O Bar Oe</q></p>
   <p><q>Father!</q> Hilda seldom called her father</p>
   <pb n="293"/>
   <p><q>Father</q>, but she believed herself to be in a desperate situation and desperate speech and measures were necessary. <q>Father, you have simply got to beat him to-night. You-——</q></p>
   <p><q>You leave the room, miss</q>,</p>
   <p><q>Dad, I </q></p>
   <p><q>Leave the room!</q> roared P. D.</p>
   <p><q>Oh, if you only knew how unhappy I am</q>, cried Hilda piteously. Her father took her by the shoulders and turned her bodily out, closing the door sharply between them, and</p>
   <p>returning to pace the floor of his own office, and work off some of the upsetting influences which might not be well for that calmness and poise of mind necessary for a game of chess.</p>
   <p>The ranch house was a great, unwieldy building, with a wide hall dividing on one side the enormous living-room and on the other the dining-room, beyond which was P. D.’s office and study.</p>
   <p>Hilda shot out of her father’s office into the darkened dining-room, and from there into the lighted hall, where she collided with the<pb n="294"/> entering Cheerio. On him, she turned the last vials of her wrath.</p>
   <p><q>I’ve something to say to you. Everything on this ranch is at a standstill on your account. If we don’t gather in our cattle soon, there'll be a lot of lost and dead O Bar O stock when the first blizzard comes. I wish you’d never come here. You've pulled my old Dad down, and look what you’ve done to me—look!—I’m glad you’re going away! I don’t want ever to see your face again!</q></p>
   <p>Even as she said the words, Hilda longed to recall them. Cheerio’s hurt look was more than she could bear, and she fled up the stairs like one pursued. He heard the bang of her door, and a strangely softened look stole into his face as he turned into the living-room.</p>
   <p>The chess board was still set up, the men standing on the positions of the previous night, when the game had remained unfinished at the ending hour of ten o’clock. Cheerio cast a swift glance about him, studied the board a moment, and then with another furtive glance, quickly changed the position of a Black Queen<pb n="295"/> and a White Pawn. His hand was scarcely off the board when Hilda McPherson slipped from between the portieres.</p>
   <p>As swiftly and passionately as she had fled up the stairs, so she had run down again, com-</p>
   <p>punction overwhelming her, torn and troubled by that look on the man’s face. But her reaction turned to amazement and indignant scorn as she watched him at the chess board. If she had repented her harsh treatment of him before, now, more than ever, she ascended in judgment upon him. His glance fell guiltily before her accusing one. Hilda seized upon the first word that came to her tongue, regardless of its odiousness.</p>
   <p><q>Cheat! Cheat! Now I understnd how you’ve been beating my Dad! You’ve been changing the positions. You can’t deny itl I’ve caught you red-handed. Oh, oh! I might have guessed it. To think that for a single moment I believed in you, and now to discover you’re not only a——</q></p>
   <p>He flinched, almost as if physically struck, and turned white. Then his face stiffened.</p>
   <pb n="296"/>
   <p>His heels came together with that peculiarly little military click that was characteristic of him when moved. His face was masklike as he stared straight at Hilda. Something in his silence, some element of loneliness and helplessness about this man clutched at the stormy heart of the girl, and stopped the words upon her lips, as her father came into the room. Hilda had the strange feeling of a wild mother at bay. Angry with her child, she yet was ready to fight for and defend it. All unconsciously, she had covered her lips with her hands to crush back the hot words that were surging up to expose him to her father.</p>
   <p><q>What’s this? Why so much excitement? Why all this hysterical waste of force? It carried even to my office—electrical waves of angry sound. No doubt could be heard across at the bunkhouse or the barns. I'll make a test some day. Sit down, sit down. If you wish to witness our game, oblige us with silence, if you please</q>.</p>
   <p>To Cheerio he said:</p>
   <p><q>Be seated, sir. You will pardon the ex-</q><pb n="297"/> citement of my daughter. Youth is life’s tempestuous period—hard to govern—hard to restrain, a pathological, problematical time of life. Be seated, sir. My move, I believe, sir.</p>
   <p>Hilda felt weak and curiously broken. She sat forward in her chair, her eyes so dark and large that her face, no longer rosy, seemed now peculiarly small and young.</p>
   <p>Old P. D. scratched his chin and pinched his lower lip as he examined the board through his glasses. Cheerio was not looking at the board, his sad, somewhat stern glance was pinned upon Hilda.</p>
   <p>There was a pause, and suddenly P. D.’s face jerked forward. A crafty twitch of the left eyebrow. He glanced up at Cheerio, moved a Bishop three paces to the right. Cheerio withdrew his eyes reluctantly from the drooping Hilda, looked absently at the board and made the obvious move. Instantly P. D.’s hand shot toward his Queen. A pause, and then suddenly through the room, like the pop of a gun, P. D.’s shout resounded :</p>
   <p><q>Check!</q></p>
   <pb n="298"/>
   <p>Pause.</p>
   <p><q>Check!</q></p>
   <p>This time louder.</p>
   <p><q>Check to your King, sir! Game! Game!</q> Up leaped P. D. McPherson, sprang toward his opponent, smashed him upon the shoulder, gripped him by both hands, and shouted:</p>
   <p><q>Beat youl! By Gad! Id rather beat you than go to Chicago. Damn your hands and feet, you’re a dashed damned fine player, and it’s an honour to beat you, sir! Come along with me, sir!</q></p>
   <p>He dragged his opponent out, and arm and arm they hurried across to the bunkhouse to proclaim the <q>damnfine news</q> and to order all hands of the O Bar O to set out on the following morning upon that annual Fall round-up which had been put off for so long. But before Cheerio had left the room, and even while her father was all but embracing him, his glance had gone straight into the eyes of Hilda, pale as death and slowly arising.</p>
   <p>Like one moving in sleep, feeling her way as she passed, Hilda McPherson followed her<pb n="299"/> father and Cheerio. But she could go no farther than the verandah. There she sat crouched down on the steps, her face in her hands, overwhelmed by the unbearable pain that seemed to clutch at her heart. The truth had shocked Hilda into a realization of the inexcusable wrong and insult that she had dealt to this man. No words were needed. She comprehended exactly what had happened</p>
   <p>in that room. Cheerio, she now knew, had changed the men on the board for her father’s advantage. And she had called him a cheat!</p>
   <p>She took her hands down from her face, and spoke the words aloud:</p>
   <p><q>I called him a cheat! I called him a— coward! Oh, what am I to dor</q></p>
   <p>The man who had been sitting in the swinging couch, and whom she had not seen, strolled across the verandah and came directly down the steps to where the unhappy Hilda was crouched.</p>
   <p><q>Miss McPherson! Can I do anything for your</q></p>
   <p>Hilda was in too much pain to feel either<pb n="300"/> surprise or resentment for the intrusion. She said piteously:</p>
   <p><q>I called him a cheat! a coward!</q></p>
   <p><q>A coward—him/</q></p>
   <p>Duncan Mallison’s face darkened with an almost angry red.</p>
   <p><q>You may as well know this much at least</q>, he said roughly. <q>The man you called a coward won the Victoria Cross for an act of sublime heroism during the war</q>.</p>
   <p>Hilda stood up. She looked beaten and small. She was wrenching her hands together as she backed toward the door. Her lips were quivering. She tried to speak, but the words could not come, and she shook her head dumbly.</p>
   <p>The reporter, who probably understood human nature far better than the average person, was touched by the girl’s evident misery. He put his hand under Hilda’s arm, and guided her to the door. There he said soothingly:</p>
   <p><q>Now, don’t worry. Everything’s all right, and you’re in luck. We’re going to take him</q><pb n="301"/> on the paper. Fine job. He’ll make out great. So, don’t worry. First thing in the morning we'll be off, and you can depend upon me to do the best I can for him. He’s a darned good pal.</p>
   <pb n="302"/>
</div>
