<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="chapter" n="10">
            <head>Chapter X</head>
            <p>HOo.Ly SMOKE was strong as an ox and had			
<lb/>the reputation of phenomenal deeds done			
<lb/><q>across the line,’ where to use his own boasts			
<lb/></q><q>they did things brown</q>. It is true, he had			
<lb/>come hastily out of that particular part of the			
<lb/>American union, with a posse at his heels. He			
<lb/>had secured a berth at O Bar O in a busy sea<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>son, when help was scarce and work heavy.			
<lb/>His big physique stood him in good stead			
<lb/>when it came to a matter of endurance, though			
<lb/>he was too heavy for swift riding, needed for			
<lb/>breaking horses or cutting out cattle. How<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ever, there was no man in the country could			
<lb/>beat him at lariat throwing and he was gen<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>erally esteemed a first-rate hand. His last			
<lb/>name was actually <q>Smoke</q>, and his first ini<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tial <q>H</q> it did not take the men long to dub			
<lb/>him <q>Holy Smoke</q> though he was more			
<lb/>shortly called <q>Ho</q>.</p>
            <p>Other nicknames were secretly applied to</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 116]</fw>
            <pb n="117"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>him. Secretly because Ho had achieved such			
<lb/>a reputation as a fighter that few of the men			
<lb/>cared to risk his displeasure by calling him to			
<lb/>his face <q>Windy Ho</q> or <q>Blab</q>. His was the			
<lb/>aggressive, loud-voiced overbearing type of</p>
            <p>personality that by sheer noise often will win			
<lb/>out in an argument and makes an impression			
<lb/>on those who are not expert students of char<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>acter. Few at O Bar O questioned the prow<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ess of which Ho everlastingly boasted, for he			
<lb/>looked the part he played. His favourite			
<lb/>boast was that he <q>could lick any son-of-a-gun			
<lb/>in Alberta, just as I licked every son-of-a-gun			
<lb/>in Montana</q> with one hand tied behind. No			
<lb/>one accepted his challenge, pugnaciously			
<lb/>tossed forth, and little Buddy Wallace, one of			
<lb/>P. D.’s diminutive jockies, hurriedly retreated			
<lb/>when the big fellow merely stretched out a			
<lb/>clinched fist toward him.</p>
            <p>Even Bully Bill, himself somewhat of a			
<lb/>blusterer, discovered in Ho a personality more			
<lb/>domineering than his own. It was uncomfort<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>able to have the big bully around, but the fore<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>man had never quite screwed up the courage to</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[117]</fw>
            <pb n="118"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p><q>fire the man</q> as more than once P. D. had			
<lb/>suggested. Easy-going and good-natured			
<lb/>Bully Bill had suffered Ho to remain all of			
<lb/>that summer, enduring meanwhile the fellow’s			
<lb/>arrogance and boasts and even threats of vio<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>lence to each and every hand upon the place.			
<lb/>He had wormed his way to the position of tem<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>porary assistant foreman, as Bully Bill had dis<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>covered that the men took orders from him as			
<lb/>meekly as from P. D. himself. This was up			
<lb/>to the time that Cheerio drifted into O Bar O.			
<lb/>Soon after that memorable day, another even			
<lb/>more important in the annals of O Bar O			
<lb/>dawned that not only elevated the Englishman			
<lb/>permanently from the woodpile and chores to			
<lb/>the proud position of first rider. but lost Ho			
<lb/>his prestige in the cattle country.</p>
            <p>The row started in the cook-car. The first			
<lb/>prod in his side had been ignored by Cheerio,			
<lb/>who had continued to eat his meal in silence,			
<lb/>just as if a vicious punch from the thick elbow			
<lb/>of the man on his right had not touched him.			
<lb/>Holy Smoke winked broadly down the length			
<lb/>of the table. At the second prod, Cheerio</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[118]</fw>
            <pb n="119"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>looked the man squarely in the eye and said			
<lb/>politely:</p>
            <p><q>I wouldn’t keep that up if I were you</q>.</p>
            <p>This brought a roar of laughter followed by			
<lb/>the third prod. There was a pause. He had			
<lb/>raised in the interval his bowl of hot soup in			
<lb/>his hands and was greedily and noisily swal<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>lowing, when a surprising dig in his own left			
<lb/>rib not only produced a painful effect but sent			
<lb/>the hot soup spluttering all over him. Up rose			
<lb/>the huge cowhand, while in the tense silence			
<lb/>that ensued all hands held their breath in			
<lb/>thrilled suspense. As Ho cleared his vision—			
<lb/>temporarily dimmed by the hot soup, Cheerio,			
<lb/>who had also risen in his seat, said quietly:</p>
            <p><q>I d-don’t want to hurt you, you know,			
<lb/>b-but the fact is it’s got to be done. S-suppose			
<lb/>we go outside. T-too bad to m-make a m-m<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>mess of Chum Lee’s car</q>.</p>
            <p>Holy Smoke snorted, hitched his trousers			
<lb/>up by the belt, and then in ominous silence he			
<lb/>accompanied the Englishman, followed by</p>
            <p>every man in the cook-car, including Chum			
<lb/>Lee.</p>
            <p>s</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[119]</fw>
            <pb n="120"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>A ring was made in short order and into the			
<lb/>ring went the snorting, loudly-laughing Ho			
<lb/>and the lean, quiet young Englishman.</p>
            <p><q>I hate this sort of a thing</q>, said Cheerio,			
<lb/><q>and if you feel equal to an apology, old man,			
<lb/>we'll let it go at that</q>.</p>
            <p>Holy Smoke retorted with a low string of			
<lb/>oaths and a filthy name that brought Cheerio’s			
<lb/>fist squarely up to his jaw.</p>
            <p>To describe that fight would require more			
<lb/>craft and knowledge than the author possesses.			
<lb/>Suffice it to say that weight and size, the			
<lb/>strength of the powerful hands and limbs			
<lb/>availed the cowhand nothing when pitted			
<lb/>against the scientific skill of one of the cleanest			
<lb/>boxers in the British army, who, moreover,			
<lb/>had studied in the east that little-known but			
<lb/>remarkable art of wrestling known as jiujitsu.			
<lb/>The big man found himself whirling about in			
<lb/>a circle, dashing blindly this way and that,			
<lb/>and through the very force of his own weight			
<lb/>and strength overcoming himself, and in the			
<lb/>end to find himself literally going over the			
<lb/>head of the man who had ducked like light-</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 120 ]</fw>
            <pb n="121"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>ning under him, There on the ground			
<lb/>sprawled the huge, beaten bully, who had tyr<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>annized over the men of O Bar O. His the			
<lb/>fate to come to out of his daze only to hear the			
<lb/>frantic yells and cheers of the encircling men			
<lb/>and to see his antagonist borne back into the			
<lb/>cook-car upon the shoulders of the men.			
<lb/>Holy Smoke was a poor loser. His defeat,			
<lb/>while it quenched in a measure his outward			
<lb/>show of bluster, left him nursing a grudge			
<lb/>against Cheerio, which he promised himself			
<lb/>would some day be wiped out in a less con<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>spicuous manner and place. Not only had			
<lb/>his beating caused him to lose caste in the eyes			
<lb/>of the men of the ranching country, but the			
<lb/>story went the rounds of the ranches, and the			
<lb/>big cowhand suffered the snubs and heartless			
<lb/>taunts of several members of the other sex.			
<lb/>Now Ho was what is termed <q>‘a good looker</q>,			
<lb/>and his conquests over the fair sex generally			
<lb/>had long been the subject of gossip and joke			
<lb/>or serious condemnation. He was, however,			
<lb/>ambitious and aspired to make an impression			
<lb/>upon Hilda McPherson. For her this big</p>
            <p>[ rar ]</p>
            <pb n="122"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>handsome animal had no attraction, and his			
<lb/>killing glances, his oily compliments and			
<lb/>the flashy clothes that might have impressed			
<lb/>a simpler-minded maid than she, aroused			
<lb/>only her amused scorn. Herself strong and			
<lb/>independent by nature, beneath her thorny ex<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>terior Hilda McPherson had the tender heart			
<lb/>of the mother-thing, and the brute type of man			
<lb/>appealed less to her than one of a slighter and			
<lb/>more esthetic type.</p>
            <p>Furthermore, Hilda loved little Jessie			
<lb/>Three-Young-Mans, a squaw of fifteen sad			
<lb/>years, whose white-faced blue-veined papoose			
<lb/>was kept alive only by the heroic efforts of			
<lb/>Hilda and the Agency doctor. The Morley			
<lb/>Indian Reserve adjoined the O Bar O ranch,			
<lb/>and P. D. employed a great many of the tribe			
<lb/>for brush-cutting, fencing and riding at round<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ups. No matter how unimportant a job given			
<lb/>to a <q>brave</q>, he moved upon the place the fol<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>lowing day with all of his relatives far and			
<lb/>near, and until the job was done, O Bar O			
<lb/>would take on the aspect of an Indian en<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>campment. At such times Hilda, who knew</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 122]</fw>
            <pb n="123"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>personally most of the Indians of the Stoney			
<lb/>tribe, would ride over to the camp daily to call			
<lb/>upon the squaws, her saddle bags full of the			
<lb/>sweet food the Indians so loved. She was			
<lb/>idolized by the Indian women. When riding			
<lb/>gauntlets and breeks were to be made for the			
<lb/>daughter of P. D. only the softest of hides			
<lb/>were used and upon them the squaws lavished			
<lb/>their choicest of bead work. They were for			
<lb/><q>Miss Hildy, the Indian’s friend</q>. Of all the			
<lb/>squaws, Hilda loved best Jessie Three-Young<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>Mans; but Jessie had recently fallen into deep			
<lb/>trouble. Like her tiny papoose, the Indian			
<lb/>girl’s face had that faraway longing look of			
<lb/>one destined to leave this life ere long. She			
<lb/>who had strayed from her own people clung			
<lb/>the closer to them now when she was so soon to			
<lb/>leave them forever. Hilda alone of the white			
<lb/>people, the Indian girl crept forth from her			
<lb/>tent to greet. What she refused to tell even			
<lb/>her parents, Jessie revealed to Hilda McPher<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>son and accordingly Hilda loathed Holy			
<lb/>Smoke.</p>
            <p>However, Ho was assistant foreman at O</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 123 ]</fw>
            <pb n="124"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>Bar O and very often in full charge of the			
<lb/>ranch, for there were times when Bully Bill			
<lb/>went to the camps to oversee certain opera<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tions and in his absence Ho had charge of the			
<lb/>ranch and its stock. Also in P. D.’s absence,			
<lb/>Hilda was accustomed to take her father’s			
<lb/>place so far as the men were concerned, and			
<lb/>if there were any questions that needed re<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ferring to the house they were brought to her.			
<lb/>Thus she was forced to come into contact with			
<lb/>the foreman as well as his assistant.</p>
            <p>Ho had what Hilda considered a <q>disgust<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing habit</q> of injecting personal remarks into			
<lb/>his conversation when he came to the house			
<lb/>on matters connected with the cattle, and no			
<lb/>amount of snubbing or even sharp reproof or			
<lb/>insult feazed him. He was impervious to hurt			
<lb/>and continued his smirking efforts to ingrati<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ate himself with P. D.’s daughter. He always			
<lb/>spruced himself up for those calls at the ranch<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>house, slicked his hair smooth with oil and			
<lb/>axle grease, put on his white fur chaps, car<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ried his huge Mexican sombrero with its In<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>dian head band, and with gay handkerchief</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 124 ]</fw>
            <pb n="125"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>at his neck, Ho set out to make a <q>hit</q> with his			
<lb/>employer’s daughter.</p>
            <p>At the time when Cheerio was reading from			
<lb/>Dumas, P. D. was away in Edmonton, and for			
<lb/>a few days Bully Bill had gone down to Cal<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>gary, accompanying his men with a load of			
<lb/>steers for the local market. Ho, therefore, in			
<lb/>the absence of both of the bosses, was in charge</p>
            <p>of the ranch, and one evening he presented			
<lb/>himself at the house, ostensibly to inquire re<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>garding the disposition of certain yearlings			
<lb/>that had been shipped by Bully Bill from the			
<lb/>Calgary stockyards. Were they to be turned			
<lb/>on the range with the other stuff? Should he			
<lb/>keep them in separate fields? How about re<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>branding the new stuff? Should he go ahead			
<lb/>or wait till the round-up of the O Bar O year<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>lings and brand all at one time?</p>
            <p><q>Dad’s in Edmonton</q>, replied Hilda. <q>You			
<lb/>had better wait till he gets back, though I don’t			
<lb/>know just when that will be. He’s playing			
<lb/>chess</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Couldn’t you get him by phone or wire,			
<lb/>Miss Hilda? Rather important to know what</q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[125 ]</fw>
            <pb n="126"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>to do with this new stuff, seein’ as how they’re			
<lb/>pure-bred. Maybe the boss’!l want them spe<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>cially cared for.</p>
            <p><q>I could phone, of course, for I know where			
<lb/>to get him, but it makes him mad as a hornet			
<lb/>to talk on the telephone, especially long dis<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tance, and as for a wire, like as not, if Dad’s			
<lb/>playing chess, he’d just chuck it into his pocket			
<lb/>and never bother to read it</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Wa-al, I just thought I’d come along over			
<lb/>and talk it out with you, Miss Hilda. Your			
<lb/>orders goes, you know, every time</q>.</p>
            <p>He helped himself to a seat, which the girl			
<lb/>had not proffered him, and stretched out his			
<lb/>long legs as if for a prolonged visit. Hilda			
<lb/>remained standing, looking down at him			
<lb/>coolly, then she quietly moved toward the			
<lb/>door, and opened it.</p>
            <p><q>That'll be all, then</q>, she said, and held			
<lb/>the screen door open.</p>
            <p>The cowhand, with a black look at the back			
<lb/>of the small, proud head, arose and taking the			
<lb/>hint he passed out. Hilda snapped the screen</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 126 ]</fw>
            <pb n="127"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>door and hooked it. From outside, in a last			
<lb/>effort to detain her, Ho said:</p>
            <p><q>One minute, Miss Hilda. Did you say			
<lb/>them doegies were to go into the south pasture			
<lb/>with our own stuff, then?</q></p>
            <p>Hilda had not mentioned the south pasture.			
<lb/>However she said now:</p>
            <p><q>I suppose that will be all right, won’t it?</q></p>
            <p><q>Well, if they was mine I’d keep ’em in the			
<lb/>corrals for a bit, and give ’em the once-over in			
<lb/>case they’s any blackleg among ’em. They’s			
<lb/>one or two looks kind o’ suspicious</q>.</p>
            <p><q>All right, then. Keep them in the cor<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>rals</q>,</p>
            <p>After all, the man knew his business, and			
<lb/>she looked at him curiously through the screen			
<lb/>door.</p>
            <p><q>Everything else on the place all right?			
<lb/>Nothing loose? I thought I saw some stuff			
<lb/>in the bull pasture when I rode up from the			
<lb/>Minnehaha ranch to-day</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Them doegies is all right, Miss Hilda.			
<lb/>There ain’t nothin’ out ’cept what’s meant to			
<lb/>be out. You leave it to me. Nothin’s goin</q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 127 ]</fw>
            <pb n="128"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>to git out of hick with the boss away, you can			
<lb/>take it from me.</p>
            <p><q>I didn’t mean to question that</q>, she said			
<lb/>quickly.</p>
            <p>Her father’s sense of squareness in treat<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ment of his men was shared by her, and she			
<lb/>added with a slightly more friendly tone:</p>
            <p><q>You know an awful lot about cattle, don’t			
<lb/>you, Hoe</q></p>
            <p>To give Ho <q>an inch</q> was to yield the			
<lb/>proverbial mile. Instantly he was grinning			
<lb/>back at her, his chest swelling with conceit			
<lb/>and self-esteem, as he pressed against the			
<lb/>screen door, his bold eyes seeking hers.</p>
            <p><q>I know "bout everything they is to know			
<lb/>bout cattle—the two-legged as well as the			
<lb/>four</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Ts that sor</q></p>
            <p><q>You see, Miss Hilda, they ain’t much dif<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ference between ’em, whichever way you look			
<lb/>at’em. Some folks are scrub stock and go up			
<lb/>blind before the branding iron; others is like			
<lb/>yourself, Miss Hilda, with high spirits and			
<lb/>you got to get ’em broke in the Squeezegate</q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 128 ]</fw>
            <pb n="129"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>before you can use ’em. Pretty hard to slip			
<lb/>a lariat over that kind, but they’s a saying			
<lb/>among cowhands that ‘every outlaw has his			
<lb/>day,’ and I’m thinking—his bold eyes leered			
<lb/>into her own with significance, <q>the rope’ll git			
<lb/>you too</q>.</p>
            <p><q>You think so, do you? Well, who do you			
<lb/>think is smart enough to get the rope over my			
<lb/>head, I’d like to knowP</q></p>
            <p>He leered and chuckled. The conversation			
<lb/>was to his liking.</p>
            <p><q>Can’t say, but the woods is full of them			
<lb/>as is achin’ for the chance. Some day when			
<lb/>you’re loose on the range maybe you'll slip			
<lb/>under</q>.</p>
            <p>Hilda’s scorn had turned to anger. Holy			
<lb/>Smoke’s body was against the screen door,			
<lb/>bulging the wirework in. His cunning gaze			
<lb/>never left her face. He had lowered his voice			
<lb/>meaningly.</p>
            <p><q>How about that English fly, Miss? He’s			
<lb/>getting fair handy with the lariat, they do			
<lb/>say</q>.</p>
            <p>Hilda had flushed scarlet and drawn back</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 129 ]</fw>
            <pb n="130"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>with blazing eyes, but the words of the cow<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>hand on the outer side of the door stopped			
<lb/>her in her premeditated flight and sent a cold			
<lb/>shiver all over her.</p>
            <p><q>Ye needn’t to worry "bout him, Miss Hilda.			
<lb/>He ain’t likely to swing his lariat in your			
<lb/>direction. It’s hooked already over another			
<lb/>one</q>.</p>
            <p>Hilda’s dry lips, against her will, moved in			
<lb/>burning query:</p>
            <p><q>Who do you mean?</q></p>
            <p>She scarcely knew her own voice. Some<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>thing wild and primitive was surging through			
<lb/>her being: She wanted to cry out, to hurl			
<lb/>something into the face of the grinning man			
<lb/>at the door, yet fascinated, tormented, she			
<lb/>stayed for an answer:</p>
            <p><q>Her that’s under his pillow. Her that he			
<lb/>takes along of him wherever he goes and has			
<lb/>locked up in one of them gold gimcracks as if			
<lb/>her face was radio. It’d make you laugh to			
<lb/>see him take it to bed with him, and tuck it			
<lb/>just as if it was heaven under his pillow			
<lb/>and——</q>’</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 130]</fw>
            <pb n="131"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>Hilda stared blankly at the man on the			
<lb/>other side of the door. She uttered not a word.			
<lb/>Her hand shot out, as if she were dealing a			
<lb/>blow to him, and the inside door banged hard.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[131]</fw>
            <pb n="132"/>
         </div>