<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="chapter" n="12">
            <head>Chapter XII</head>
            <p>Hoy SMOKE rode in ahead with orders			
<lb/>from Bully Bill for all hands finished riding			
<lb/>to fall to and help at the branding and the de<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>horning. To each man was assigned some			
<lb/>especial post or task, and Ho was in his ele<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ment as he shouted his orders to the men,			
<lb/><q>showing off</q> in great form. His left eye had			
<lb/>flattened in a broad wink to the veterinary			
<lb/>surgeon, as he paused by Cheerio, turned now			
<lb/>from the Squeezegate and trying to recapture			
<lb/>the enthusiasm that had animated him before			
<lb/>he had noted that platform.</p>
            <p>‘Hey you there! Bull ses yer to give a hand			
<lb/>to the Doc, and there ain’t no time neither for			
<lb/>mannicarring your nails before fallin’ to. This			
<lb/>ain’t no weddin’ march, take it from me. We			
<lb/>ain’t had no round-up for fun. We’re here to			
<lb/>brand and dehorn, d’ you get me?</p>
            <p><q>Righto!</q></p>
            <p>Cheerio drew up sprightly before Dr. Mur-</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 143 ]</fw>
            <pb n="144"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>ray and saluted that grimy, nicotine-stained			
<lb/><q>vet</q>. The latter glimpsed him over in one			
<lb/>unflattering and comprehensive sweep of a			
<lb/>pair of keen black eyes. Then, through the			
<lb/>corner of his mouth, he hailed young Sandy,			
<lb/>right on the job at the fire.</p>
            <p><q>Hey, kid, give a poke, will yer? Keep that			
<lb/>fire agoing</q>.</p>
            <p>This was a job upon which Sandy doted.			
<lb/>From his baby years, fire had been both his			
<lb/>joy and his bane, for despite many threats and			
<lb/>whippings, the burning down of a costly barn			
<lb/>brought a drastic punishment that was to stick			
<lb/>hotly in the memory of even a boy who loved			
<lb/>fire as dearly as did Sandy. It caused him			
<lb/>forevermore to regard matches with respect			
<lb/>and an element of fear. P. D. had deliberately			
<lb/>burned the tips of his son’s fingers. Though			
<lb/>Sandy feared the fire, he still loved it. With			
<lb/>both care and craft, therefore, he poked the			
<lb/>fire, and pounded the huge pieces of coal till			
<lb/>they spluttered and burst into flames. The			
<lb/>heat grew intense.</p>
            <p>The cattle were now pouring into the cor-</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 144 ]</fw>
            <pb n="145"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>rals and the riders by the gates were cutting			
<lb/>out such of the mothers as had gotten through,			
<lb/>besides certain weaklings of the herd that were			
<lb/>to be spared the branding. These, temporarily			
<lb/>driven to adjoining corrals, set up the most			
<lb/>deafening outcries and calls for their young,			
<lb/>while in the calf corrals these sturdy young			
<lb/>creatures voiced their indignant and anguished			
<lb/>protests.</p>
            <p>Darting in and out of the clamouring herd,			
<lb/>the experienced <q>hands</q> bunched and sepa<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>rated them according to the bellowing orders			
<lb/>of Holy Smoke.</p>
            <p>The scorching crunch of the closing</p>
            <p>Squeezegate and the first long bawl of agony			
<lb/>swept the pink from the cheeks of the Eng<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>lishman. He was seized with a sudden, over<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>whelming impulse to flee from this Place of			
<lb/>Horrors, but as he turned instinctively toward			
<lb/>the gate, he saw Hilda standing upon it. She			
<lb/>had climbed to the third rung and, hands hold<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing lightly to the top rail, she watched the			
<lb/>operations with professional curiosity. For a			
<lb/>moment, Cheerio suffered a pang of revolting</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[145 ]</fw>
            <pb n="146"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>repugnance. That one so young and so lovely			
<lb/>should be thus callous to suffering seemed to			
<lb/>him an inexcusable blemish.</p>
            <p>It may be that Hilda sensed something of			
<lb/>his judgment of her, for there was a pro<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>nounced lifting of that dangerous young chin			
<lb/>and the free toss of the head so characteristic			
<lb/>of her wild nature, while her dark eyes shone			
<lb/>defiantly. Almost unconsciously, he found			
<lb/>himself excusing her. She had been born to			
<lb/>this life. Since her baby years she had been			
<lb/>freely among cattle and horses and men.			
<lb/>Daughter of a cattleman, Hilda knew that the			
<lb/>most painful of the operations, namely, the de<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>horning, was, in a measure, a merciful thing			
<lb/>for the cattle, who might otherwise gore each			
<lb/>other to death. The vaccination was but a pin			
<lb/>prick, an assurance against the deadly black<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>leg. As for the branding, it was not nearly as			
<lb/>painful as was generally supposed, and first			
<lb/>aid was immediately administered to relieve			
<lb/>the pang of the burning. It was the only			
<lb/>means the cattlemen had for the identification			
<lb/>of their property. She resented, therefore,</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 146 ]</fw>
            <pb n="147"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>the horror and reproach which she sensed in			
<lb/>the stern gaze of the Englishman. Her cool,			
<lb/>level glance swept his white, accusing face.			
<lb/><q>Pretty sight, isn’t it?</q> she taunted. <q>If			
<lb/>* she went on, defi<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>antly, </q><q>it is to see a brand slapped on true!</q>			
<lb/>With a nonchalant wisp of a smile, her toss-</p>
            <p>ing head indicated the stake, to which a three-</p>
            <p>there’s one thing I love,’</p>
            <p>month-old calf was bound, its head upturned			
<lb/>as the red-hot branding iron smote with a firm,			
<lb/>quick shot upon its left side.</p>
            <p>The odour of burnt hide nauseated Cheerio.			
<lb/>He felt the blood deserting his face and lips.			
<lb/>His knees and hands had a curiously numb			
<lb/>sensation. He was dizzy and almost blind.			
<lb/>He found himself holding to the gate rail,			
<lb/>the critical, judging glance of the girl fixed in			
<lb/>question upon his face.</p>
            <p>Like one hypnotized, he forced his gaze to<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ward the branded calf and he saw something			
<lb/>then that brought his trembling hand out in a			
<lb/>gesture of almost entreaty and pain. A long,			
<lb/>red spurt of blood was trickling down the ani<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>mal’sside. The old terror of blood swept over</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 147 ]</fw>
            <pb n="148"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>him in a surge—a terror that had bitten into</p>
            <p>‘his soul upon the field of battle. It was some<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>thing constitutional, pathological, utterly be<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>yond his control.</p>
            <p>Cheerio no longer saw the girl beside him,			
<lb/>nor felt the stab of her scornful smile. He had			
<lb/>the impulse to cry out to her, to explain that			
<lb/>which had been incomprehensible to his com<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>rades in France.</p>
            <p>Hilda’s voice seemed to come from very far			
<lb/>away and the tumult that made up the bawling			
<lb/>voices of Holy Smoke and the raging hands of			
<lb/>the O Bar O was utterly unintelligible to him;			
<lb/>nor could he comprehend that the shouts were			
<lb/>directed at him. In a way, the shouting			
<lb/>brought him stark back to another scene, when,			
<lb/>in wrath, men seemed to rush over him and			
<lb/>all in a black moment the world had spun			
<lb/>around him in a nightmare that was all made			
<lb/>up of blood—filthy, terrifying, human blood.</p>
            <p>Ho’s bawling message was transmitted from			
<lb/>bawling mouth to bawling mouth.</p>
            <p><q>Take the rope at the south stake, and take</q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 148 ]</fw>
            <pb n="149"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>it damn quick. Are yer goin’ to let the bloody			
<lb/>calf wait all the damn day for his brandin’e</p>
            <p>Above the tumult cut the girl’s quiet, in<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>cisive words:</p>
            <p><q>Get on your job! You’re wanted at the			
<lb/>south stake</q>.</p>
            <p><q>My job? Oh, by Jove, what was it I was			
<lb/>to dor</q></p>
            <p>His hand went vaguely across his eyes. He			
<lb/>staggered a few paces across the corral.</p>
            <p><q>Hold the rope!</q> squealed Sandy, jumping			
<lb/>up and down by the stake. <q>TI gotter keep the			
<lb/>fire goin’, and the other fellers has their hands			
<lb/>full at the Squeezegate</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Hold the bally rope! Oh, yes. Wh-wh<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>where is the bally thing?</q></p>
            <p><q>Here! Catch him! That’s Jake! There			
<lb/>you go, round and round. Keep agoin’.			
<lb/>Hold taut there! Don’t let go whatever you			
<lb/>do. That calf’s awful strong. If you don’t			
<lb/>look out she’ll get away!</q></p>
            <p>Sandy’s young wrists had been barely strong			
<lb/>enough to hold the rope that bound the			
<lb/>wretched calf to the stake. Pink Eye, wield-</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 149 ]</fw>
            <pb n="150"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>ing with skill a long lariat that never failed			
<lb/>to land upon the horns of the desired calf and			
<lb/>bring it to the stake, urged all hands along			
<lb/>with profane and impure language. Auto<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>matically and with perfect precision, Hoot<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>mon was clapping the brand upon one calf			
<lb/>after another and passing them along to the			
<lb/><q>Vet</q>, who in turn thrust the syringe into the			
<lb/>thigh, the prick of the vaccination being			
<lb/>dulled in comparison with the fiercer pang			
<lb/>of the branding iron. Now the rope had			
<lb/>passed from Sandy to Cheerio and there was a			
<lb/>pause.</p>
            <p><q>Get a wiggle on you! Hold tight! Round			
<lb/>this way! For the love of Saint Peter!</q></p>
            <p>At the other end of the rope that Sandy			
<lb/>had thrust into his hands, a three-month-old			
<lb/>calf pulled and fought for freedom. From its			
<lb/>head, where the dehorning shears had already			
<lb/>performed their work a dark sickening stream			
<lb/>dripped. Sandy had twisted the rope partly			
<lb/>around the post but it still remained un<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>knotted.</p>
            <p>Someone was calling something across the</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 150 ]</fw>
            <pb n="151"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>corral, Cheerio found himself going around			
<lb/>and around the post. Suddenly a wild baw] of			
<lb/>anguish from the tortured animal sent him			
<lb/>staggering back and at the same moment the			
<lb/>calf seemed to plunge against him and the hot			
<lb/>blood spurted against his face.</p>
            <p>At that moment he clearly heard again the			
<lb/>crisp whipping words of his captain, scorch<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing his soul with its bitter ring of hatred and			
<lb/>scorn. The rope slipped from his hand. He			
<lb/>threw up his arm blindly, shrinking back.			
<lb/>His breath caught in the old craven sob.			
<lb/>Down into deep depths of space he sank,			
<lb/>sickened.</p>
            <p>Hilda McPherson had leaped down from			
<lb/>the rail and with an inarticulate cry, she gath<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ered Cheerio’s head into her arms. It was the			
<lb/>coarse sneering voice of Holy Smoke that re<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>called her and forced her to see that shining			
<lb/>thing that was pinned to the breast of the un<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>conscious man.</p>
            <p><q>Wearin’ her over his heart, huh!</q> chuckled			
<lb/>Ho, one thick, dirty finger upon the locket,			
<lb/>while his knowing glance pinned the stricken</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[x51]</fw>
            <pb n="152"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>one of the girl. With a sob, Hilda drew back,			
<lb/>and came slowly to her feet, her eyes still look-</p>
            <p>ing down at the unconscious face with an ele<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ment of both terror and anguish.</p>
            <p>He returned with a cry—a startling cry of			
<lb/>blended agony and fear, for the odour of blood			
<lb/>was still in his nostrils and all about him was			
<lb/>the tumult of the battlefield; but all that Hilda			
<lb/>noted was that his first motion was that grasp			
<lb/>at his breast. His hand closed above the			
<lb/>locket. He sat up unsteadily, dazedly. He			
<lb/>even made an effort now to smile.</p>
            <p><q>That’s f-funny. Carn’t stand the blood.			
<lb/>M-makes me f-funky. C-c-constitutional—</q>			
<lb/>His words dribbled off.</p>
            <p>Hilda said nothing. She continued to stare			
<lb/>down at him, but her face had hardened.</p>
            <p><q>What t’ ’ell’s the matter?</q> snarled Ho.			
<lb/><q>Ain’t yer fit to stand the gaff of a bit of			
<lb/>brandin’ even?</q></p>
            <p>The girl’s averted face gave him no encour<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>agement, and Cheerio went on deliriously,			
<lb/>slipping deeper and deeper into the mire of			
<lb/>disgrace.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 152 ]</fw>
            <pb n="153"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p><q>C-carn’t stand the b-b-blood. M-makes me			
<lb/>sick. Constitutional. Affected me like that in			
<lb/>France. I w-w-went f-funky when they			
<lb/>needed me m-most—dr-opped out, you know</q></p>
            <p>—f-r-r-ran away and-——</p>
            <p>Ho, hand cupped at the back of his ear, was			
<lb/>drinking in every word of the broken confes<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>sion, while his delighted eyes exchanged			
<lb/>glances with the girl. Her chin had gone to			
<lb/>a high level. Without looking at Cheerio, she			
<lb/>said:</p>
            <p><q>Say no more. We have your number</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Better get to the bunkhouse</q>, said Ho.			
<lb/><q>This ain’t no place for a minister’s son</q>.</p>
            <p>Cheerio managed somehow to come to his			
<lb/>feet. He still felt fearfully weak and the per<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>sisting odour of blood and burnt hide made			
<lb/>him sick beyond endurance. Limping to the			
<lb/>gate, he paused a moment to say to the girl,			
<lb/>with a pathetic attempt at lightness of speech:</p>
            <p><q>Fraid I’m not cut out for cowboy life.			
<lb/>I'd j-jolly well like to learn the g-game. I			
<lb/>d-don’t seem exactly to fit</q>.</p>
            <p>She was leaning against the corral gate.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 153]</fw>
            <pb n="154"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>Her face was turned away, and the averted			
<lb/>cheek was scarlet. He felt the blaze of her			
<lb/>scornful eyes and suffered an exquisite pang of			
<lb/>longing to see them again as sometimes, after			
<lb/>the readings in the evening, humid and wide,			
<lb/>they had looked back at him in the twilight.			
<lb/><q>No, you don’t fit,’ she said slowly. </q><q>It			
<lb/>takes a man with guts to stand our life—a dead</q></p>
            <p>game sport, and not—not »</p>
            <p>She left the sentence unfinished, leaving the			
<lb/>epithet to his imagination. She turned her			
<lb/>back upon him. He limped tothe house. For			
<lb/>a long time he sat on the steps, his head in his			
<lb/>hands.</p>
            <p>Slowly there grew into his consciousness an<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>other scene. He had come to suddenly out of			
<lb/>just such a moment of unconsciousness as that			
<lb/>he had suffered at the corral. Then there had			
<lb/>flooded over him such an overpowering con<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>sciousness of what had befallen him that he			
<lb/>had staggered, with a shout, to his feet. At the			
<lb/>psychological moment, when his company had			
<lb/>started forward, he had welched, stumbled</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[154 ]</fw>
            <pb n="155"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>back, and, with the anguished oaths of the cap<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tain he loved ringing in his ears, Cheerio had			
<lb/>gone down into darkness. He had come to			
<lb/>as one in a resurrection, born anew, and in<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>vigorated with a passionate resolve to compen<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>sate with his life for that error, that moment			
<lb/>of weakness.</p>
            <p>There was an objective to be taken at any			
<lb/>cost. The men had gone on. He found him<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>self crawling across No Man’s Land. But a			
<lb/>hundred feet away he came to his company.			
<lb/>Upon the ground they lay, like a bunch of			
<lb/>sheep without a leader. There was not an			
<lb/>officer left, save that one who had been his			
<lb/>friend and who had cursed him for a renegade			
<lb/>when he turned back. Fearfully wounded, his			
<lb/>captain was slowly pulling his way along the			
<lb/>ground, painfully worming toward that clump			
<lb/>of wood from which the sporadic bursts of			
<lb/>gun fire were coming. Cheerio understood.			
<lb/>Someone had to put that machine-gun out of			
<lb/>commission or they would all be annihilated.			
<lb/>He was crawling side by side with his captain,			
<lb/>begging him to turn back and to trust him to</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[155]</fw>
            <pb n="156"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>take his place. He was pleading, arguing,			
<lb/>threatening and forcing the wounded man			
<lb/>down into a shell-hole where he could not			
<lb/>move. Now he was on his own job.</p>
            <p>Alone, within forty or fifty yards of the ma<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>chine-gun, he paused, to take stock of what he			
<lb/>had in the way of ammunition with him. He			
<lb/>found he had a single smoke bomb and re<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>solved to use it. Getting into a shell-hole, he			
<lb/>unslung his rifle and placed the bomb into it			
<lb/>and prepared it for firing. He waited for the			
<lb/>right wind to shift the smoke and then care<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>fully fired the gun.</p>
            <p>By some remarkable stroke of fortune, it			
<lb/>fell and exploded in such a position that the			
<lb/>wind carried the smoke in a heavy cloud im<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>mediately over the German machine-gun post,			
<lb/>rendering the operators of the machine abso<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>lutely powerless. At that moment Cheerio			
<lb/>leaped from the shell-hole, and rushing for<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ward, pulled a pin from a Mills bomb, as he			
<lb/>ran. When about twenty yards away, he threw			
<lb/>the bomb into the smoke and fell to the ground</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 156 ]</fw>
            <pb n="157"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>to await the explosion. It came with a terrific			
<lb/>crash, fragments of the bomb bursting over<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>head. ‘Jumping up and grasping his rifle			
<lb/>firmly, he plunged into the smoke which had			
<lb/>not yet cleared. Suddenly he fell into a			
<lb/>trench, and he could not restrain a cheer to			
<lb/>find that the machine-gun was lying on its side.			
<lb/>It was out of action.</p>
            <p>There was no time to survey the situation,			
<lb/>for two of the enemy had rushed toward him			
<lb/>swinging their <q>potato mashers</q> as the British			
<lb/>soldiers were wont to call this type of bomb.			
<lb/>Now that he realized that he had accom<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>plished his objective, his elation had turned			
<lb/>to the old sickening feeling of terror, as he			
<lb/>watched one of the Germans pull the little			
<lb/>white knob and throw the grenade. It missed			
<lb/>him and struck the parapet of the trench.			
<lb/>About to rush him, the Germans were re<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>strained by an officer who had come up un<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>observed until then. He would take the Eng<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>lishman prisoner. There were questions he			
<lb/>desired to put to him. Yelling: <q>Komm			
<lb/>mit!</q> they pushed him to his feet, and with</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 157]</fw>
            <pb n="158"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>prods of the bayonet, Cheerio went before the			
<lb/>Germans.</p>
            <p>His hands swept his face as if by their mo<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tion he put away that scene that had come back			
<lb/>so Clearly to memory. No! Not even the girl			
<lb/>he loved—for in his misery, Cheerio faced the			
<lb/>fact that he loved Hilda—not even she could			
<lb/>truthfully name him—coward!</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[158]</fw>
            <pb n="159"/>
         </div>