<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="chapter" n="6">
            <head>Chapter VI</head>
            <p><hi rendition="#smallcaps">PURELY</hi> by accident, the wall of reserve			
<lb/>that Hilda had reared between herself and			
<lb/>Cheerio was, for the nonce at least, removed.			
<lb/>Sandy had desired to go over a certain cliff,			
<lb/>incredibly steep and slippery and four hun<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>dred feet above the river. Now Sandy could			
<lb/>climb up and down places with the agility			
<lb/>and sureness of a mountain goat, but even a			
<lb/>mountain goat would have hesitated to go			
<lb/>over the side of that cliff.</p>
            <p>Hilda came out of her absent trance with			
<lb/>a start, as she realized the intention of the			
<lb/>daring and reckless youngster. Over an out<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>jutting rock Sandy was poised.</p>
            <p><q>Sandy McPherson! You cut out that			
<lb/>darned nonsense. You can’t go down there.			
<lb/>It’s too doggone steep</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Guess I can if I want to</q>, retorted the			
<lb/>boy, looking over the perilous edge and			
<lb/>scrutinizing the grade for any possible root</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 69 ]</fw>
            <pb n="70"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>or tree stump upon which he might grasp in			
<lb/>an emergency. <q>Say</q>, his head jerked side<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ways toward Cheerio, who had dismounted			
<lb/>himself to investigate the situation. <q>Will			
<lb/>you look after Silver Heels till I get back?			
<lb/>*Tain’t safe for Aim to go over, but I'll be			
<lb/>Jake</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Sandy! You come back! Dad said the			
<lb/>earth wasn’t safe under those rocks there, and			
<lb/>any minute one of ’em might roll over. That			
<lb/>rock’s moving now! Sandy! Oh, stop him!			
<lb/>D-d-don’t let-—him! Please!</q></p>
            <p>She had appealed to Cheerio. It was the			
<lb/>first request she had ever made of him. In<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>stantly he grasped the arm of her brother.</p>
            <p><q>Come on, old man. There’s a prospect			
<lb/>over yonder that looks a jolly sight better than			
<lb/>down there</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Aw, girls give me a pain</q>, declared the			
<lb/>disgusted Sandy. <q>What do they want to			
<lb/>come spyin’ along for anyway, and throwin’			
<lb/>fits about nothin’. What do they know about			
<lb/>dinosauruses or anything else, I’d like to			
<lb/>know?</q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[70]</fw>
            <pb n="71"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p><q>On you go, old man!</q></p>
            <p>He had hoisted the grumbling boy upon his			
<lb/>horse. Sandy raced angrily ahead. Cheerio			
<lb/>looked at Hilda with the expectant boyish			
<lb/>smile of one hoping for reward. He had			
<lb/><q>taken her part</q>. Thanks were his due,			
<lb/>Thanks indeed he did not get. Hilda’s glance			
<lb/>met his own only for a moment and then she			
<lb/>said, while the deep colour flooded all of her			
<lb/>face and neck:</p>
            <p><q/><q>Now you can see for yourself what your			
<lb/>fool expeditions might lead to. Sandy’s the			
<lb/>only brother I have in the world, and first			
<lb/>thing you know he’ll be going over one of			
<lb/>those cliffs and then—then—you'll be entirely			
<lb/>to blame</q>.</p>
            <p>Discomfited, Cheerio lost the use of his			
<lb/>tongue. After a moment he inquired, some<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>what dejectedly:</p>
            <p><q>Sh-shall we c-c-c-call them off then?</q></p>
            <p>Hilda was unprepared for this. Though			
<lb/>she would not have admitted it to herself for			
<lb/>anything in the world, those evening rides			
<lb/>were becoming the most important events in</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[71]</fw>
            <pb n="72"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>her life. Indeed, she found herself looking			
<lb/>forward to and thinking of them all day.			
<lb/>Faced now with the possibility of their being			
<lb/>ended, she said hurriedly and with a slight			
<lb/>catching of her breath that made Cheerio			
<lb/>look at her with an odd fixity of expression:</p>
            <p><q>No, no—of course not. I wouldn’t want			
<lb/>to disappoint my brother, b-but I can’t			
<lb/>trust that boy alone. I’ve always taken care			
<lb/>of Sandy. That’s why I come along. Sandy’s			
<lb/>just a little boy, you know</q>.</p>
            <p>How that <q>little boy</q> would have snarled			
<lb/>with wrath at his sister’s designation! Even			
<lb/>Cheerio’s eyes twinkled, and Hilda, to cover			
<lb/>up her own embarrassment, hastily pressed			
<lb/>her heel into her horse’s flank, and for the first			
<lb/>time she suffered him to ride along beside			
<lb/>her.</p>
            <p>It was intensely still and a dim golden haze			
<lb/>lay like a dream over all the sky and the land,			
<lb/>merging them into one. Into this glow rode			
<lb/>the girl of the ranching country and the man			
<lb/>from the old land across the sea. The air			
<lb/>was balmy and full of the essence of summer.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[72]</fw>
            <pb n="73"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>There was the sweet odour of recently-cut hay			
<lb/>and green feed and a suave wind whispered			
<lb/>and fragrantly fanned the perfumed air about			
<lb/>them. They came out of the woods directly			
<lb/>into the hay lands and passed through fields of			
<lb/>thick oats already turning golden. A strange			
<lb/>new emotion, a feeling that pained by its very			
<lb/>sweetness was slowly growing into being in			
<lb/>the untutored heart of the girl of the foot<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>hills. Glancing sideways at the man’s fine,			
<lb/>clean-cut profile, his gaze bent straight ahead,			
<lb/>Hilda caught her breath with a sudden fear			
<lb/>of she knew not what. Why was it, she asked			
<lb/>herself passionately, that she was unable to			
<lb/>speak to this man as to other mene Why			
<lb/>could she scarcely meet his clear, straight			
<lb/>glance, which seemed always to question her			
<lb/>own so wistfully? What was the matter with			
<lb/>her and with him that his mere presence near			
<lb/>her moved her so strangely? Why was she			
<lb/>riding alone with him now in this strange,			
<lb/>electrical silence? As the troubled questions			
<lb/>came tumbling over one another through the			
<lb/>girl’s mind, Cheerio suddenly turned in his</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">C73]</fw>
            <pb n="74"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>saddle and directly sought her gaze. A won<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>derful, a winning smile, which made Hilda			
<lb/>think of the sunshine about them, broke over			
<lb/>the man’s face. She was conscious of the			
<lb/>terrifying fact that that smile awoke in her			
<lb/>breast tumultuous alarms and clamours. She			
<lb/>feared it more than a hostile glance. Feared			
<lb/>the very friendly and winning quality of it.</p>
            <p>Impetuously the girl dug her little spurred			
<lb/>heels into her horse’s flanks and rode swiftly			
<lb/>ahead.</p>
            <p>It was nearly ten o’clock, yet the skies were			
<lb/>incredibly bright and in the west above the			
<lb/>wide range of mountains, shone the splendour			
<lb/>of a late sunset, red, gold, purple, magenta			
<lb/>and blue. All of the country seemed tinted			
<lb/>by the reflected glow of the night sun. Hilda,			
<lb/>riding breathlessly along, had the sense of one			
<lb/>in a race, running to escape that which was			
<lb/>pursuing her. On and on, neck and neck with			
<lb/>the galloping horse beside her, and feeling its			
<lb/>rider’s gaze still bent solely upon her.</p>
            <p>Presently there was a slackening of the run<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ning speed; gradually the galloping turned to</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 74]</fw>
            <pb n="75"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>the shorter trot. Daisy and Jim Crow, pant<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing from the long race, slowed down to a lope.			
<lb/>Some of the fever had run out of Hilda’s			
<lb/>blood and she had recovered her composure.			
<lb/>Silence for a long interval, while they rode			
<lb/>steadily on into the immense sun glow. Then:			
<lb/><q>R-ripping, isn’t it?</q> said the man, softly.			
<lb/><q>Meaning what?</q> demanded the girl,			
<lb/>angry with herself that her voice was tremu-</p>
            <p>lous.</p>
            <p>Almost they seemed to be riding into the			
<lb/>sky itself. Sky and earth had the curious phe<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>nomenon of being one.</p>
            <p><q>Everything</q>, he replied, with an eloquent			
<lb/>motion of his hand. <q>It’s a r-ripping—land!			
<lb/>I'm jolly glad I came</q>.</p>
            <p><q>T don’t suppose</q>, said Hilda, <q>that you			
<lb/>have skies like this in England</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Hardly</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Tt’s foggy and dark there, I’ve heard</q>,			
<lb/>said Hilda.</p>
            <p>He glanced at her, as if slightly surprised.</p>
            <p><q>Why no, that hardly describes it, you			
<lb/>know</q>.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">(75]</fw>
            <pb n="76"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>He was thoughtful a moment, and then			
<lb/>said, with a smile, as if glad to reassure her:</p>
            <p><q>Tt’s a dashed fine place, all the same.			
<lb/>C-carn’t beat it, you know</q>.</p>
            <p>That brought the girl’s chin up. For some			
<lb/>reason, she could not have analyzed, it hurt			
<lb/>and offended her to hear him praising the			
<lb/>land from which he had come.</p>
            <p><q>Hm! I wonder why Englishmen who			
<lb/>think so darned much of their own old land			
<lb/>bother to come to wild outlandish places like			
<lb/>Canada</q>.</p>
            <p>If she had expected him to deny that			
<lb/>Canada was wild and outlandish she was to			
<lb/>be disappointed, for he replied eagerly:</p>
            <p><q>Oh, by Jove! th-that’s wh-why we like it,			
<lb/>you know. It’s—it’s exhilarating—the differ<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ence—the change from things over there.			
<lb/>One gets in a rut in the old land and travel is			
<lb/>our only antidote</q>.</p>
            <p>Hilda had never travelled. She had never			
<lb/>been outside the Province of Alberta. Cal<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>gary and Banff were the only cities Hilda had			
<lb/>ever been in. She was conscious now of a</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 76 ]</fw>
            <pb n="77"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>sense of extreme bitterness and pain. Like			
<lb/>some young wounded creature who strikes			
<lb/>out blindly when hurt, Hilda said:</p>
            <p><q>Look here, Mr. Whatever your			
<lb/>name is, if you Englishmen just come out to			
<lb/>Canada out of curiosity and to——</q></p>
            <p><q>But, my dear child, Canada is part of us!			
<lb/>We’re all one family. I’m at home here</q>.</p>
            <p><q>No, you’re not. You're a fish out of			
<lb/>water</q>.</p>
            <p>er</p>
            <p/>
            <p><q>T s-say</q></p>
            <p><q>And look here, I don’t let anyone call me			
<lb/>‘dear child.’ I won’t be patronized by you			
<lb/>or anyone like you. I’m not a child anyway.			
<lb/>I’m eighteen and that’s being of age, if you			
<lb/>want to know</q>.</p>
            <p>He could not restrain the smile that came			
<lb/>despite himself at this childish statement.			
<lb/>Hilda’s face darkened, and her eyelids were			
<lb/>smarting with the angry tears that, much to			
<lb/>her indignation, seemed to be trying to force			
<lb/>their way through. She said roughly, in an			
<lb/>effort to hide the impending storm:</p>
            <p><q>Anyway you can’t tell me that there is any-</q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[77]</fw>
            <pb n="78"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>thing whatsoever in England to compare			
<lb/>with—that—for instance.</p>
            <p>Her quirt made an eloquent motion toward			
<lb/>the west, along the complete horizon of which			
<lb/>the long line of jagged peaks were silhouetted			
<lb/>against the gilded skies.</p>
            <p><q>Righto!</q> said the man, softly and then			
<lb/>after a pause he added almost gently, and as			
<lb/>if he were recalling something to memory:			
<lb/><q>But I doubt if there’s anything rarer than			
<lb/>our English country lanes—lawns—fine old			
<lb/>places—the streams—but you must see it all			
<lb/>some day</q>.</p>
            <p>When he spoke, when he looked like that,			
<lb/>with the faraway absent expression in his			
<lb/>eyes. Hilda had a passionate sense of rebel<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>lion and resentment. For some reason she			
<lb/>could not have explained she begrudged him			
<lb/>his thought of England. It tormented her to			
<lb/>think that the man beside her was homesick.			
<lb/>Her quirt flicked above Daisy’s neck. A			
<lb/>short swift gallop and back again to the lope			
<lb/>of the cow ponies. The ride had whipped			
<lb/>the colour into her cheeks and brought back</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 78 J</fw>
            <pb n="79"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>the fire to her eyes. She was ready now with			
<lb/>the burning questions that for days she had			
<lb/>ached to have answered.</p>
            <p><q>If England’s such a remarkable place,			
<lb/>why do you come to Canada to make a home			
<lb/>for this—what was her name, did you say?</q></p>
            <p><q>Her namer Oh, I see—you mean—			
<lb/>Nanna</q>.</p>
            <p>He said the name softly, almost tenderly,			
<lb/>and Hilda’s breath came and went with the			
<lb/>sudden surge of unreasonable fury that swept			
<lb/>over her. He answered her lightly, deliber<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ately begging the question.</p>
            <p><q>Why not? This is the p-p-promised			
<lb/>land!</q></p>
            <p><q>Are you making fun of Canada?</q> she de<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>manded imperiously.</p>
            <p><q>No—never. I s-said that quite seriously</q>.</p>
            <p>She shot her next question roughly. She			
<lb/>was determined to know the exact relation<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ship of this Nanna to the man beside her.			
<lb/>Undoubtedly she was the woman of the			
<lb/>locket, whose fair, lovely face Hilda was see-</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[79]</fw>
            <pb n="80"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>ing in imagination too often these days for			
<lb/>her peace of mind.</p>
            <p><q>Ts she your sister?</q></p>
            <p><q>Oh, no. No relation whatever. At least,			
<lb/>no blood relation</q>.</p>
            <p><q>T see. I sup-pose you think her very—			
<lb/>pretty?</q></p>
            <p><q>Lovely</q>, said Cheerio. Something had			
<lb/>leaped into his eyes—something bright and			
<lb/>eager. He leaned toward Hilda with the im<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>pulse to confide in her, but the look on the			
<lb/>girl’s face repelled him, so that he drew back			
<lb/>confounded and puzzled. Hilda set her			
<lb/>little white teeth tightly together, put up her			
<lb/>nose, and, with a toss of her head, said:</p>
            <p><q>For goodness sakes, let’s get home. Hi,			
<lb/>Daisy! get a wiggle on you, you old poke</q>.</p>
            <p>She was off on the last lap of the journey.</p>
            <p>In her room, she faced herself in the wide			
<lb/>mirror and revealed a remarkable circum<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>stance so far as she was concerned. Tears,			
<lb/>bitter and scorching, were running down her			
<lb/>face. Clinching her hands, she said to the			
<lb/>tear-stained vision in the mirror:</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 80]</fw>
            <pb n="81"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p><q>Tt’s just because I hate him so! Oh, how			
<lb/>I hate him. I never knew anyone in all the			
<lb/>days of my life that I hated so much before			
<lb/>and I’d give anything on earth if only I could			
<lb/>just hurt him!</q></p>
            <p>Hurt him she did, for the following even<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing when he brought her horse, saddled and			
<lb/>ready for her, to the front of the ranch house,			
<lb/>Hilda, in the swinging couch on the verandah			
<lb/>apparently deeply absorbed in a dictionary,			
<lb/>looked up coolly, and inquired what the hell			
<lb/>he was doing with her horse.</p>
            <p><q>Wh-why I th-th-thought you would be			
<lb/>coming with us as usual</q>, said the surprised			
<lb/>Cheerio.</p>
            <p><q>No thank you, and I’m quite able to			
<lb/>saddle my own horse when I want to go</q>, said			
<lb/>Hilda, and returned to a deep perusal of the			
<lb/>dictionary. But the crestfallen and puzzled			
<lb/>Cheerio did not see her, as on tiptoe, she stole			
<lb/>around the side of the house, to catch a last			
<lb/>glimpse of him as he rode out with Sandy be<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>side him. Her cheeks were hot and her eyes			
<lb/>humid with undropped tears as over the still</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[81]</fw>
            <pb n="82"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>evening air her brother’s shrill young voice			
<lb/>floated:</p>
            <p><q>Hilda not coming! Gee! we’re in luck/			
<lb/>Now we can go over the cliff!</q></p>
            <p>Hilda didn’t care just then whether that			
<lb/>brother of hers went over the cliff or not.			
<lb/>She felt forsaken, bitter, ill-used and ex<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tremely unhappy and forlorn. But she had			
<lb/>had her last ride in the magical evenings on a			
<lb/>dinosaur quest.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[82]</fw>
            <pb n="83"/>
         </div>