<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="chapter" n="3">
            <head>Chapter III</head>
            <p>P. D. MCPHERSON, or <q>P. D</q>. as he was			
<lb/>better known throughout the ranching country,			
<lb/>owner of the O Bar O, was noted for his ec<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>centricities, his scientific experiments with			
<lb/>stock and grain, and for the variety and quality			
<lb/>of his vocabulary of <q>cusses</q>.</p>
            <p>An ex-professor of an Agricultural College,			
<lb/>he had come to Alberta in the early days, be<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>fore the trails were blazed. While the rail<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>roads were beginning to survey the new coun<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>try, he had established himself in the foothills			
<lb/>of the Rocky Mountains.</p>
            <p>Beginning with a few head of cattle im<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ported from the East, P. D. had built up his			
<lb/>herd until it was famous throughout the cattle			
<lb/>world. His experiments in crossing pure-bred			
<lb/>grades of cattle in an attempt to produce an			
<lb/>animal that would give both the beef of the			
<lb/>Hereford and the butterfat and cream of the</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 29]</fw>
            <pb n="30"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>Holstein, had been followed with unabated			
<lb/>interest.</p>
            <p>He had been equally successful with his			
<lb/>horses and other stock. Turning from cattle			
<lb/>and stock, P. D. next expended his genius upon			
<lb/>the grain. It was a proud and triumphant day			
<lb/>for O Bar O when, at the annual Calgary Fair,			
<lb/>the old rancher showed a single stalk of wheat,			
<lb/>on which were one hundred and fifty kernels.</p>
            <p>His alfalfa and rye fields, in a normally dry			
<lb/>and hilly part of the country, were the wonder			
<lb/>and amazement of farmers and ranchers.</p>
            <p>The Government, the Railways, the Flour			
<lb/>mills and the Agricultural Colleges, sought			
<lb/>him out, and made tempting offers to induce			
<lb/>him to yield up to them his secrets.</p>
            <p>P. D. stroked his chin, pinched his lower			
<lb/>lip, drew his fuzzy eyebrows together, and			
<lb/>shook his fine, shaggy old head. He was not			
<lb/>yet satisfied that his experiments had reached			
<lb/>perfection.</p>
            <p>He'd <q>think it over</q>. He’d <q>see about it			
<lb/>some day, maybe</q>, and he <q>‘wasn’t so damned			
<lb/>cussed sure that it would benefit the world to</q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 30]</fw>
            <pb n="31"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>produce cheap wheat at the present time.			
<lb/>This way out, gentlemen! This way out!</p>
            <p>He was a rude old man, was P. D. McPher<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>son,</p>
            <p>In a way, he was obliged to be so, for other<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>wise he would have been enormously imposed			
<lb/>on. O Bar O was in the heart of the game and			
<lb/>fishing country, and was, therefore, the mecca			
<lb/>of all aspiring hunters and fishermen, to say			
<lb/>nothing of the numerous campers and motor			
<lb/>hoboes, who drove in every day upon the			
<lb/>land and left their trail of disorder and dirt			
<lb/>behind, and quite often small or large forest			
<lb/>fires, that were kept under control only by the			
<lb/>vigilance of O Bar O.</p>
            <p>The ranch was noted for its hospitality, and			
<lb/>no tramp or stranger or rider along the trail			
<lb/>had ever been turned from its door. The line,			
<lb/>however, had to be drawn somewhere, and it			
<lb/>was drawn in so far as the idle tourists, paus<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing en route to Banff or Lake Louise to <q>beat</q>			
<lb/>a meal or a pleasant day at the ranch, were			
<lb/>concerned, or the numerous motor hoboes,			
<lb/>who, denied at the ranch house their numerous</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[31]</fw>
            <pb n="32"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>requests for milk and eggs and gasolene and			
<lb/>the privilege of spending the night there,			
<lb/>slipped in under the bridge by the river, and			
<lb/>set up their camps on the banks of the Ghost			
<lb/>River,</p>
            <p>About the time when his wheat had brought			
<lb/>him considerable, but undesired, fame, P. D.,			
<lb/>holding his lower lip between thumb and fore<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>finger, was looking about for new experimen<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tal worlds to conquer. By chance, his mother<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>less son and daughter, then of the impression<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>able ages of four and ten respectively, shot			
<lb/>under his especial notice, through the medium			
<lb/>of a ride down the bannister and resultant			
<lb/>noise.</p>
            <p>P. D. studied his offspring appraisingly and			
<lb/>thoughtfully, and as he looked into the grimy,			
<lb/>glooming young faces, he conceived another			
<lb/>one of his remarkable <q>inspirations</q>.</p>
            <p>It was soon after this, that P. D. founded			
<lb/>that <q>School of Nature</q>, to which were bid<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>den all of the children of the neighbouring			
<lb/>ranch country, and into which his own			
<lb/>progeny were unceremoniously dumped.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 32]</fw>
            <pb n="33"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>However, when the curriculum of this Insti<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tution of Learning became more fully under<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>stood, despite the fame of its founder and			
<lb/>president, there were none among the parents			
<lb/>of the various children who felt justified in			
<lb/>sending them to the O Bar O School of Na<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ture.</p>
            <p>Even the most ignorant among them be<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>lieved that school existed only mainly for the			
<lb/>purpose of teaching the young minds how to			
<lb/>shoot with reading, writing, spelling and			
<lb/>arithmetic.</p>
            <p>P. D. proposed only the slightest excursion			
<lb/>into these elementary subjects. Nature, so he			
<lb/>declared, addressing the assembled farmers at			
<lb/>a special meeting, was the greatest of all			
<lb/>teachers, a book into which one might look,			
<lb/>without turning a single leaf, and learn all that			
<lb/>was necessary for the knowledge of mankind.</p>
            <p>He was convinced, so eloquently proclaimed			
<lb/>P. D., that school such as the world knew it,			
<lb/>was antiquated in its methods and wholly un<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>necessary and wrong. To teach the young the			
<lb/>secrets and mysteries of nature—that alone</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[33]</fw>
            <pb n="34"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>was needed to produce a race of supermen and			
<lb/>women,</p>
            <p>One timid little woman arose, and asked			
<lb/>what <q>supermen</q> meant, and the huge, rough			
<lb/>father of the family of ten replied’ that it			
<lb/>meant <q>men who liked their supper</q>.</p>
            <p>The meeting broke up in a riot—so far as			
<lb/>P. D. was concerned, and his neighbours de<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>parted with his wrathful imprecations ringing			
<lb/>in their ears.</p>
            <p>Not to be daunted by the lack of support af<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>forded him by his neighbours, P. D. set at			
<lb/>once to put his theories into practice upon his			
<lb/>helpless children.</p>
            <p>It came to pass that the children of P. D.			
<lb/>missed the advantages of the ordinary modern			
<lb/>schools. Had P. D., in fact, carried out his			
<lb/>original curriculum, which he prepared with			
<lb/>scientific detail, it is quite possible that the re<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>sults might have turned out as satisfactorily as			
<lb/>his experiments with cattle, pigs, sheep and			
<lb/>horses. P. D. reckoned not, however, with the			
<lb/>vagaries and impetuosities of youth and human			
<lb/>nature. Unlike dumb stock, he had fiery</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 34]</fw>
            <pb n="35"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>spirits, active imaginations, and saucy tongues			
<lb/>to deal with. He was not possessed with even			
<lb/>the normal amount of patience desirable in a			
<lb/>good teacher. His classes, therefore, were			
<lb/>more often than not punctuated by explosive			
<lb/>sounds, miraculous expletives, indignant out<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>cries, and the ejection or hurried exit from the			
<lb/>room of a smarting, angry-eyed youngster, suf<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>fering from the two-fold lash of parental			
<lb/>tongue and hand.</p>
            <p>Then when some of his original ideas were			
<lb/>just beginning to take substantial root in their			
<lb/>young minds and systems, P. D. fell a victim to			
<lb/>a new and devastating passion, which was			
<lb/>destined to hold him in thrall for the rest of			
<lb/>his days.</p>
            <p>Chess was his new mistress, alternately his			
<lb/>joy and his bane. Even his children were for<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>gotten in the shuffle of events, and, turned			
<lb/>upon their own resources, they grew up like			
<lb/>wild young things, loose on a great, free range.</p>
            <p>If, however, the young McPhersons had			
<lb/>missed school, they had learned much of which			
<lb/>the average child of to-day is more or less igno-</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">035]</fw>
            <pb n="36"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>rant. They knew all of the theories concerned			
<lb/>in the formation of this earth of ours, and the			
<lb/>living things upon it. They were intimately			
<lb/>acquainted with every visible and many in<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>visible stars and planets in the firmament.			
<lb/>They had a plausible and a comprehensible			
<lb/>explanation for such phenomena as the milky			
<lb/>way, the comets, the northern lights, the			
<lb/>asteroids and other denizens of the miraculous			
<lb/>Alberta sky above them. They knew what the			
<lb/>west, the east, the north and the south winds			
<lb/>portended. They could calculate to a nicety			
<lb/>the distance of a thunderstorm. No mean			
<lb/>weather prophets were the children of P. D.			
<lb/>McPherson; nor were their diagnosis depend<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ent upon guess-work, or an aching tooth, or			
<lb/>rheumatic knee, or even upon intuition or su<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>perstition, as in the case of the Indian.			
<lb/>Woodlore they knew, and the names and			
<lb/>habits of the wild things that abounded in the			
<lb/>woods of O Bar O. Insects, ants, butterflies,			
<lb/>bees, were known by their scientific names. A			
<lb/>rainbow, a sunrise, sunset, the morning mist,			
<lb/>fog, the night sun of Alberta, the Japanese cur-</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 36]</fw>
            <pb n="37"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>rent that brought the Chinook winds over the			
<lb/>Rocky Mountains, that changed the weather			
<lb/>from thirty below zero to a tropical warmth in			
<lb/>Alberta, the melting clouds in the skies, the			
<lb/>night rainbows—all these were not merely			
<lb/>beautiful phenomena, but the result of natural			
<lb/>causes, of which the McPherson children were			
<lb/>able to give an intelligent explanation,</p>
            <p>They could ride the range and wield the			
<lb/>lariat with the best of the cowpunchers.			
<lb/>Hilda could brand, vaccinate, dehorn, and			
<lb/>wean cattle. She was one of the best brand			
<lb/>readers in the country, and she rode a horse as			
<lb/>if she were part of the animal itself. She			
<lb/>could leap with the agility of a circus rider			
<lb/>upon the slippery back of a running outlaw,			
<lb/>and, without bridle or saddle, maintain her			
<lb/>place upon a jumping, bucking, kicking,			
<lb/>wildly rearing <q>bronc</q>.</p>
            <p>Untamed and wild as the mavericks that,			
<lb/>eluding the lariat of the cowpuncher, roamed			
<lb/>the range unbranded and unbroken, Hilda and			
<lb/>Sandy McPherson came up out of their child<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>hood years, and paused like timid, curious</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[37]</fw>
            <pb n="38"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>young creatures of the wild upon the perilous			
<lb/>edge of maturity.</p>
            <p>Hilda was not without a comprehension of			
<lb/>certain things in life that had been denied her.			
<lb/>If her heart was untamed, it was not the less			
<lb/>hungry and ardent. Though she realized that			
<lb/>she had missed something precious and desir<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>able in life, she was possessed with a spartan			
<lb/>and sensitive pride. About her ignorance, she			
<lb/>had erected a wall of it.</p>
            <p>It was all very well to ride thus freely over			
<lb/>the splendid open spaces and to wend her fear<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>less way through the beckoning woods of the			
<lb/>Rocky Mountain foothills. It was fine to be			
<lb/>part of a game which every day showed the			
<lb/>results of labour well done, and to know that			
<lb/>such labour was contributing to the upkeep			
<lb/>and value of the world. Yet there were times			
<lb/>when a very wistful expression of wonder and			
<lb/>longing would come into the girl’s dark eyes,			
<lb/>and the craving for something other than she			
<lb/>had known would make her heart burn within			
<lb/>her.</p>
            <p>To appease this heart hunger, Hilda sought</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[38]</fw>
            <pb n="39"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>a medium through the reading matter obtain<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>able at O Bar O; but the reading matter con<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>sisted of the Encyclopedia Brittanica, Dar<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>win’s <q>Origin of the Species</q>, several scientific			
<lb/>works, and two voluminous works on the sub<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ject of chess.</p>
            <p>For a time, the Encyclopedia afforded suffi<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>cient material to satisfy at least her curiosity;			
<lb/>but presently a new source was tapped. From			
<lb/>the bunkhouse came dime novels and the			
<lb/>banned newspapers, which P. D. had more			
<lb/>than once denounced as <q>filthy truck fit for the			
<lb/>intelligence of morons only</q>. Besides these			
<lb/>were the Poltce Gazette, two or three penny			
<lb/>dreadfuls, Hearsts’, and several lurid novels of			
<lb/>the blood-and-thunder type. This precious			
<lb/>reading matter, borrowed or <q>swiped</q> by			
<lb/>Sandy and Hilda, while the men were on the			
<lb/>range, was secretly devoured in hayloft and			
<lb/>other secure places of retreat, and made a pro<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>found impression upon their eager young			
<lb/>minds.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[39]</fw>
            <pb n="40"/>
         </div>