<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="chapter" n="24">
   <head>Chapter XXIV</head>
   <p><hi rendition="#smallcaps">OF</hi> all the emotions, whether sublime or ridiculous, that obsess the victim of that curious malady of the heart which we call Love, none is more torturing or devastating in its effect than that of jealousy with its train of violent reactions.</p>
   <p>Love affected and afflicted Hilda and Cheerio in different and yet in similar ways.</p>
   <p>Hilda, kneeling by her bed, her arms clasped about her pillow, into which she had buried her hot young face, gave herself up at first to the sheer ecstasy and glow of those first exalting, electrical thrills. All she comprehended was that she was in love.</p>
   <p>Love! It was the most beautiful, the most sacred, the most precious and the most terrible thing in all the universe. That was what Hilda thought. Gradually her thoughts began to assemble themselves coherently. Sitting upon the floor by her bed, Hilda brought back to mind every incident, every word and look<pb n="275"/> that had passed between her and Cheerio that she could recall since first he had come to O Bar O.</p>
   <p>Who was this man she loved? What was he doing at O Bar OP? Where had he come from? Who were his people? She did not even know his name. The very things that had aroused the derision of the men, his decently-kept hands, the daily shave and bath, his speech, his manner, his innate cleanliness of thought and person—these bespoke the gentleman, and Hilda McPherson had the ranch girl’s contempt for a mere gentleman. In the ranching country, a man was a man. That was the best that could be said of him.</p>
   <p>With the thought of his past, came irresistibly back to torment her the woman of the locket—‘‘Nanna, for whom he had come to Canada to make a home. She had never been wholly absent from Hilda’s thought and unconsciously now, as in the midst of her bliss she came back vividly to mind, a little sob escaped her. She tried to fight the encroaching thought of this woman’s claim.</p>
   <pb n="276"/>
   <p><q>Suppose he had been in love with her, I’ve cut her out! She is done for</q>.</p>
   <p>Thus Hilda, to the unresponsive wall facing her.</p>
   <p>Suppose, however, they were engaged. That was a word that was followed by martriage. This thought sent Hilda to her feet, stiff with a new alarm. The unquiet demon of Jealousy had struck its fangs deep into the girl’s innermost heart. She no sooner tried to recall his face as he had looked at her in the moonlight, the warm clasp of his hand, the term of endearment that had slipped from his lips, when the knife was twisted again within her, and she saw the lovely face of the other ‘woman smiling at her from the gold locket, with her fair hair enshrined on the opposite side.</p>
   <p>The recollection was intolerable—unendurable to one of Hilda’s tempestuous nature. Suppose she should come to Alberta! Perhaps she would not release him, even if he desired it! Suppose she should come even to O Bar O. How would she—Hilda—bear to<pb n="277"/> meet her? Her wild imagination pictured the arrival, and Hilda began to walk her floor. Love was now a purgatory. What was she to do? What was she to do? Hilda asked herself this question over and over again, and then when her pain became more than she could bear, she turned desperately to her door. At any cost, however humiliating to her pride, she would learn the truth. She would go directly to him. She would ask him point-blank whether from this time on it was to be her or —Nanna!</p>
   <p>She had done without her dinner. She could not have eaten had she been able to force herself to the table. Her father had called her, Sandy had pounded upon her door. It mattered not. Hilda was deaf to all summons, save those clamouring ones within her.</p>
   <p>As far as that goes, she was not the only one at O Bar O who had gone supperless.</p>
   <p>Cheerio, after she had left him, remained at the foot of the steps, just looking up at the door through which the world for him seemed to have vanished. How long he stood thus,<pb n="278"/> cannot be estimated by minutes or seconds. Presently he sat down upon the steps, and soon was lost in a blissful daze of abstraction.</p>
   <p>Above him spread the great map of the skies, at this time of year especially beautiful, star-spotted and slashed with the long rays of Northern lights and the night rainbows. Still and electric was the night. Keen and fresh the air. The ranch sounds were like mellow musical echoes. Even the clang of Chum Lee’s cow-bell, calling all hands to the evening meal, seemed part of the all-abiding charm of that perfect night.</p>
   <p>The voices of the men en route from bunkhouse to cook-car, the sharp bark of the dog Viper, and the answering growls of the cattle dogs, the coyote, still wailing wildly in the hills.</p>
   <p>Lights were low in the bunkhouse and on full in the cook-car. The absorbing job of <q>feeding</q> was now in process.</p>
   <p>All these things Cheerio noted vaguely, with a gentle sort of delight and approval. They were all part of the general beauty of<pb n="279"/> life on this remarkable ranch. He was conscious of a big, uplifting sense. He wanted to shout across the world praise of this new land that he had discovered; of the utter peace and joy of ranching in the foothills of the Rocky Mountains; of the girl of girls who was more to him now than anything else on earth.</p>
   <p>A wide moon was now overhead, and the country was bathed in a silvery light. The skies were star-spotted, and alive with mystery and beauty.</p>
   <p>Snatches of poetry sang in his head, and for the first time since the days when he had penned his boyish love lyrics to Sybil Chennoweth, Cheerio indited new ones to Hilda, the girl he now loved:</p>
   <p><q>Oh, Hilda, my darling, the sky is alive, And all of the stars are above; The moon in her gown of silvery sheen— She knows of my love—my love</q>.</p>
   <p>It mattered not to the lover whether his verses were of a high order from a critical<pb n="280"/> point of view. They were heartfelt—an expression of what seemed surging up within him. He needed a medium through which he might speak to Hilda. On the back of an envelope, he scratched:</p>
   <p><q>Hilda of the dark brown eyes And lips so ripe and red</q>.</p>
   <p>Hilda, of the wilful ways,</p>
   <p>And small, proud, tossing head.</p>
   <p>And so it went. But, like Hilda, the first incoherent rhapsody gave way presently to soberer thoughts. He was inspired by a desire to do something to prove himself worthy of the girl he loved. He was overtaken with an appalling realization of his shortcomings. What had he to offer Hilda? What had he done to deserve her? He was but one of twenty or more paid <q>hands</q> on her father’s ranch. He was penniless; nameless!</p>
   <p>She was no ordinary girl. That brown-eyed girl, with her independent toss of head and her free, frank nature, he knew had the ten-<pb n="281"/> der heart of a mother. Cheerio had watched many a time when she knew it not. He had seen her with the baby colts, the calves, the young live-stock of the ranch; the hidden litter of kittens in the barn, whose existence was so carefully hidden from her father. He had watched Hilda caring for the sick little Indian papoose, wrapping antiseptic salve bandages on a little boy’s sore arm, and stooping to kiss the brown face and pat the shoulder of the little Indian mother. No wonder she was adored by half the country-side. No wonder the Indians called her <q>little mother</q> and friend. She was as straightforward, honest, and clean as a whistle. She was fearless and fine as a soldier. There was about her slim, young grace a boyish air of courage. Hilda! There never was another girl like his in all the whole world.</p>
   <p>Now Cheerio felt humbled, unworthy. Followed a boyish desire to give Hilda things. He regretted his poverty, and suffered a sense of resentment and irritation for the first time at the thought of the power and pride of a<pb n="282"/> great family name that should by rights be his and Hilda’s. What had he to offer her? Nothing—but the trifling trinket, a family heirloom, in which long since he had replaced the picture of the English girl with the one Sandy had given him of Hilda. Automatically his hand closed about the locket. It was a fine old antique. Hilda would appreciate it. He would show her her own and Nanna’s face inside it. He pictured her shining eyes as she would take the trinket from his hand. Once she had told him she possessed not a single piece of jewellery. P. D. had denounced them as <q>baubles, suitable for savages only—relics of days of barbarism. The modern woman who pierced her ears</q>, said P. D. McPherson, <q>and hung silly stones from them was little better than the half-naked black women who hung jewels and rings from their noses</q>.</p>
   <p>But Hilda did not share her father’s opinion. She had spoken wistfully, longingly, enviously. This was after reading a chapter<pb n="283"/> concerning Anne of Austria’s diamonds and D’Artagnan’s famous recovery of the same.</p>
   <p>Well, Hilda should have her first piece of jewellery from his hands. The ancient Chelsmore locket. It would take the place of the ring between them. It would be the symbol of their love.</p>
   <pb n="284"/>
</div>
