<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="chapter" n="22">
            <head>Chapter XXII</head>
            <p>DuNCAN MaALLISON pushed the little			
<lb/>swinging gate open with his knee and saun<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tering across to the City desk, threw a bundle			
<lb/>down upon it.</p>
            <p><q>Why, hello, Dunc! Backe</q></p>
            <p><q>Hi, there, Dunc?’</q></p>
            <p>Several heads bent above typewriters raised			
<lb/>long enough to call across a word of greeting.			
<lb/>Charley Munns, City Editor of the Calgary			
<lb/>Blizzard, his desk heaped high with an amaz<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing mass of papers, glanced up with a detached			
<lb/>query in his harassed young blue eyes.</p>
            <p><q>Well?</q></p>
            <p>Mallison proceeded to untie the string about			
<lb/>his package. Munns glanced at the first of the			
<lb/>pictures, jerked his chin out and looked again.			
<lb/>Mallison showed the second and then, slowly,			
<lb/>the third. Munns had pushed back the heap			
<lb/>of papers. Pipe in hand, tired young blue			
<lb/>eyes suddenly bright and alert, he examined</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 253 ]</fw>
            <pb n="254"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>the remarkable sketches. An interested group			
<lb/>had gathered at the back of the city editor’s			
<lb/>chair, and the sketches passed from hand to			
<lb/>hand. Mallison who had, without words,			
<lb/>merely laid the package of sketches before his			
<lb/>city editor, continued reticent when questioned			
<lb/>by the staff.</p>
            <p><q>Whose work was it? Where had he got			
<lb/>them? Had they been exhibited? What were			
<lb/>they doing in Calgary?</q> and so forth.</p>
            <p>Oh, they were the work of a friend of his.			
<lb/>Didn’t matter who. None of them knew his			
<lb/>name. No, they hadn’t been exhibited.</p>
            <p>Then he sat him down by the ‘<q>Chief’s</q>			
<lb/>desk, hugged his chin, and stared gloomily be<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>fore him. The men were back at their desks,			
<lb/>and Munns signed some slips, and then turned			
<lb/>his attention back to his reporter.</p>
            <p><q>Good work. Typical Stoneys, eh? Don’t			
<lb/>know who your friend is, Dunc, but it is worth			
<lb/>two sticks—more if you’re personally inter<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ested. By the way, about P. D.2 How’d you			
<lb/>come out?</q></p>
            <p>The city editor had picked up again one of</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 254 ]</fw>
            <pb n="255"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>the sketches and was examining it interestedly.			
<lb/>It was of a young girl, standing on the top of			
<lb/>a hill, her horse, reins dropped, behind her,			
<lb/>its mane blowing in the wind. She was in			
<lb/>breeks, with a boy’s riding boots and her			
<lb/>sweater was a bright scarlet. On her head			
<lb/>was a black velvet tam. Something in the			
<lb/>wide-eyed dreaming look of the girl, as if she			
<lb/>were gazing across over an immense distance,			
<lb/>seeing probably hills yet higher than the one			
<lb/>on which she stood, with the clear blue skies			
<lb/>as her only background, held the attention of			
<lb/>the jaded city editor.</p>
            <p><q>That's really great. Fine! Who’s the			
<lb/>girl, by the way?</q></p>
            <p><q>Hilda McPherson</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Oh ho!</q></p>
            <p>Mallison pulled out the slat of the desk,			
<lb/>rested his elbows upon it, and began talking.			
<lb/>As he talked, his city editor’s eyes returned			
<lb/>time and again to the sketches, and suddenly			
<lb/>he ejaculated:</p>
            <p><q>Hello! What's this?</q></p>
            <p>Absently turning over the sketches, the pho-.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">F255]</fw>
            <pb n="256"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>tograph of Cheerio was suddenly revealed.			
<lb/>Charley Munns’ brows were puckering. One			
<lb/>other talent this man possessed. An almost			
<lb/>uncanny gift of memory. It was said of him			
<lb/>that he never forgot a face once seen.</p>
            <p><q>Half a mo’!l</q></p>
            <p>He had swung around a rackety file, that			
<lb/>revolved on low wheels. Digging into it, he			
<lb/>presently found the <q>obit</q> that he sought, and			
<lb/>slapped down upon the desk a pile of press			
<lb/>clippings, duplicate of the photograph which			
<lb/>the reporter had found at O Bar O, and a con<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>cise, itemised description of the man in</p>
            <p>question.</p>
            <p>Editor and reporter scanned the story			
<lb/>swiftly. There was no question now as to the			
<lb/>identity of the man at O Bar O. Cheerio’s			
<lb/>obit read like a romance. Son and heir of			
<lb/>Lord Chelsmore, he had left his art studios in			
<lb/>Italy to return to England, there to enlist as			
<lb/>a common soldier in the ranks. Among those			
<lb/>missing in France, posthumous honors had			
<lb/>been bestowed upon him. Soon after this, his			
<lb/>father had died, and his younger brother had</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 256 ]</fw>
            <pb n="257"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>succeeded to the title and estates and had mar<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ried his former fiancée.</p>
            <p>Charley Munns glanced through the vari<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ous clippings, nodded his head, and slapped			
<lb/>them back into the big manila envelope.</p>
            <p><q>T think you’ve stumbled across a big thing</q>,			
<lb/>he said. <q>This man is probably the real Lord			
<lb/>Chelsmore. Find out just what he’s doing up			
<lb/>here. Not only a good news story here, but			
<lb/>a fine feature story, if you want to do it</q>.</p>
            <p>But the reporter was staring out angrily be<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>fore him. Certain instincts were warring			
<lb/>within him. He wanted to shove his knees			
<lb/>under that typewriter desk and begin pound<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing out a story that would proclaim Cheerio’s			
<lb/>secret to the world. But a feeling of com<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>punction and shame held him back.</p>
            <p>After all, the fellow had a right to his own			
<lb/>secret. He had been darned nice to the re<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>porter. Was a darned good friend. Mal<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>lison’s mind went back to those long, pleasant			
<lb/>Sundays, when they had talked and smoked to<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>gether. He recalled a day, when with a			
<lb/>friendly smile, Cheerio had tossed from his</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 257 ]</fw>
            <pb n="258"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>horse into Mallison’s arms a fine haunch of			
<lb/>venison. A man couldn’t buy venison from			
<lb/>the Indians, nor, at that time, could he shoot			
<lb/>deer. The Indians alone had that right, and			
<lb/>while they were not permitted to sell venison			
<lb/>to the white men, there was no law to prevent			
<lb/>them from making gifts of the desired meat.			
<lb/>Nor was there any law that prevented the			
<lb/>white man returning the compliment with a			
<lb/>bag of sugar or a can of molasses or whatever			
<lb/>sweet stuff the red man might demand.			
<lb/>Cheerio remarked that he had no use for the			
<lb/>venison at the ranch house and the stuff was a			
<lb/>hanged sight better cooked over a camp fire,			
<lb/>so <q>There you are, old man. One minute, and			
<lb/>I'll give you a hand</q>.</p>
            <p>He had built the fire and he had cut up and			
<lb/>broiled the venison, and he had spread it			
<lb/>thickly with O Bar O butter, and with a			
<lb/>friendly grin, he had dished it out to the			
<lb/>camper.</p>
            <p>Mallison felt himself shrivelling under a			
<lb/>mean pang. It was a dirty trick to have taken			
<lb/>the sketches, though Mallison proposed to</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 258 ]</fw>
            <pb n="259"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>show them to certain prominent folk of Cal<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>gary who might help the fellow who was a			
<lb/>ranch hand. He had not intended to exploit			
<lb/>his friend. He had a good enough story about			
<lb/>P. D., and he had been sent to <q>cover</q> P. D.			
<lb/>and the chess game. So why:</p>
            <p>His chair scraped the floor. He leaned			
<lb/>heavily across the city desk.</p>
            <p><q>T say, Chief, I don’t need to find out what			
<lb/>he’s doing up here. I know. He’s up here			
<lb/>so’s not to stand in the way of his brother's			
<lb/>happiness. That’s how I dope it out. And			
<lb/>he’s a darned good sort, and I’m hanged if I			
<lb/>want the job of writing a story like that. He’s			
<lb/>a friend of mine, and it’d be a scurvy trick.			
<lb/>It’s none of our dashed business, anyway</q>.</p>
            <p><q>It’s a good newspaper story</q>, said the city			
<lb/>editor without emphasis.</p>
            <p><q>Oh, I dunno. Who gives a hang in this			
<lb/>country about an Englishman? You can dig			
<lb/>up a dozen stories like that any day up here in			
<lb/>Alberta</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Maybe you can</q>.</p>
            <p>Charley Munns answered five telephone</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[259]</fw>
            <pb n="260"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>calls in succession, signed two slips brought to			
<lb/>him by a boy, read a telegram, called an as<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>signment across to a reporter who rose from			
<lb/>his typewriter and made an instant exit, and			
<lb/>then turned back to the gloomy Mallison at			
<lb/>his elbow. A grin twisted the city editor’s			
<lb/>mouth, and a humorous twinkle lighted up his			
<lb/>tired eyes.</p>
            <p><q>Suit yourself, Dunc. Give’s a column,			
<lb/>then, about old P. D. and the chess, and run			
<lb/>a few of the Indian pictures and the one of the			
<lb/>old man—the one with the pipe and the hat.			
<lb/>Cut out the Cheerio man, then. If he’s satis<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>fied where he is, let him stay—among those			
<lb/>missing. We should worry</q>.</p>
            <p>Duncan Mallison grinned delightedly.</p>
            <p><q>Thanks! Ill tell him what you said</q>.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 260 ]</fw>
            <pb n="261"/>
         </div>