<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="chapter" n="9">
            <head>Chapter IX</head>
            <p><q><hi rendition="#smallcaps">AND</hi> they saw by the red flashes of the			
<lb/>lightning against the violet fog at six paces			
<lb/>behind the governor, a man clothed in black			
<lb/>and masked by a visor of polished steel,			
<lb/>soldered to a helmet of the same nature, which			
<lb/>altogether enveloped him. .. </q>.</p>
            <p><q> ‘Come, monsieur,’ said Saint Mars sharply			
<lb/>to the prisoner—‘Monsieur, come on.’</q></p>
            <p><q>Say, ‘</q><q>Monseigneur</q>,’ cried Athos from			
<lb/>his corner, with a voice so terrible that the			
<lb/>governor trembled from head to foot. Athos			
<lb/>insisted upon respect being paid to fallen			
<lb/>majesty. The prisoner turned around.</p>
            <p><q> ‘Who spoke?’ said Saint Mars</q>.</p>
            <p><q> Tt was I,’ said D’Artagnan</q>.</p>
            <p><q> ‘Call me neither </q><q>monsieur</q> nor <q>mon<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>seigneur</q>,’ said the prisoner— ‘Call me			
<lb/><q>Accursed</q>.’</p>
            <p><q>Fle passed on, and the iron door creaked			
<lb/>after him</q>.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 104 ]</fw>
            <pb n="105"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p><q>Ten o’clock!</q></p>
            <p><q>Oh-h!</q></p>
            <p><q>Tt’s not—not quite ten, Your watch’s			
<lb/>slow</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Ten minutes after</q>, declared Cheerio,			
<lb/>hiding a smile as he glanced at his watch in			
<lb/>the slightly waning light.</p>
            <p>A murmur of protest from Hilda, and a			
<lb/>growl from Sandy, ready to argue the point.			
<lb/>It seemed as if they always reached the			
<lb/>most thrilling part of the narrative when <q>ten			
<lb/>o’clock</q> the limit hour set for the end of the			
<lb/>reading would come and Cheerio would, with			
<lb/>seeming reluctance, close the enthralling book.</p>
            <p>The readings had been substituted for the			
<lb/>daily riding trips. The adventures of <q>The			
<lb/>Three Musketeers</q> were proving of even more			
<lb/>enthralling interest to Sandy than the fossi<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>lized bones of the early inhabitants of the			
<lb/>North American continent. No dime novel of			
<lb/>the most lurid sort had had the power to fasci<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>nate or appeal to the imagination of the young			
<lb/>McPhersons as this masterpiece of the elder			
<lb/>Dumas. They were literally transplanted in</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 105 ]</fw>
            <pb n="106"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>thought into the France of the Grande Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>arche.</p>
            <p>Hilda indeed so lost herself each night in			
<lb/>the chronicle that she forgot her grudge			
<lb/>against the reader, and sat on one side of him			
<lb/>almost as closely, peering over his arm at the			
<lb/>page, as Sandy on the other side. Of course,			
<lb/>the steps were not wide and barely accommo<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>dated the three and Hilda’s place was next to			
<lb/>the wall. Cheerio sat between the two.</p>
            <p>After the readings there would follow an			
<lb/>excited discussion of the story that was almost			
<lb/>as interesting as the tale itself. It was aston<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ishing how much this Englishman knew about			
<lb/>France in the time of Louis the XIV. Sandy			
<lb/>would pepper him with questions, and some<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>times sought to entrap him into returning to			
<lb/>the tale.</p>
            <p><q>What was Aramis doing at that time? I			
<lb/>betchu he had a finger in it all the time. Was			
<lb/>he a regular priest?</q></p>
            <p><q>Tf I'd a been D’Artagnan you bet I’d ’ve			
<lb/>stood up for the Man in the Iron Mask. I			
<lb/>betchu he’d ’ve made a better king than Louis</q>.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 106 ]</fw>
            <pb n="107"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>Couldn’t you read just as far as where they			
<lb/>take the mask off? Did they ever take it off?			
<lb/>Say, if you set your watch by Chum Lee’s			
<lb/>clock, he’s eight minutes and </p>
            <p><q>The clock’s all right, old man. To-mor<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>row’ll be here soon. It’s getting pretty dark			
<lb/>now anyway</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Oh, that don’t mean it’s late, and I c’d get			
<lb/>a lantern if you like. Days are shorter now in			
<lb/>Alberta. Before long we won’t have any night			
<lb/>light at all, ’cept the star and moon kind</q>.</p>
            <p>Hilda was as concerned in the fortunes of			
<lb/>the Musketeers as her brother, but she was			
<lb/>obliged to curb her curiosity. With the end<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing of the reading, her diffidence and re<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>straint would gradually creep back upon her.			
<lb/>She was not going to let this man know how			
<lb/>throbbingly interested she was. She did not			
<lb/>wish him to know how limited had been her			
<lb/>reading up to this time. That was a family			
<lb/>skeleton that was none of his business, and she			
<lb/>could have given Sandy a hard shaking when			
<lb/>he disclosed to Cheerio the type of literature			
<lb/>that he and Hilda had been <q>raised on</q>.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 107 ]</fw>
            <pb n="108"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>Cheerio, with intense seriousness, assured			
<lb/>them that their father was <q>dead right</q>. That			
<lb/>sort of reading, as P. D. had declared, was			
<lb/><q>truck</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Well, it’s all there is anyway</q>, defended			
<lb/>Sandy.</p>
            <p><q>Not by a jugful, old man. There’s no			
<lb/>limit to the amount of books in this good old			
<lb/>world of ours—fine stuff, like this, Sandy.			
<lb/>Some day you'll look upon them as friends—			
<lb/>living friends</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Geel I wisht I knew where I could get			
<lb/>’em then</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Why you can get all the books you want in			
<lb/>the public library and in the b-book stores</q>.</p>
            <p><q>That’s easy enough to say</q>, burst from			
<lb/>Hilda, <q>but Dad never gives us time when we			
<lb/>go to Calgary to get anywhere near a library,			
<lb/>and he’d have a fit if we were to buy books.			
<lb/>He says that he’ll choose all that we need to			
<lb/>read, and he doesn’t believe in stories or fiction			
<lb/>and books like that. He says it’s all made-up			
<lb/>stuff and what we want to read—to study, he			
<lb/>says—is Truth</q>.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 108 }</fw>
            <pb n="109"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p><q>Hmph!</q> from Sandy. <q>Yes, Mister Dar<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>win and Mister Huxley and a lot of for’n stuff.			
<lb/>He’s got a heap of French and German books,			
<lb/>but a lot of good they do us, since we can’t			
<lb/>read ’em. He’s got five volumes of chess alone,			
<lb/>and books and books ’bout cattle and pigs and			
<lb/>horses. Just s’f any boy wanted to read that			
<lb/>sort of bunk. It’s a doggone shame. [If it			
<lb/>wasn’t for the bunkhouse Hilda and I never</q></p>
            <p>would ’ve had no ejucation at all.</p>
            <p>Cheerio laughed. He could not help him<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>self, though he quickly repressed it, as he felt			
<lb/>the girl beside him stiffening.</p>
            <p><q>Well, old man, the stuff from the bunk<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>house will do you more harm than good. I			
<lb/>wouldn’t touch it with a stick. Tell you what			
<lb/>we'll do. When we’re through with the Mus<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>keteers, we'll have a regular course of read<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing</q>.</p>
            <p><q>You said there were three sequels to the			
<lb/>Musketeers</q>.</p>
            <p><q>So there are, and we'll read them too; but			
<lb/>we want to vary our reading. Now we'll</q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 109 ]</fw>
            <pb n="110"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>tackle a bit of Scott and then there’s some			
<lb/>poetry I want you to read and </p>
            <p><q>Poetry! Slush-mush! Gee, we don’t			
<lb/>want any poetry</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Oh, yes, you do. Wait till you hear the			
<lb/>kind of poetry I’m going to read to you. Wait			
<lb/>till we get into the ‘Idylls of the King.’ </q></p>
            <p><q>Idols! You mean gods like the savages			
<lb/>worship?</q></p>
            <p><q>‘No—but never mind. You'll see when we			
<lb/>get to them</q>.</p>
            <p>Hilda said, with some pride:</p>
            <p><q>First time we go to Calgary, I’m going to			
<lb/>buy some books for myself</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Where you going to get the money from?</q></p>
            <p>demanded Sandy.</p>
            <p><q>I suppose Lady Bug won’t take the first			
<lb/>prize at the Fall Horse Show—Oh, no, of			
<lb/>course not</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Ye-eh, and he’ll make you put the prize			
<lb/>money in the bank</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Fe won’t</q>.</p>
            <p><q>How won't he?</q></p>
            <p><q>Because</q>, said Hilda, with dignity, <q>I</q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 110 ]</fw>
            <pb n="111"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>happen to be eighteen years old. That’s of			
<lb/>age. Hecan’t. Of course, you——</p>
            <p>Sandy groaned. Hilda had on more than			
<lb/>one occasion rubbed in to him the sore matter			
<lb/>of his infernal youth and her own advantage			
<lb/>of being of age—the extraordinary powers			
<lb/>that descended upon her in consequence of			
<lb/>those eighteen years.</p>
            <p><q>I betchu</q>, said Sandy, <q>that Dad’ll whirl			
<lb/>us through the town, in and out for the Fair,			
<lb/>and we won’t get anywhere near a book-store			
<lb/>or the libry, and we won’t get a hopping			
<lb/>chance to do any shopping. And if we do,			
<lb/>he’ll go along to choose for us. Besides he’ll			
<lb/>make you give him a list of the things you buy,			
<lb/>and you won’t dare to put books on that list.			
<lb/>He calls it systematic, scientific, mathmatical			
<lb/>training of the mind. Oh, my God—frey!</q></p>
            <p><q>I don’t care</q>, said Hilda bitterly. <q>TI in<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tend to buy what I choose with my own money.			
<lb/>I’m going to get that book ‘The Sheik.’ I			
<lb/>saw it in the movies, with Valentino, and it			
<lb/>was just lovely. Dad was playing chess at the			
<lb/>Palliser and left me in the car, and [ got out</q></p>
            <p>fxr ]</p>
            <pb n="112"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>and went to the movies, and I just loved it,			
<lb/>and I’m going every time I get a chance. You			
<lb/>just watch me.</p>
            <p>Something in the eager, hungry way in			
<lb/>which the girl spoke touched Cheerio and			
<lb/>caused him suddenly to put his hand over the			
<lb/>small one resting on her lap. His touch had			
<lb/>an electrical effect upon the girl. She started			
<lb/>to rise, catching her breath in almost a sob.			
<lb/>She stood hesitating, trembling, her hand still			
<lb/>held in that warm, comforting grasp. At that			
<lb/>moment Cheerio would have given much to be			
<lb/>alone with the girl. A few moments only of			
<lb/>this thrilling possession of the little hand.			
<lb/>Then it was wrenched passionately free.			
<lb/>Hilda was regaining possession of her senses.			
<lb/>The dusk had fallen deeply about them and			
<lb/>he could not see her face, but he felt the quick,			
<lb/>throbbing breath. A moment only she stayed,			
<lb/>and then there was only the blur of her fleeing			
<lb/>shadow in the night. Yet despite her going			
<lb/>Cheerio felt strangely warmed and most in<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tensely happy. He was acquiring a better			
<lb/>knowledge and understanding of Hilda. Her</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 112 ]</fw>
            <pb n="113"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>odd moods, her chilling almost hostile attitude			
<lb/>and speech no longer distressed him. Per<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>haps this might have been due to an amazing			
<lb/>and most delicious explanation that her red<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>haired brother had vouchsafed :</p>
            <p><q>I guess my sister’s stuck on you</q>, had vol<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>unteered Sandy carelessly, whittling away at			
<lb/>a stick, and utterly unconscious of the effect			
<lb/>of his words on the alert Cheerio. <q>Cause			
<lb/>she swipes you to your face and throws a fit			
<lb/>if anyone says a word about you behind your			
<lb/>back</q>.</p>
            <p>Little did that freckled-faced boy realize			
<lb/>the amazing effects of his words. No further			
<lb/>information in fact might have come from			
<lb/>him at this juncture had not Cheerio flagrantly			
<lb/>bribed him with <q>two bits</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Go on Sand </q></p>
            <p><q>Go on with what?</q></p>
            <p><q>About what you were saying about your			
<lb/>sister</q>.</p>
            <p><q/><q>Wa-al—</q> Sandy scratched his chin after			
<lb/>the manner of his father, as he tried to recall			
<lb/>some specific instance to prove his sister’s in-</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[113]</fw>
            <pb n="114"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>terest in the briber. <q>I said myself that you			
<lb/>were a poor stiff and she says: ‘You judge</q></p>
            <p>everyone by yourself, don’t your’? And then			
<lb/>I heard her give Hello to Bully Bill, ’cause he			
<lb/>said that Holy Smoke was the best rider at			
<lb/>O Bar O and Hilda says: ‘Why, Cheerio can			
<lb/>ride all around him and back again. He’s			
<lb/>just a big piece of cheese.’ And I heard Ho			
<lb/>himself makin’ fun of you ’bout takin’ baths			
<lb/>every day and ’bout your boiled Sunday shirts,			
<lb/>and Hilda says to him: ‘ "I'wouldn’t be a bad			
<lb/>idea if you took a leaf or two out of his book			
<lb/>yourself; only you'll need to stay in the river			
<lb/>when you do get there, though it'll be hard			
<lb/>on the river.’ And another time I heard her			
<lb/>say to Bully Bill when he was referrin’ to you			
<lb/>as a vodeveel act, that time they put you to			
<lb/>breakin’ Spitfire, she says: ‘Wonder what			
<lb/>you’d look like yourself on his back? Wonder			
<lb/>if you’d stay on. Spitfire’s pretty slippery,			
<lb/>you know, and you’re no featherweight,’ and			
<lb/>Bully Bill says: ‘Hell, I ain’t no tenderfoot,’			
<lb/>and she says: ‘’Course not. You’re a hard<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>boiled pig’s foot,’ and before he could sass her</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[114]</fw>
            <pb n="115"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>back—if he dared and he don’t dare, neither,			
<lb/>she was off into the house and had banged the			
<lb/>door on him. You know Hilda. Geel</p>
            <p>Yes, he was beginning to know Hilda!</p>
            <p>[rs]</p>
            <pb n="116"/>
         </div>