<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="chapter" n="18">
            <head>Chapter XVIII</head>
            <p><hi rendition="#smallcaps">IF</hi> the orders issued from headquarters			
<lb/>(viz. P. D. McPherson) had been implicitly			
<lb/>obeyed, the life of the newspaper man would			
<lb/>have been most uncomfortable. Even as it			
<lb/>was, he was prudent enough to give the house			
<lb/>a wide berth. <q>Dunc</q> Mallison was fond of			
<lb/>fishing, and his assignment was in the nature			
<lb/>of a vacation for him. He possessed a <q>dinky</q>			
<lb/>little flivver, whose front seat turned back on			
<lb/>hinges, transforming the interior into a tol<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>erably comfortable bed, ala Pullman. Scout<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing along the banks of the Ghost River, which			
<lb/>bounded one side of the O Bar O ranch, the			
<lb/>newspaper man found an ideal place for a			
<lb/>camp, not far from the cave where Cheerio			
<lb/>painted of a Sunday in secret.</p>
            <p>Though <q>Dunc</q> fished the greater part of			
<lb/>the day, he nevertheless dispatched bulletins			
<lb/>to his paper in town, and began work on a			
<lb/>feature story concerning P. D., the mysterious			
<lb/>Cheerio, Hilda McPherson, <q>beautiful daugh-</q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 208 ]</fw>
            <pb n="209"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>ter of the Chess Champion and famous			
<lb/>rancher, Sandy, the wise young son and heir			
<lb/>of O Bar O, and the various other folk who			
<lb/>made up that temperamental ranch. The re<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>porter depended not upon personal interviews			
<lb/>with P. D. himself after that first explosive<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>forced session, through the medium of the evi<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>dently belligerent Hilda. Sandy, the guileless			
<lb/>and the garrulous, himself interested in the			
<lb/>attractions of the Ghost River canyon, was a			
<lb/>mine of information upon which the reporter			
<lb/>drew at length. Sandy was unable to resist			
<lb/>the cigarette case, nor did the resulting tumult			
<lb/>in his stomach of that first day’s indulgence			
<lb/>prevent his appearance at the newspaper man’s			
<lb/>camp and the reindulgence in the noxious			
<lb/>weed, which his father had once vehemently			
<lb/>declared was <q>purely poisonous</q>.</p>
            <p>Besides Sandy, Mallison had made the ac<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>quaintance of Cheerio. The latter, on his way			
<lb/>to his <q>cave studio</q>, had paused at the sight			
<lb/>of the reporter, fishing in the forbidden waters			
<lb/>of the Ghost River. Now P. D. had nailed			
<lb/>at the Bridge on the Banff Road, large signs,</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 209 ]</fw>
            <pb n="210"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>warning all aspiring fishermen to keep away			
<lb/>from the Ghost River, and these prominent			
<lb/>notices were signed <q>P. D. McPherson, Fish			
<lb/>and Game Warden</q>. Cheerio, an employe of			
<lb/>the O Bar O, was puzzled for a moment what			
<lb/>to do in the circumstances, but the triumph<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ant smile of the reporter as he held up three			
<lb/>shining-bodied trout, disarmed the English<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>man, who grinned back in sympathetic re<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>sponse, and a moment later was sitting on the			
<lb/>bank beside the trespasser, filling his pipe from			
<lb/>his old rubber pouch.</p>
            <p>All of that quiet Sunday morning, the two			
<lb/>fished and smoked, and though their conversa<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tion practically consisted of monosyllabic re<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>marks about the water or the possibility of			
<lb/>there being a pool farther up the river where			
<lb/>their chances might be even better and grunts			
<lb/>of satisfaction or exclamations of delight			
<lb/>when something nibbled or bit at the end of			
<lb/>the lines, almost unconsciously a quiet feeling			
<lb/>of comradeship grew up between them, and			
<lb/>each took the measure of the other and knew			
<lb/>him for a kindred spirit.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 210 ]</fw>
            <pb n="211"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>In the middle of the afternoon, they counted			
<lb/>with pride the results of the day’s work.			
<lb/>Cheerio made a <q>rock stove</q> and built a fine			
<lb/>bonfire in it, while Mallison cleaned and pre<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>pared the fish. While the bacon was splut<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tering upon the pan, Sandy came down			
<lb/>through the bush, and squatting down before			
<lb/>the reporter’s improvised table of an upturned			
<lb/>suit case, he sniffed the odour of frying bacon			
<lb/>hungrily and said vehemently, as his hands			
<lb/>rested upon his stomach, <q>Oh, boy!</q> Mal<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>lison was an excellent cook, and Cheerio and			
<lb/>Sandy were excellent eaters and they did jus<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tice to the fare set before them by the camper.</p>
            <p>After the meal, the three <q>chinned</q>, as			
<lb/>Sandy expressed it, until the deepening of the			
<lb/>sun glow showed the end of the approaching			
<lb/>day, and Sandy’s drowsy head slipped back			
<lb/>upon the grass and his questions came irregu<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>larly and presently not at all. Then Cheerio			
<lb/>dumped his pipe, shook the half-asleep boy,			
<lb/>and said:</p>
            <p><q/><q>Come on, old man. Time to get back</q>,			
<lb/>and Sandy sat up with a start, rubbed his</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">{ 211 }</fw>
            <pb n="212"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>eyes, yawned, and unwillingly arose and			
<lb/>moved toward Silver Heels, whose bridle had			
<lb/>slipped down the slender trunk of the tree to			
<lb/>which it had been loosely tied.</p>
            <p>At the ranch house, the nightly games pro<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ceeded. Sometimes a game would end with</p>
            <p>a single night’s playing; at other times a game			
<lb/>would drag along for a week.</p>
            <p>Cheerio had won three games in succession,			
<lb/>when he suggested that his opponent should			
<lb/>be allowed a handicap. P. D. received this			
<lb/>generous suggestion with hostility and fury.</p>
            <p><q>What for? What for? Because you win			
<lb/>a damnation game or two, do you mean to			
<lb/>insinuate that I am out of your class?</q></p>
            <p><q>Nn-n-not at all, sir</q>, stammered Cheerio,			
<lb/>‘b-b-but you see, I’ve a b-b-bit of an advan<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tage over you, sir. B-b-been playing ch-chess			
<lb/>for a long time b-b-before coming to the			
<lb/>ranch.</p>
            <p>It was true enough, P. D. admitted, that he			
<lb/>was off his game on account of having had			
<lb/><q>only children and amateurs</q> to play with.			
<lb/>Nevertheless he had not fallen to the damned</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">{ 212 ]</fw>
            <pb n="213"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>handicap class. There were thirty-one days in			
<lb/>the month; they had been playing but ten in<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>conclusive and insignificant days; he was			
<lb/>neither a cripple nor a moron and he’d give his			
<lb/>opponent a dashed stiff fight before he was			
<lb/>through with him, and he asked for no quarter			
<lb/>whatsoever now.</p>
            <p>The fierceness with which the old man took			
<lb/>his well-meaning suggestion caused Cheerio			
<lb/>to stammer further explanations. During his			
<lb/>recent stay in Germany, so he said, he had			
<lb/>played constantly, and the Germans were ex<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>cellent players.</p>
            <p>This was the first intimation that he had			
<lb/>been in Germany, and the information passed			
<lb/>over P. D.’s head as of no especial interest,			
<lb/>but Hilda’s eyes narrowed and she began to			
<lb/>speculate v on the cause of his presence in			
<lb/>their late enemy’s country. From day to day,			
<lb/>Hilda had been hardening her heart more and			
<lb/>more against him and she was ready to believe			
<lb/>the worst. Hilda had her opinion of a man			
<lb/>who pretended to be a cowpuncher, who wore			
<lb/>a piece of jewellery dangling from a black</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[213 ]</fw>
            <pb n="214"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>fob at his waist. She despised the type of man,			
<lb/>so she told herself, who carried a woman’s face			
<lb/>in a locket. Only a <q>sissy</q> would do an asi<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>nine and slushy thing like that, and sissies			
<lb/>were not popular in the ranching country.			
<lb/>However, apparently unconscious of, or in<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>different to, her glance of scorn at the depised			
<lb/>locket, he continued daily to wear it, and quite			
<lb/>often, right before her eyes, even lovingly and			
<lb/>tenderly toyed with it.</p>
            <p><q>What were you doing in Germany?</q>			
<lb/>queried Sandy, pop-eyed with interest.</p>
            <p>Cheerio moved uneasily, thrust his hand			
<lb/>through his hair, looked dashed and worried,			
<lb/>and shook his head.</p>
            <p><q>When were you there?</q> persisted Sandy.			
<lb/><q>Was it when the war was on?</q></p>
            <p><q>Y-y-y-yes, I believe it wa </q> admitted			
<lb/>Cheerio, uncertainly.</p>
            <p><q>Believe it was!</q> said Hilda. <q>Don’t you			
<lb/>know when you were there?</q></p>
            <p><q>Well—</q> began Cheerio, miserably, <q>‘you			
<lb/>see </q></p>
            <p>He was interrupted by P. D., whose exas-</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[214]</fw>
            <pb n="215"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>perated glare turned from his son to his daugh<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ter.</p>
            <p><q>Ts this a game of chess, or a quizz concern<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing international questions touching upon the			
<lb/>infernal recent war?</q></p>
            <p><q>Chess, by all means, sir</q>. Thus Cheerio,			
<lb/>placatingly, and with evident relief at the			
<lb/>change of subject. To Sandy, he promised:</p>
            <p><q>Tell you all about Germany some day, old			
<lb/>man, wh-wh-when I’m f-ff-feeling a b-bit			
<lb/>more f-fit to tackle the s-ssubject</q>. To P. D.			
<lb/>persuasively:</p>
            <p><q>How about it, governor? It’s quite fair			
<lb/>under the circumstances that I should yield			
<lb/>you something. What do you say to a Castle?			
<lb/>One will do me first-rate</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Sir, when I want quarter, I’ll ask for it.			
<lb/>I'll have you know that I have never yet taken			
<lb/>a dashed flippity handicap and when the time			
<lb/>comes for me to do that, by Gad! I'll cease			
<lb/>to play. I play, sir, chess, and I want no			
<lb/>damned favouritism. I'll be placed under no			
<lb/>G—D—oblig—D—igation to any man</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Righto! Your move, sir</q>.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[215]</fw>
            <pb n="216"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>P. D. was indeed off his game. He was,			
<lb/>moreover, the victim of a creeping panic. He			
<lb/>made longer pauses, debated a move for a			
<lb/>solid hour, in the meanwhile moving (in his			
<lb/>head) every single man upon the board; im<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>agine their effect in such and such a position,			
<lb/>then presupposing a move which his oppo<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>nent never intended to make, with a crafty			
<lb/>quiver of a bushy eyebrow old P. D. would			
<lb/>move to the attack, when the position of his			
<lb/>King called for defense.</p>
            <p>Once Cheerio made an obviously bad and			
<lb/>wild move. This was when looking up un<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>expectedly he had found Hilda regarding			
<lb/>him, not with her usual expression of hate and			
<lb/>scorn, but with her dark eyes brimming with			
<lb/>something that brought a strange tug to his			
<lb/>heart and dimmed his own eyesight.</p>
            <p>At that bad move, P. D.’s amazed eyes shot			
<lb/>up above his glasses and he coughed angrily.			
<lb/>If his opponent were attempting to curry			
<lb/>favour with him by playing badly, he would			
<lb/>receive no thanks. P. D. removed Cheerio’s			
<lb/>valuable Bishop which had been sacrificed by</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 216 ]</fw>
            <pb n="217"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>his absent move, and snarled across the board:</p>
            <p><q>Damned curious move, sir. You wish to			
<lb/>stop for to-night?</q></p>
            <p><q>M-m-m-ore c-c-areful next time</q>, mur<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>mured Cheerio, stiffened by the fact that			
<lb/>Hilda had blinked the brightness out of her			
<lb/>eyes, and her chin was at a most disdainful			
<lb/>angle. More careful he was; wary, keen and			
<lb/>cunning. Before the clock pointed to nine			
<lb/>o’clock, Cheerio murmured his firm, if slightly			
<lb/>regretful:</p>
            <p><q>Check! Game!</q></p>
            <p>P. D. studied the board, his eyebrows			
<lb/>twitching. His King was enclosed on all			
<lb/>sides. Not even a chance for stalemate. This,			
<lb/>though Cheerio had sacrificed his Bishop.			
<lb/>P. D. blinked behind his glasses, cleared his			
<lb/>throat noisily and grunted:</p>
            <p><q>Four games for you, sir</q>. After another			
<lb/>noisy clearing of throat:</p>
            <p><q>Tides turn, sir. Tides turn. He ‘laughs			
<lb/>best who laughs last.’ </q></p>
            <p><q>Oh, rather</q>, agreed Cheerio eagerly.</p>
            <p>Undemonstrative Hilda came behind her</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 217]</fw>
            <pb n="218"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>father, solicitous and sweet, hovered above			
<lb/>him a moment, sat on the arm of his chair, put			
<lb/>her arm about his shoulders, cuddled her			
<lb/>warm cheek lovingly against the top of his			
<lb/>grey head. P. D. jerked up, shaking the			
<lb/>embracing arms irritably from his shoulders.</p>
            <p><q>Well, well, what’s this? What’s this?			
<lb/>Stop pawing me</q>, he objected. ‘What in the			
<lb/>name of Holy Christmas are you whimpering			
<lb/>about? I don’t like it. Women’s tears are a			
<lb/>scientific evidence of a weak intellect. Stop			
<lb/>sniffing, I say! Stop leaking on my neck!			
<lb/>Damn dash it all! Get away! Get away!</p>
            <p>Hilda’s rare tears, dropping like pearls			
<lb/>down her russet cheeks, described as leaks! In			
<lb/>the presence of that man, stooping above the			
<lb/>chess board the better to hide the amused grin			
<lb/>that would show despite his best efforts, de<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>spite indeed the stony glare (if eyes moist with			
<lb/>running-over tears could stonily glare) that			
<lb/>Hilda favoured him with.</p>
            <p>She had no soft thoughts for him now. If			
<lb/>she could have forgotten his confession at the</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 218 ]</fw>
            <pb n="219"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>corrals, Hilda felt that she never, never could			
<lb/>forgive his treatment of her father.</p>
            <p>Just what Hilda would have desired him to			
<lb/>do in the circumstances, cannot be said. She</p>
            <p>would have shared her father’s resentment had			
<lb/>Cheerio purposely played a poor game, in			
<lb/>order to give the older man an opportunity to			
<lb/>win. Nevertheless she bitterly resented the			
<lb/>fact that his victories were crushing the spirit			
<lb/>of the old chess warrior. There had been			
<lb/>some discussion—an idea, in fact, put out in			
<lb/>the newspaper of that miserable reporter who			
<lb/>was camped down by the river, on the edge of			
<lb/>the O Bar O lands, that in the event of P. D.’s			
<lb/>failure to beat the Englishman that the latter			
<lb/>should take his place in Chicago, so that			
<lb/>Canada’s chances of the world championship			
<lb/>might be more likely assured.</p>
            <p>That story, read by Hilda in the newspaper			
<lb/>brought her from the camp by Sandy, and			
<lb/>jealously hidden from her father, caused the			
<lb/>girl’s heart to ache. She was intensely pa<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>triotic, was Hilda, and she desired, as any good			
<lb/>Canadian would, to see the championship</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 219]</fw>
            <pb n="220"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>wrested from the U. S. A., but she loathed the			
<lb/>thought of the wrester being Cheerio. She			
<lb/>had fondly hoped to see her father in that de<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>sired role. Her heart coiled in tenderness</p>
            <p>about the crochetty, thorny old man, with his			
<lb/>stumbling moves. She could not recall when			
<lb/>her father had played so poorly or so uncer<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tainly. He seemed to have lost all of his			
<lb/>former skill. His confidence in himself as a			
<lb/>chess player was completely gone. Anyone			
<lb/>could have seen that after watching the old			
<lb/>man play. Even the winning of one game			
<lb/>might have a good effect and restore P. D.’s			
<lb/>former confidence and craft. It was the daily			
<lb/>absorption in the game, and the constant losing			
<lb/>which was having its bad psychological effect			
<lb/>upon him. Hilda knew that if P. D. failed			
<lb/>to keep that Chicago engagement, he would			
<lb/>suffer the bitterest disappointment of his life.			
<lb/>She feared, indeed, it would seriously affect			
<lb/>his health. He would lose his interest in chess			
<lb/>forever, and for P. D. to lose interest in chess			
<lb/>was tantamount to losing interest in life itself.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 220 ]</fw>
            <pb n="221"/>
         </div>