<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="chapter" n="1" change="#proofed">
            <head>Chapter I</head>
            <p><hi rendition="#smallcaps">Along</hi> the <placeName>Banff National Highway</placeName>, auto<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>mobiles sped by in a cloud of dust, heat, noise			
<lb/>and odour. They stopped not to offer a lift to			
<lb/>the wayfarer along the road, for they were			
<lb/>intent upon making the evergrowing grade to			
<lb/><placeName>Banff</placeName> on <soCalled>high</soCalled>.<note type="editorial">Make some note here "Some Motorists" etc.</note></p>
            
            <p>This year <term ref="gls:tram1">tramps</term> were common on the road,			
<lb/>war veterans, for the most part, <soCalled>legging it</soCalled>			
<lb/>from <placeName>Calgary</placeName> to lumber or road camp, or			
<lb/>making for the ranches in the foothills, after			
<lb/>that elusive job of which the Government			
<lb/>agent in England had so eloquently expatiated,			
<lb/>but which proved in most cases to be but a			
<lb/>fantastic fable.<note type="editorial"/> With somewhat of that pluck			
<lb/>which had meant so much to the world, when			
<lb/>the <soCalled>vets</soCalled> were something more than mere job			
<lb/>hunting tramps, these men from across the sea
            <fw type="pageNum">[7]</fw>
            <pb n="8"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
<lb/>trudged in the heat, the dust and the dry			
<lb/><term ref="gls:alka1">alkali-laden</term> air. Sometimes they were taken			
<lb/>on at camp or ranch. More often they were			
<lb/>shunted farther afield. One wondered where			
<lb/>they would finally go, these <soCalled>boys</soCalled> from the			
<lb/>old land, who had crossed to the Dominion of			
<lb/>Canada with such high hopes in their breasts.<note type="editorial">Note about The Dominion of Canada (i.e. pre 1967).</note></p>
            <p>The <placeName ref="plc:obar1">O Bar O</placeName> lies midway between <placeName>Calgary</placeName>			
<lb/>and <placeName ref="plc:banf1">Banff</placeName>, in the foothills of the ranching			
<lb/>country. Its white and green buildings grace			
<lb/>the top of a hill that commands a view of the			
<lb/>country from all sides.</p>
            <p>From the <placeName>Banff</placeName> road the fine old ranch pre<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>sents an imposing sight, after miles of road			
<lb/>through a country where the few habitations			
<lb/>are mainly those melancholy shacks of the first			
<lb/>homesteaders of <placeName>Alberta</placeName>.</p>
            <p>When <q><persName>Bully Bill</persName></q><!--What kind of quote here?-->, foreman of the <placeName>O Bar
<lb/>O</placeName>, drove his herd of resentful steers from the			
<lb/>green feed in the north pasture, where they			
<lb/>had broken through the four lines of barbed			
<lb/>wire, he was shouting and swearing in a blood<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>curdling and typically O Bar O<!--Placename if adjectival?--> fashion,			
<lb/>whirling and cracking his nine feet long bull
            <fw type="pageNum">[8]</fw>
            <pb n="9"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
<lb/>whip over the heads of the animals, as they			
<lb/>swept before him down to the main gate.</p>
            <p><persName>Bully Bill</persName> had <soCalled>herding</soCalled> down to a science,			
<lb/>and <q>them doegies</q>, as he called them, went in			
<lb/>a long line before him like an army in review.			
<lb/>Had events followed their natural course, the			
<lb/>cattle should have filed out of the opened gate			
<lb/>into the roadway, and across the road to the			
<lb/>south field, where, duly, they would distribute			
<lb/>themselves among the <term>hummocks</term> and <term>coulies</term>			
<lb/>that afforded the most likely places for graz<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing. On this blistering day, however, <persName>Bully			
<lb/>Bill</persName>’s formula failed. Something on the wide			
<lb/>road had diverted the course of the driven			
<lb/>steers. Having gotten them as far as the road,			
<lb/><persName>Bully Bill</persName> paused in his vociferous speech and			
<lb/>heady action to take a <soCalled>chaw</soCalled> of his favorite			
<lb/>plug; but his teeth had barely sunk into the			
<lb/>weed when something caused him to shift it			
<lb/>to his cheek, as with bulging eyes, he sat up			
<lb/>erectly upon his horse, and then moved for<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ward into swift action.</p>
            <p>A certain pausing and grouping, a bunching			
<lb/>together and lowering of heads, the ominous
            <fw type="pageNum">[9]</fw>
            <pb n="10"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
<lb/>movement of a huge <term>roan</term> steer ahead of the			
<lb/>herd, apprised the experienced cowpuncher			
<lb/>of the fact that a stampede was imminent.</p>
            <p>As he raced through the gate, <persName>Bully Bill</persName>			
<lb/>perceived the cause of the revolution of his			
<lb/>herd. Directly in the path of the animals was			
<lb/>a strange figure. Not the weary footsore tramp			
<lb/>common to the trail. Not the nervy camper,			
<lb/>applying at <placeName>O Bar O</placeName> for the usual donation of			
<lb/>milk and eggs. Neither neighbour, nor <term>Indian</term><!--Think about best way to gloss "Indian"-->			
<lb/>from <placeName>Morley</placeName>. Here was a clean tweed-clad			
<lb/>Englishman, with a grip in his hand. How			
<lb/>he had maintained his miraculous neatness			
<lb/>after forty-four miles of tramping all of the			
<lb/>way from Calgary cannot be explained.</p>
            <p>Eye to eye he faced that <term>roan</term> steer, whose			
<lb/>head sank loweringly, as he backed and swayed			
<lb/>toward that moving mass behind him, all			
<lb/>poised and paused for the charge.</p>
            <p>Time was when the Englishman had been			
<lb/>in another kind of a charge, but that is a			
<lb/>different story, and <placeName>France</placeName> is very far away			
<lb/>from <placeName>Alberta, Canada</placeName>.</p>
            <p>As the dumbfounded cowpuncher raced
            <fw type="pageNum">[10]</fw>
            <pb n="11"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
<lb/>wildly in his direction, the man afoot did a			
<lb/>strange thing. Raising on high his grip in his			
<lb/>hand, he flung it directly into the face of the			
<lb/><term>roan</term> steer. In the scattering and scampering			
<lb/>and bellowing that ensued, it was hard to dis<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tinguish anything but dust and a vast, moving			
<lb/>blur, as the startled herd, following the lead			
<lb/>of the <term>roan</term> steer, swept headlong down the			
<lb/>road, to where in the canyon below, the <placeName>Ghost</placeName>			
<lb/>and the <placeName>Bow Rivers</placeName> had their junction.</p>
            <p>From the direction of the corrals swept			
<lb/>reinforcements, in the shape of <soCalled>Hootmon</soCalled>,			
<lb/>a Scot so nicknamed by the outfit, because of			
<lb/>his favourite explosive utterance,<note type="editorial"><!--Do I need a note here?--></note> and <persName>Sandy</persName>,			
<lb/>son of the <placeName>O Bar O</placeName>, red-haired, freckled<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>faced and indelibly marked by the sun above,			
<lb/>who rode his <term>Indian bronc</term> with the grace and			
<lb/>agility of a circus rider.</p>
            <p>Into the roaring mêlée charged the yelling			
<lb/>riders. Not with the <soCalled>hobo-dude</soCalled><!--Gloss?-->, lying on			
<lb/>the inner side of the barbed-wire fence,			
<lb/>through which he had scrambled with alacrity			
<lb/>before the roan steer had recovered from the			
<lb/>onslaught of the grip, were the <soCalled>hands</soCalled> of the
            <fw type="pageNum">[11]</fw>
            <pb n="12"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
<lb/>ranch concerned. Theirs the job to round up			
<lb/>and steady that panic-stricken herd; to bring			
<lb/>order out of chaos; to soothe, to beat, to drive			
<lb/>into a regulation bunch, and safely land the			
<lb/>cattle in the intended south field.</p>
            <p>Half an hour later, when the last of the tired			
<lb/>herd had passed through the south gate, when			
<lb/>the bellowings had died down and already the			
<lb/>leaders were taking comfort in the succulent			
<lb/>green grass on the edges of a long slough,			
<lb/><persName>Bully Bill</persName> bethought him of the cause of all			
<lb/>this extra work and delay. He released that			
<lb/>plug of tobacco from his left cheek, spat			
<lb/>viciously, and with vengeance in his eye, rode			
<lb/>over to where the intruder still reclined upon			
<lb/>the turf. Said turf was hard and dry, and			
<lb/>tormenting flies and grasshoppers and flying			
<lb/>ants leaped about his face and neck; but he			
<lb/>lay stretched out full-length upon his back,			
<lb/>staring up at the bright blue sky above him.			
<lb/>As <persName>Bully Bill</persName> rode over, he slowly and easily			
<lb/>raised himself to a sitting posture.</p>
            <p><said who="#Hootman" toWhom="#Cheerio">Hi! you there!</said> bawled the foreman, in the			
<lb/>overbearing voice that had earned for him his
            <fw type="pageNum">[12]</fw>
            <pb n="13"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
               nickname. <said who="#Hootman" toWhom="#Cheerio">What the hell are you squattin’			
<lb/>out here for? What d’ya mean by stirrin’ up			
<lb/>all this hell of a racket? What the hell d’ya			
<lb/>want at <placeName>O Bar O</placeName>?</said></p>
            <p>The stranger smiled up at him, with the sun			
<lb/>glinting in his eyes. His expression was guile<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>less, and the engaging ring of friendliness and			
<lb/>reassurance in his voice caused the irate cow<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>hand to lapse into a stunned silence, as he			
<lb/>gaped at this curious specimen of the human			
<lb/>family on the ground before him.</p>
            <p><said who="#Cheerio" toWhom="#Hootman">Ch-cheerio!</said> said the visitor. <said>No harm			
<lb/>done. I’m f-first rate, thank you. Not even			
<lb/>scratched. How are you?</said></p>
            <p><persName>Hootmon</persName> applied his spurs to his horse’s			
<lb/>flanks, and cantered up the hill in the direction			
<lb/>of the corrals, there to recount to an interested			
<lb/>audience old <persName>Bully Bill</persName>’s discomfiture and			
<lb/>amazement.</p>
            <p>Things move slowly in a ranching country,			
<lb/>and not every day does the Lord deposit a			
<lb/>whole <term>vaudeville act</term> at the door of a ranch			
<lb/>house.</p>
            <p><persName>Sandy</persName>, seeking to curry favour with the con<pc force="weak">-</pc>
            <fw type="pageNum">[13]</fw>
            <pb n="14"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
<lb/>founded foreman, winked at him broadly, and			
<lb/>then deliberately pricked the rump of the			
<lb/>unfortunate Silver Heels<!--Tag horses names?--> with a pin. Kicking			
<lb/>around in a circle, the bronco backed and			
<lb/>bucked in the direction of the man upon the			
<lb/>grass, now sitting up and tenderly examining			
<lb/>an evidently bruised shin.</p>
            <p>At this juncture, the long-suffering Silver			
<lb/>Heels developed an unexpected will of his			
<lb/>own. Shaking himself violently from side to			
<lb/>side, he reared up on his hind legs, and by a			
<lb/>dash forward of his peppery young head, he			
<lb/>jerked the reins from the hands of the sur<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>prised lad, who shot into the air and nearly			
<lb/>fell into the lap of the Englishman.</p>
            <p>That individual gripped the boy’s arm			
<lb/>tightly and swung him neatly to his side.</p>
            <p><said who="#Sandy" toWhom="#Cheerio">You leggo my arm!</said></p>
            <p><persName>Sandy</persName> squirmed from the surprisingly iron			
<lb/>grip of the visitor.</p>
            <p>The tramp, as they believed him to be, was			
<lb/>now sitting up erectly, with that sublime,			
<lb/>smooth air of cheerful condescension which			
<lb/>Canadians so loathe in an Englishman.<note type="editorial"><!--Some note here re: The Dukes in Alberta etc--></note></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[14]</fw>
            <pb n="15"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p><said who="#Cheerio" toWhom="#Sandy">Cheerio, old man!</said> said he, and slapped			
<lb/>the unwillingly impressed youngster upon the			
<lb/>back. <said who="#Cheerio" toWhom="#Sandy">Not hurt much—what?</said></p>
            <p><said who="#Sandy" toWhom="#Cheerio">Hurt—nothing! Whacha take me for?</said></p>
            <p><persName>Sandy</persName>, a product of <placeName>O Bar O</placeName>, let forth a			
<lb/>typical string of hot cusses, while the English<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>man grinned down upon him.</p>
            <p><said who="#Sandy" toWhom="#Cheerio">What the hell you doin’ sittin’ on our			
<lb/>grass?</said> finished <persName>Sandy</persName> shrilly. <said who="#Sandy" toWhom="Cheerio">What cha			
<lb/>want at our ranch?</said></p>
            <p><said who="#Cheerio" toWhom="#Sandy">Oh, I say! Is this a rawnch then?</said></p>
            <p>He turned a questioning eager gaze upon			
<lb/>the foreman, who now sat with right leg rest<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing across the pummel of the saddle, studying			
<lb/>their visitor in puzzled silence. After a mo<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ment, having spat and transferred his plug			
<lb/>from the left to the right cheek, <persName>Bully Bill</persName>			
<lb/>replied through the corner of his mouth.</p>
            <p><said toWhom="#Cheerio" who="#Bill">You betchour life this ain’t no rawnch,			
<lb/>Ain’t no <emph>rawnches</emph> this side o’ the river. They			
<lb/><emph>ranch</emph> on this side</said>.</p>
            <p>The other looked unenlightened, and <persName>Bully			
<lb/>Bill</persName> condescended further explanation, with a			
<lb/>flicker of a wink at the delighted <persName>Sandy</persName>.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[15]</fw>
            <pb n="16"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p><said who="#Bill" toWhom="#Cheerio">Yer see, it’s like this. On the south side of			
<lb/>the river, there’s a sight of them English			
<lb/><soCalled>dooks</soCalled><note type="editorial">I.e. Dukes</note> and earls and lords and princes.<!--Maybe here is where I put the contextual note re: WE's article on Dukes etc--> They			
<lb/>play at rawnching, doncherknow<note type="editorial">I.e. Don't you know.</note>. On the			
<lb/>north side, we’re the real cheese. We're out			
<lb/>to raise beef.<!--Note here about beef industry in Alberta?--> We <emph>ranch</emph>!</said></p>
            <p>Having delivered this explanation of things			
<lb/>in the cattle country, <persName>Bully Bill</persName>, well pleased			
<lb/>with himself, dropped his foot back into his			
<lb/>stirrup and saluted the Englishman conde<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>scendingly:</p>
            <p><said who="#Bill" toWhom="#Cheerio">Here’s lookin’ at you!</said><!--Research needed here: Is this referring to malboro? Is that relevant yet?--> he said, and gently			
<lb/>pressed his heel into his horse’s side.</p>
            <p><said who="#Cheerio">I say———!</said></p>
            <p>The tramp had sprang to his feet with sur<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>prising agility, and his nervy hand was at the			
<lb/>mouth of <persName>Bully Bill</persName>’s mount.</p>
            <p><said who="#Cheerio" toWhom="#Bill">I say, old man, will you hold on a bit? I			
<lb/><seg type="stutter">w-w</seg>onder now, do you, by any chance, need			
<lb/>help on your ranch? Because if you do, I’d			
<lb/>like to apply for the position. If this is a			
<lb/>cattle ranch, I'll say that I know a bit about			
<lb/>horses. <seg type="stutter">R-r-r-r</seg>idden <seg type="stutter">s-s</seg>ome in my time, and			
<lb/>I <seg type="stutter">t-t</seg>ook care of a <seg type="stutter">c-c</seg>ar-load of cattle <seg type="stutter">c-c</seg>oming
            <fw type="pageNum">[16]</fw>
            <pb n="17"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
<lb/>up from the east. <seg type="stutter">W-w-w</seg>orked my way out			
<lb/>here, in fact, and as to <seg type="stutter">w-w</seg>ages, nominal ones			
<lb/>will be quite satisfactory as a <seg type="stutter">s-s</seg>tarter</said>.</p>
            <p><persName>Bully Bill</persName>, his mouth gaped open, was sur<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>veying the applicant from head to foot, his			
<lb/>trained eye travelling from the top of the			
<lb/>sleekly-brushed blond hair, the smoothly-			
<lb/>shaven cheek, down the still surprisingly			
<lb/>dapper form to the thin shoes that were so			
<lb/>painfully inadequate for the trail. <persName>Sandy</persName> was			
<lb/>doubled up in a knot, howling with fiendish			
<lb/>glee. <persName>Bully Bill</persName> spat.</p>
            <p><said who="#Cheerio" toWhom="#Bill">T <seg type="stutter">d-d</seg>on’t <seg type="stutter">m-m</seg>ind roughing it at all</said>, con<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tinued the applicant, wistfully. <said who="#Cheerio" toWhom="#Bill"><seg type="stutter">D-d</seg>on’t			
<lb/>judge me by my clothes. Fact is, old man,			
<lb/>they happen to be all I’ve <seg type="stutter">g-g</seg>ot, you see.			
<lb/><seg type="stutter">B-b</seg>ut I’m quite <seg type="stutter">c-c</seg>ompetent to——</said></p>
            <p>Bully Bill said dreamily, looking out into			
<lb/>space, and as if thinking aloud.</p>
            <p><said who="#Bill">We ain’t as tough as we’re cracked up to be.			
<lb/>Of course, they’s one or two stunts you got to			
<lb/>learn on a cattle ranch—rawnch—beggin’
<lb/>your pardon———</said></p><!--Is this said to Cheerio?-->
            <fw type="pageNum">[17]</fw>
            <pb n="18"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p><said who="#Cheerio" toWhom="#Bill">That’s quite all right, old man. Don’t			
<lb/>mention it. Is there a chance then for me?</said></p>
            <p>There was not a trace of a smile on Bully			
<lb/>Bill’s face as he solemnly looked down into			
<lb/>the anxious blue eyes of the applicant.</p>
            <p><said who="#Bill" toWhom="#Cheerio">They’s the makin’s of a damn fine cowboy			
<lb/>in you</said>, he said.</p>
            <p><said who="#Cheerio" toWhom="#Bill">I say!</said></p>
            <p>A smile broke all over the somewhat			
<lb/>pinched face of the strange tramp. That smile			
<lb/>was so engaging, so sunny, so boyish that the			
<lb/>cowpuncher returned it with a characteristic			
<lb/>grin of his own.</p>
            <p><said who="#Cheerio" toWhom="#Bill">D-you really mean to say that I’m en<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>gaged?</said></p>
            <p><said who="#Bill" toWhom="#Cheerio">You betchu</said>.</p>
            <p><said who="#Cheerio" toWhom="#Bill">Thanks awfully, old man</said>, cried the other			
<lb/>cordially, and extended his white hand, which			
<lb/>gripped the horney one of the cowpuncher, at			
<lb/>rest on his leather-clad knee.</p>
            <p><persName>Bully Bill</persName> rode off at a slow lope, and as he			
<lb/>rode, he steadily chewed. Once or twice he			
<lb/>grunted, and once he slapped his leg and made			
<lb/>a sound that was oddly like a hoarse guffaw.</p><!--Note here maybe?-->
            <fw type="pageNum">[18]</fw>
            <pb n="19"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>In the wake of the loitering horse, carrying			
<lb/>his now sadly-battered grip in his hand, the			
<lb/>Englishman plugged along, and as he came he			
<lb/>whistled a cheery strain of music.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[19]</fw>
         </div>