<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="chapter" n="27">
            <head>Chapter XXVII</head>
            <p><hi rendition="#smallcaps">HILDA</hi> awoke with a sob. She sat up in bed,			
<lb/>pressing her hands to her eyes. Slowly, pain<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>fully, she recalled the events of the previous			
<lb/>night.</p>
            <p>She had called him a cheat—a coward! She			
<lb/>had said that she never wished to see his face			
<lb/>again! She had driven him from O Bar O.			
<lb/>He had gone out of her life now forever.</p>
            <p>Hilda could see the dim light of the ap<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>proaching dawn already tinting the wide east<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ern sky. It was a chill, raw morning. -He			
<lb/>would walk out from O Bar O, with his old,			
<lb/>battered grip in his hand and that gray suit			
<lb/>that had so edified the ranch hands. Her			
<lb/>breast rose and swelled. The tears of the			
<lb/>previous night threatened to overwhelm her			
<lb/>again. Hilda had literally cried practically			
<lb/>all of the night, and her hour’s sleep had come			
<lb/>only through sheer exhaustion.</p>
            <p>The unhappy girl crept out of bed and knelt</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 302 }</fw>
            <pb n="303"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>by the window, peering out in the first grey			
<lb/>gloom of the Autumn morning, toward the			
<lb/>bunkhouse. She fancied she saw something			
<lb/>moving in that direction, but the light was			
<lb/>dim, and she could not be sure.</p>
            <p>It was cold and damp as she knelt on the			
<lb/>floor. No matter. He would be cold and			
<lb/>chilled, too, and she had driven him from O			
<lb/>Bar O!</p>
            <p>A light gleamed now in the dusk over at the			
<lb/>saddle rooms. A glance at her watch showed			
<lb/>it was not yet six o’clock. He would make an			
<lb/>early start, probably leaving before the men			
<lb/>started off on the round-up—they were to			
<lb/>leave for the range at seven that morning.</p>
            <p>Without quite realizing what she was doing,			
<lb/>Hilda dressed swiftly. The cold water on her			
<lb/>tear-blistered face soothed and cooled it. She			
<lb/>wrapped a cape about herself, put on a knitted			
<lb/>tam.</p>
            <p>The halls were dark, but she dared not turn			
<lb/>on the electric lights, lest she should awaken			
<lb/>Sandy or her father. Feeling her way along			
<lb/>the wall, she found the stairs, and clinging to</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 303 ]</fw>
            <pb n="304"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>the bannister went quickly down. A moment			
<lb/>to seek the door knob, and swing the big door			
<lb/>open. At last she was out of the house.</p>
            <p>The cold air smote:and revived her. It			
<lb/>gave her courage and strength.</p>
            <p>The darkness was slowly lifting, and all			
<lb/>over the sky the silvery waves of morning were			
<lb/>now spreading. Hilda sped like a fawn across			
<lb/>the barn yard, through the corrals and directly			
<lb/>to the saddle room, from whence came the			
<lb/>light. The upper part of the door was open,			
<lb/>and Hilda pushed the lower part and stepped			
<lb/>inside.</p>
            <p>A man in white chaps was bending over a			
<lb/>saddle to which he was attaching a lariat rope.			
<lb/>As the lower door slammed shut behind Hilda,			
<lb/>he started like an overtaken thief, and jumped			
<lb/>around. Hilda saw his face. It was Holy			
<lb/>Smoke.</p>
            <p>All at once Hilda McPherson knew that			
<lb/>before her stood the man who had tried to			
<lb/>lariat her in the woods. She stared at him now			
<lb/>in a sort of fascinated horror. A cunning look			
<lb/>of surprised delight was creeping over the</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 304 ]</fw>
            <pb n="305"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>man’s face. Hilda put her hand behind her			
<lb/>and backed for the door. At the same time,			
<lb/>once again she raised her voice, and sent forth			
<lb/>that loud cry of alarm:</p>
            <p><q>Hi-yi-yi-yi-yl-yi-yi-itiii-i-i-i-i!l</q></p>
            <p>The cry was choked midway. She was held			
<lb/>in a strangling hold, the big hand of the cow<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>puncher gripped upon her throat.</p>
            <p><q>There'll be none of the Hi-yi-ing for you			
<lb/>to-day! If you make another peep, I’ll choke			
<lb/>you to death! I’m quittin’ O Bar O for good			
<lb/>and all to-day, but before I go you and me has			
<lb/>got an account to settle</q>.</p>
            <p>She fought desperately, with all her splen<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>did young strength, scratching, kicking, biting,			
<lb/>beating with her fists like a wild thing at bay,			
<lb/>and, with the first release as he staggered back,			
<lb/>when her sharp teeth dug into his hands, again			
<lb/>she raised her voice; but this time her cry was			
<lb/>stopped by the brutal blow of the man’s fist.			
<lb/>She clutched at the wall behind her. The			
<lb/>earth seemed to rock and sway and for the first			
<lb/>time in all her healthy young life, Hilda Mc<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>Pherson fainted.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 305 ]</fw>
            <pb n="306"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>She lay on a sheepskin, a man’s coat beneath			
<lb/>her head. Chum Lee knelt beside her, cup in			
<lb/>hand. She swallowed with difficulty, for her			
<lb/>throat pained her and she still felt the grip of			
<lb/>those terrible fingers. Hilda moaned and			
<lb/>moved her head from side to side. The			
<lb/>Chinaman said cheerfully:</p>
            <p><q>All lightee now, Miss Hilda. Chum Lee			
<lb/>flix ’im fine. Slut ’im. Bang ’im. Slut ’im			
<lb/>up till Mr. Cheeriocome. Big fight!</q> Chum			
<lb/>Lee’s eyes gleamed. <q>All same Holy Smoke			
<lb/>bad man. Take ’im gun. Banfi! Sloot Mr.			
<lb/>Cheerio. Velly good, now lide on Jail</q>.</p>
            <p>Hilda understood only that Holy Smoke			
<lb/>had shot Cheerio.</p>
            <p>She clutched the Chinaman’s arm, and			
<lb/>forced herself to her feet. Pushing Chum Lee			
<lb/>aside, Hilda made her way from the saddle			
<lb/>shed, where they had laid her.</p>
            <p>Outside, the sharp cold air of the Fall morn<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing was like a dash of bitter water and brought			
<lb/>its revivifying effect. Hilda turned in the di<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>rection of the voice she now heard clearly, for			
<lb/>sound carries far in a country like Alberta,</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 306 ]</fw>
            <pb n="307"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>and although Hilda could clearly hear the			
<lb/>voices of the men, they were in fact more than			
<lb/>a mile from the ranch. She was obsessed with			
<lb/>the idea that Cheerio had been killed and that			
<lb/>her men had taken his murderer into the			
<lb/>woods and were hanging him. Oh! she			
<lb/>wanted a hand in that hanging. Everything			
<lb/>primitive and wild in her nature surged now			
<lb/>into being, as she made her way blindly down</p>
            <p>that incredibly long hill and ran stumblingly			
<lb/>through the pasture lands to where the group			
<lb/>of men were about some strange object that			
<lb/>was tied and bound half sitting on a rail.			
<lb/>Then Hilda understood, and waves of unholy			
<lb/>joy swept over her in a flood. They were tar<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ring and feathering Holy Smoke!</p>
            <p>Above the deafening roar of the cheering			
<lb/>shouting voices, presently rose the clear call			
<lb/>of the one she knew. No fluttering, stammer<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing tongue now. The voice of a captain, a			
<lb/>leader among men:</p>
            <p><q>One, two, three! In she goes!</q></p>
            <p>The rail was swung back and forth, and at			
<lb/>that <q>Three</q>, with a roar from twenty or</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 307 ]</fw>
            <pb n="308"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>thirty throats, it was released from the hands			
<lb/>gripping it at either end and plunged into the			
<lb/>muddy water of the shallow slough. It de<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>scribed a somersault. Head downward went			
<lb/>the man they had tarred and feathered. The			
<lb/>rail jerked over, and the head of Holy Smoke			
<lb/>arose out of the water, a grotesque paste of			
<lb/>mud and tar covering it completely. Loud			
<lb/>shouts of glee arose from the men. They			
<lb/>jeered and yelled to the struggling wretch in</p>
            <p>the water.</p>
            <p>From the direction of the ranch, came the			
<lb/>sound of the loud clanking breakfast bell of			
<lb/>Chum Lee. In high good humour, with appe<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tites whetted and vengeance satisfied, the men			
<lb/>of O Bar O retraced their steps toward the			
<lb/>ranch, prepared for that hearty breakfast			
<lb/>which should stiffen them against the invigor<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ating work of at last rounding up.</p>
            <p>Cheerio alone remained by the slough, and			
<lb/>Hilda, watching him from the little clump of			
<lb/>bush, witnessed a strange and merciful act on			
<lb/>his part; the sort of thing a man: of Cheerio’s			
<lb/>type was accustomed to do at the front, when</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 308 ]</fw>
            <pb n="309"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>an enemy, hors de combat, needed final suc<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>cour. Cheerio thrust two long logs into the			
<lb/>mud of the slough, very much as he had done			
<lb/>when he had rescued the heifer in the woods.			
<lb/>Now also he went out across the logs and cut			
<lb/>the ropes that bound the man to the rail.			
<lb/>Holy Smoke grasped after the logs, clung to			
<lb/>them desperately, and Cheerio gave his stiff			
<lb/>order to him to get off the place as expedi<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tiously as possible if he valued his hide.</p>
            <p>Having set the man free, Cheerio returned			
<lb/>to the bank, stopped to clean the mud off his			
<lb/>boots with a handy stick and then moved to			
<lb/>follow after the men, now at a considerable			
<lb/>distance.</p>
            <p>Hilda, her blue and red cape flapping back			
<lb/>from her as she came from the little bush to<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ward him, was holding out both her hands, but			
<lb/>as Cheerio stopped short they dropped help<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>lessly at her side. His grave eyes slowly trav<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>elled over the piteous little figure in his path.			
<lb/>The eyes that had been so stern now softened,			
<lb/>but Cheerio could not speak at that moment.			
<lb/>Something rose in his throat and held him</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 309 ]</fw>
            <pb n="310"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>spellbound, looking at the girl he loved and			
<lb/>whom he had expected never to see again.			
<lb/>Hilda’s eyes were unnaturally wide and dark;			
<lb/>her lips were as tremulous as a flower and			
<lb/>quivering like those of a hurt child. The flag			
<lb/>of hostility and hate was down forever. She			
<lb/>was pathetic and most lovely in her humility.</p>
            <p>Cheerio murmured something unintelligible			
<lb/>and held out his arms to her. Hilda would			
<lb/>have gone indeed directly to that haven; but			
<lb/>there was Sandy racing along the trail on			
<lb/>Silver Heels, shouting like an Indian excited			
<lb/>queries and shrilly demanding to know why he			
<lb/>had been <q>left out of the fun</q>. Nevertheless,			
<lb/>Cheerio had sensed the unconscious motion of			
<lb/>the girl, and a light broke over his face, driv<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing away the last shadow. His wide, boyish			
<lb/>smile beamed down upon her. Speech failed			
<lb/>him not at that blessed moment.</p>
            <p><q>Darling!’ said Cheerio, in such a voice			
<lb/>that Hilda thought the word an even more			
<lb/>beautiful one than the </q><q>Dear</q> he had once			
<lb/>before called her.</p>
            <p><q>Hi, Hilday! What’s all the racket about?</q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 310]</fw>
            <pb n="311"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>What they done to Ho? Whereis he? Dad’s			
<lb/>goin’ to kill °em. He’s gone plumb crazy at			
<lb/>the house. Chum Lee come on in an tol’ ’im			
<lb/>that he beat you up. Is that true?</p>
            <p>Cheerio answered for her.</p>
            <p><q>He’s a bad lot, Sandy, and he’s got his			
<lb/>deserts</q>. His eyes were still on Hilda. It			
<lb/>didn’t seem possible that he could withdraw			
<lb/>them. Over her pale cheeks a glow was com<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing like the dawn, and her shy glance trembled			
<lb/>toward his own.</p>
            <p><q>My! Dad’s hoppin’ mad. Ses hangin’ ain’t			
<lb/>too good for him, the dirty dog, an I say it tool			
<lb/>What'd he do to youe What was you doin’ in			
<lb/>the barn at that hour?</q></p>
            <p>Hilda shook her head. Her eyes were shin<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing so that even Sandy was nonplussed.</p>
            <p><q>You don’t look beaten up</q>, said her			
<lb/>brother, and Hilda laughed and then unex<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>pectedly her eyes filled with tears and she			
<lb/>sobbed.</p>
            <p><q>Gee! I wish someone’d waked me up.			
<lb/>Doggone it, I don’t see why I was left out.			
<lb/>Wish I'd caught him hittin’ my sister! Dad’s</q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[3]</fw>
            <pb n="312"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>nearly crazy. You better hustle along home,			
<lb/>Hilda. You’d think you were the only person			
<lb/>at O Bar O now to hear Dad talk. He’s			
<lb/>thinkin’ up every mean thing he ever said to			
<lb/>you and he’s cryin’ like a baby.</p>
            <p><q>Poor old Dad!</q> said Hilda, softly.</p>
            <p>A movement on the edge of the slough now			
<lb/>attracted the incredulous eyes of Sandy Mc<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>Pherson. He was shuffling into the clothes			
<lb/>left for him on the bank. Instantly Sandy had			
<lb/>reined up beside him. He yelled insults and			
<lb/>epithets down at the shivering wretch on the			
<lb/>bank, stuck his fingers into his mouth and pro<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>duced a hooting whistle then Sandy played			
<lb/>at lariating the man, but Ho, with a venomous			
<lb/>look, grasped the rope as it fell in a ring near			
<lb/>him, and there was a tug of war for its posses<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>sion between man and boy. Sandy let go the			
<lb/>rope and concentrated upon the nine foot long			
<lb/>bull whip in his other hand. Yelling to the			
<lb/>man to move along swiftly and to get <q>to hello</q>			
<lb/>off O Bar O, Hilda’s brother pursued her as<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>sailant.</p>
            <p>Meanwhile, Hilda and Cheerio seized the</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[312]</fw>
            <pb n="313"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>opportunity to continue that interrupted duo<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>logue. He said suddenly, after a rapt mo<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ment:</p>
            <p><q>Hilda, you don’t hate me then, do you,			
<lb/>dear?</q></p>
            <p>In a little voice, Hilda said:</p>
            <p><q>No</q>.</p>
            <p><q>And you d-don’t want me to go away, do			
<lb/>your</q></p>
            <p>Hilda shook her head, too moved for more			
<lb/>speech, but her eyes brimmed at the mere			
<lb/>thought of his going. That was too much for			
<lb/>Cheerio, and regardless of Sandy, he took			
<lb/>Hilda’s hand.</p>
            <p><q>Then I'll stay</q>, he said, softly.</p>
            <p>Hand in hand, they were moving home<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ward, walking in an entranced silence, the			
<lb/>glow of the early morning drawing them			
<lb/>under its golden spell; but before Sandy had			
<lb/>joined them, all that they had yearned to say			
<lb/>and hear was spoken.</p>
            <p><q>Hilda! I love youl</q></p>
            <p><q>Oh, do your Then—then—that Nanna—</q></p>
            <p><q>Nanna is seventy-four. My old nurse</q>,</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 313 ]</fw>
            <pb n="314"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>Hilda. When I returned from—Germany—			
<lb/>I was a prisoner there nine months, Hilda—			
<lb/>Nanna was the only one at home who knew me.			
<lb/>You see—you see—it was better that they			
<lb/>shouldn’t know me. M-m-my brother was in			
<lb/>my place. And you see, Hilda, I c-came out			
<lb/>here, and N-Nanna planned to f-follow me.			
<lb/>She is seventy-four.</p>
            <p><q>Seventy-four! Oh, I thought—-I thought			
<lb/>—that picture in the locket——</q></p>
            <p><q>That was Sybil—now my brother’s wife</q>.</p>
            <p>Wonderful things were happening to Hilda.			
<lb/>She wanted to laugh; she wanted to cry, and			
<lb/>the pink cheek wavered from him, and then			
<lb/>came to rest against his rough sleeve. Cheerio			
<lb/>never even glanced back to see if Sandy were			
<lb/>at hand. He placed his arm completely and			
<lb/>competently around Hilda’s waist. Their lips			
<lb/>were very close. This time it was Hilda who			
<lb/>whispered the words, and Cheerio bent so close			
<lb/>to hear them that his lips came upon her own.</p>
            <p><q>Oh, I loved you all the time!</q> said Hilda			
<lb/>McPherson.</p>
            <p>At this juncture, they stopped walking, for</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[314]</fw>
            <pb n="315"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>one may not kiss as satisfactorily while moving			
<lb/>along.</p>
            <p>When Hilda regained her power of speech,			
<lb/>she said:</p>
            <p><q>I’m never going to say another unkind</q></p>
            <p>thing to you.</p>
            <p><q>You can say anything you want, sweet<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>heart</q>, said Cheerio. <q>Whatever you say will			
<lb/>sound just right to me—dearest old girl</q>.</p>
            <p>It occurred to Hilda that he possessed a			
<lb/>most wonderful and extensive vocabulary.			
<lb/>She had never heard such terms before, and			
<lb/>when she had read them Hilda had felt em<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>barrassed, and in her rough way had thought:			
<lb/><q>Oh, slush!</q></p>
            <p>But somehow the words had an almost			
<lb/>lyrical sound when uttered by the infatuated			
<lb/>Cheerio.</p>
            <p>They were brought back to life by the yip<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ping, jeering Sandy.</p>
            <p><q>Geel I believe you two’s struck on each			
<lb/>other!</q></p>
            <p>He reined up beside them and examined the</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[315]</fw>
            <pb n="316"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>telltale faces with all a boy’s cunning and dis- |			
<lb/>gusted amusement.</p>
            <p><q>Say, are you goin’ to git married?</q></p>
            <p><q>You better believe we are!</q> laughed			
<lb/>Cheerio, falling easily into the slang of the			
<lb/>country.</p>
            <p><q>Holy Salmon! Well, there’s no accountin’			
<lb/>for tastes</q>, said Hilda’s young brother, with			
<lb/>disparagement. ‘Then resignedly: <q>But, I			
<lb/>betchu Dad’ll be tickled. He’ll have a life			
<lb/>partner for chess. Geel Here’s where I			
<lb/>escape!</q></p>
            <p>He kicked his heels into his horse’s flanks			
<lb/>and with the grace and agility of a circus rider,			
<lb/>with neither saddle nor bridle merely a halter’			
<lb/>—Sandy was off. He turned bodily around in			
<lb/>his seat on the running horse’s back to yell			
<lb/>back at them as he rode, hand to mouth:</p>
            <p><q>Aw, cut out the spoons! I’m going to			
<lb/>hustle home and break the news to fa-ather!			
<lb/>Let ’er go, bronc! Let’er fly! Let ’er fly!</q></p>
            <p>They smiled after the vanishing boy, smiled			
<lb/>into each other’s faces and smiled at the sun<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>shine and the gilded hills, now shining in the</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 316 ]</fw>
            <pb n="317"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>full light of the marvellous Alberta sun.			
<lb/>After a moment, shyly, despite the fact that			
<lb/>she was held closely to him:</p>
            <p><q>What’s your real name?</q></p>
            <p><q>Edward Eaton Charlesmore of Maccles<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>field and Coventry</q>.</p>
            <p><q>You’re making fun of me</q>.</p>
            <p><q>N-no, I’m not, darling. That’s my real			
<lb/>name</q>.</p>
            <p>Hilda smiled delightedly.</p>
            <p><q>But what do they call you?</q></p>
            <p>He laughed, squeezed her tightly, kissed her			
<lb/>and then kissed her again.			
<lb/>: <q>Cheerio!</q> he said.</p>
            <p><q>But that’s not a real name!</q></p>
            <p><q>Tt’s good enough for me. You gave me it,			
<lb/>you know</q>.</p>
            <p><q>And—and are you really a duke or some<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>thing like that?</q></p>
            <p>Again he laughed.</p>
            <p><q>You bet I am</q>.</p>
            <p>Her face fell. She regretted his high estate.			
<lb/>Cheerio put his lips against her small pink</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[317]</fw>
            <pb n="318"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>ear, and he kissed it before he whispered what			
<lb/>he said was a great secret:</p>
            <p><q>Hilda, Pl tell you who I am: Cheerio,			
<lb/>Duke of the O Bar O, and you’re the darling			
<lb/>Duchess!</q></p>
            <p><q>That’s Jake!</q> said Hilda.</p>
            <p>THE END</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 318]</fw>
         </div>