<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="chapter" n="14">
            <head>Chapter XIV</head>
            <p><hi rendition="#smallcaps">AT</hi> the ranch house, P. D. McPherson al<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ternately paced the living-room, the hall, the			
<lb/>dining-room, the kitchen and the back and			
<lb/>front verandahs.</p>
            <p>Fourteen times he called for his daughter			
<lb/>and twice fourteen times he had roared for			
<lb/>his son.</p>
            <p>The morning’s mail (brought on horseback			
<lb/>seven miles from Morley post-office by an In<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>dian) contained a letter that P. D. had been			
<lb/>waiting for all of that summer. It was brief			
<lb/>and to the point almost of curtness. It con<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>sisted of one line scrawl of a certain famous			
<lb/>chess player in the City of Chicago and was			
<lb/>to the effect that the writer would be pleased			
<lb/>to accept the challenge of the Canadian player			
<lb/>for November 3oth of the current year.</p>
            <p>If P. D. had drunk deeply and long of some			
<lb/>inebriating cup he could not have felt any			
<lb/>more exhilarated than after reading that epis<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tle.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 162 ]</fw>
            <pb n="163"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>On November thirtieth—scarce two months			
<lb/>off—he, P. D. McPherson, chess champion			
<lb/>of Western Canada, was to go to the City of			
<lb/>Chicago, in the State of Illinois, there to sit			
<lb/>opposite the greatest chess player in the United			
<lb/>States of America and at that time demon<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>strate to a skeptical world that Canada existed			
<lb/>upon the map.</p>
            <p>He’d show ’em, by Gad! Yanks! (The			
<lb/>average Canadian refers to the average Amer<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ican as <q>Yank</q> or <q>Yankee</q> regardless of the			
<lb/>part of the States of which he may be a resi<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>dent. P. D. knew better than to refer to a			
<lb/>Chicagoan as a Yank, but had acquired the			
<lb/>habit, and in his heart he was not fussy over			
<lb/>designations. )</p>
            <p>Yanks! Hmph! P. OD. snorted and			
<lb/>laughed, and G.D.’ed the race heartily and			
<lb/>without stint. Not that he had any special			
<lb/>animus against Americans. That was just			
<lb/>P. D.’s way of expressing himself. Besides			
<lb/>he was still smarting over having been ignored			
<lb/>and snubbed for long by those top-lofty, self<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>satisfied, condescending lords of the chess</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 163 ]</fw>
            <pb n="164"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>board. For two years P. D. had banged at			
<lb/>the chess door and only now had he at last			
<lb/>been reluctantly recognised. He’d show ’em			
<lb/>a thing or two in chess.</p>
            <p>Yanks as chess players! It was to laugh!			
<lb/>P. D. had followed every printed game that			
<lb/>had been published in the chess departments			
<lb/>of the newspapers and periodicals. His fin-</p>
            <p>gers had fairly itched many a time when a			
<lb/>game was in progress to indite fiery instruc<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tions to the d-d-d-d-d-d-d-fool players, who			
<lb/>were alternately attacking and retreating at			
<lb/>times when a trick could be turned that would			
<lb/>end hostilities at a single move. P. D. knew			
<lb/>the trick. It was all his own. He had in<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>vented it; at least, he thought he had invented			
<lb/>it, and had been angry and uneasy at a sug<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>gestion put out by a recent player that it			
<lb/>was a typically German move.</p>
            <p>Two months! Two months in which to			
<lb/>practice up and study for the mighty contest,			
<lb/>which might mean that the winner would be			
<lb/>the chosen one in an international tournament			
<lb/>that would include all the nations of the world.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 164 ]</fw>
            <pb n="165"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>Ah ha! He’d waste not a precious moment.			
<lb/>He’d begin at once! At once!</p>
            <p><q>Hilda! Hilda! Hilda! Where’s that			
<lb/>girl? Hilda! Hi, you there, G— D— you			
<lb/>Chum Lee, where’s Miss Hildar</q></p>
            <p><q>Me no know, bossie. Chum Lee no sabe			
<lb/>where Miss Hilda go on afternoon</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Didn’t you see her go by?</q></p>
            <p><q>No, bossie, me no see Miss Hilda. Mebbe			
<lb/>she like go see him blandie</q> (brand).</p>
            <p><q>Beat it over to the corral and tell her I			
<lb/>want her—at once—at once!</q></p>
            <p><q>Hilda! Hil-l-Ida!</q></p>
            <p>He made a trumpet of his hands and roared			
<lb/>his daughter’s name through it.</p>
            <p><q>Hil-ldaf Where in the name of the al<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>mighty maker of mankind is that girl!			
<lb/>Hilda!</q></p>
            <p>Yanks indeed! Dog damn their souls!			
<lb/>Their smug satisfaction with themselves; their			
<lb/>genius for bragging and boasting; their ig<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>norance concerning any other part of the earth			
<lb/>save the sod on which their own land stood—			
<lb/>their colossal self-esteem and intolerance—all</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 165 ]</fw>
            <pb n="166"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>this was evidence of an amazing racial pro<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>vincialism that P. D. proposed to expose and			
<lb/>damn forevermore.</p>
            <p><q>Hilda! Damn it all, where are your</q></p>
            <p><q>Hilda! You hear me very well, miss!</q></p>
            <p>Tramp, tramp, tramp. Round and round			
<lb/>the house, inside and out, hands twitching be<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>hind, holding still to that precious letter.</p>
            <p><q>Sandy! Sandy! Sa-nn-n-ndy! Where’s			
<lb/>that boy gone?</q></p>
            <p>Tramp, tramp again and:</p>
            <p><q>Sandy! You come here, you red-haired			
<lb/>young whipper-snapper—You hear me very			
<lb/>well. Sandy! Sandy! San-n-dyl</q></p>
            <p>No reply. It was evident that the house			
<lb/>was empty and his son and daughter nowhere			
<lb/>within hearing unless in hiding. Chum Lee			
<lb/>scurried past back from the corrals, and ap<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>parently unconscious of the amazed and furi<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ous string of blistering epithets and cusses			
<lb/>that pursued him from his <q>bossie</q>.</p>
            <p>From the direction of the corrals a din			
<lb/>surged, the moaning, groaning calves and the			
<lb/>mothers penned in the neighbouring field.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[{ 166 ]</fw>
            <pb n="167"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>These cries were not music to the ears of the			
<lb/>formerly proud owner of the cattle. It mat<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tered not this day to P. D. whether a brand			
<lb/>was slapped on true or banged on upside down;			
<lb/>whether it were blurred or distinct. It mat<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tered not whether the dehorning shears had			
<lb/>snipped to one inch of the animal’s head as			
<lb/>prescribed by law, or had clipped down into			
<lb/>the skull itself. He paid a foreman cracka<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>jack wages to look after his cattle. If he			
<lb/>could not do the work properly, there were			
<lb/>other foremen to be had in Alberta. P. D.			
<lb/>had no desire whatsoever to go to the corrals			
<lb/>and witness the operations. His place at the			
<lb/>present time was the house, where one could			
<lb/>occupy their minds with the scientific game			
<lb/>of chess.</p>
            <p><q>Sandy! Sandy!</q></p>
            <p>Back into the house went the irate P. D.			
<lb/>The chess table was jerked out and the chess			
<lb/>board set up. P. D. propped up a book con<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>taining illustrations of certain famous chess			
<lb/>games, before him, and set his men in place.</p>
            <p>P. D. began the game with a dummy part-</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">{ 167 ]</fw>
            <pb n="168"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>ner, making his own move first and with pre<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>cise care his partner’s. Fifteen minutes of chess			
<lb/>solitaire and then out again, and another and			
<lb/>louder calling for his son and his daughter.</p>
            <p>No doubt they were at the corrals, dog blast			
<lb/>their young fool souls. What was the matter			
<lb/>with that bleak nit-wit of a foreman? He was			
<lb/>hired to run a ranch, and given more men for			
<lb/>the job than that allotted by any other ranch			
<lb/>for a similar work. What in blue hades did			
<lb/>he mean by drawing upon the house for labor?			
<lb/>The son and daughter of P. D. McPherson			
<lb/>were not common ranch hands that every time			
<lb/>a bit of branding or rounding-up was done			
<lb/>they should be pulled out to assist with the			
<lb/>blanketty, blistering, hell-fire work.</p>
            <p>Raging up and down, up and down, through			
<lb/>the wide verandah and back through the halls			
<lb/>and into the living-room again and again at			
<lb/>the unsatisfactory chess solitaire, the furious			
<lb/>old rancher was in a black mood when voices			
<lb/>outside the verandah caused him to jerk his			
<lb/>chin forward at attention. The missing mis<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>creants had returned!</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">{ 168 ]</fw>
            <pb n="169"/>
         </div>