<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="chapter" n="26">
            <head>Chapter XXVI</head>
            <p>P. D. was taking his <q>cat-nap</q> that evening			
<lb/>in his <q>office</q>, a room that opened off from the			
<lb/>dining-room, where the old rancher kept his			
<lb/>account books and other papers connected with			
<lb/>the running of his business. He was enjoying			
<lb/>a sweet sleep, in which he dreamed of three			
<lb/>white pawns checking a black King. The			
<lb/>three pawns were his. The King was			
<lb/>Cheerio’s. Something unpleasant and having			
<lb/>nothing to do with the soothing picture he was			
<lb/>enjoying, awoke him. He blinked fiercely,			
<lb/>cleared his throat, sat up in the big chair, and			
<lb/>glared disapprovingly at his daughter who had			
<lb/>precipitated herself almost into his lap.</p>
            <p><q>What is the meaning of this? Is it, then,			
<lb/>8.30?</q></p>
            <p><q>No, Dad. You've quarter of an hour still</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Then what in thunderation do you mean by			
<lb/>waking me for, then? Get away! Get away!</q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 290 ]</fw>
            <pb n="291"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>I don’t like to be pawed over in this manner.</p>
            <p><q>Dad, I want to talk to you about something.			
<lb/>IJ—I must talk to you</q>.</p>
            <p><q>When you wish to talk to me, you will			
<lb/>choose an hour when I have the leisure to hear			
<lb/>you</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Dad, you won’t let me speak to you through			
<lb/>the day. You always say you're calculating			
<lb/>something, and now you simply must listen to			
<lb/>me. It’s vitally important that you should.			
<lb/>You must!</q></p>
            <p><q>Must, hehr</q></p>
            <p><q>Please, Dad!</q></p>
            <p><q>Well, well, what is it? Speak up. Speak			
<lb/>up</q>.</p>
            <p>He took his watch out, glanced at it,			
<lb/>scowled, paid no attention to what his daugh<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ter was saying until the word <q>chess</q> escaped			
<lb/>her, when his glance fixed her.</p>
            <p><q>What's that?</q></p>
            <p><q>I said if you’d only defend your King in<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>stead of everlastingly attacking, don’t you see,			
<lb/>you'd stand a better chance. I’ve noticed on</q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[291 ]</fw>
            <pb n="292"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>two or three occasions that he’s left great open<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ings where I’m sure you could</p>
            <p><q>Are you trying to teach your father the			
<lb/>game of chess?</q></p>
            <p><q>Oh, no, Dad, but you know, two heads are			
<lb/>better than one. I’ve heard you say so</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Two mature heads——</q></p>
            <p><q>Mine’s mature. I’m eighteen, and I			
<lb/>think, </q></p>
            <p><q>You're not supposed to think. You're not			
<lb/>equipped for thinking. Women have a con-</q></p>
            <p>stitutional brain impediment that absolutely			
<lb/>prevents them coherently or rationally ———</p>
            <p><q>Dad, look here. Don’t you know that it’s			
<lb/>November 2oth? The cattle are still on the			
<lb/>range and everybody in the country is talking			
<lb/>about us. They think we’ve gone plumb			
<lb/>crazy. And why? Just because he wants to			
<lb/>go on and on beating you and——_</q></p>
            <p><q>What's this? What’s this? A discourse			
<lb/>of depreciation of a prized employee of O			
<lb/>Bar Oe</q></p>
            <p><q>Father!</q> Hilda seldom called her father</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 292 ]</fw>
            <pb n="293"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p><q>Father</q>, but she believed herself to be in a			
<lb/>desperate situation and desperate speech and			
<lb/>measures were necessary. <q>Father, you have			
<lb/>simply got to beat him to-night. You-——</q></p>
            <p><q>You leave the room, miss</q>,</p>
            <p><q>Dad, I </q></p>
            <p><q>Leave the room!</q> roared P. D.</p>
            <p><q>Oh, if you only knew how unhappy I am</q>,			
<lb/>cried Hilda piteously. Her father took her			
<lb/>by the shoulders and turned her bodily out,			
<lb/>closing the door sharply between them, and</p>
            <p>returning to pace the floor of his own office,			
<lb/>and work off some of the upsetting influences			
<lb/>which might not be well for that calmness and			
<lb/>poise of mind necessary for a game of chess.</p>
            <p>The ranch house was a great, unwieldy			
<lb/>building, with a wide hall dividing on one side			
<lb/>the enormous living-room and on the other the			
<lb/>dining-room, beyond which was P. D.’s office			
<lb/>and study.</p>
            <p>Hilda shot out of her father’s office into the			
<lb/>darkened dining-room, and from there into			
<lb/>the lighted hall, where she collided with the</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 293 J</fw>
            <pb n="294"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>entering Cheerio. On him, she turned the			
<lb/>last vials of her wrath.</p>
            <p><q>I’ve something to say to you. Everything			
<lb/>on this ranch is at a standstill on your account.			
<lb/>If we don’t gather in our cattle soon, there'll			
<lb/>be a lot of lost and dead O Bar O stock when			
<lb/>the first blizzard comes. I wish you’d never			
<lb/>come here. You've pulled my old Dad down,			
<lb/>and look what you’ve done to me—look!—I’m			
<lb/>glad you’re going away! I don’t want ever to			
<lb/>see your face again!</q></p>
            <p>Even as she said the words, Hilda longed to			
<lb/>recall them. Cheerio’s hurt look was more			
<lb/>than she could bear, and she fled up the stairs			
<lb/>like one pursued. He heard the bang of her			
<lb/>door, and a strangely softened look stole into			
<lb/>his face as he turned into the living-room.</p>
            <p>The chess board was still set up, the men			
<lb/>standing on the positions of the previous night,			
<lb/>when the game had remained unfinished at the			
<lb/>ending hour of ten o’clock. Cheerio cast a			
<lb/>swift glance about him, studied the board a			
<lb/>moment, and then with another furtive glance,			
<lb/>quickly changed the position of a Black Queen</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 294 ]</fw>
            <pb n="295"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>and a White Pawn. His hand was scarcely off			
<lb/>the board when Hilda McPherson slipped			
<lb/>from between the portieres.</p>
            <p>As swiftly and passionately as she had fled			
<lb/>up the stairs, so she had run down again, com-</p>
            <p>punction overwhelming her, torn and troubled			
<lb/>by that look on the man’s face. But her reac<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tion turned to amazement and indignant scorn			
<lb/>as she watched him at the chess board. If she			
<lb/>had repented her harsh treatment of him be<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>fore, now, more than ever, she ascended in			
<lb/>judgment upon him. His glance fell guiltily			
<lb/>before her accusing one. Hilda seized upon			
<lb/>the first word that came to her tongue, regard<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>less of its odiousness.</p>
            <p><q>Cheat! Cheat! Now I understnd how			
<lb/>you’ve been beating my Dad! You’ve been			
<lb/>changing the positions. You can’t deny itl			
<lb/>I’ve caught you red-handed. Oh, oh! I			
<lb/>might have guessed it. To think that for a			
<lb/>single moment I believed in you, and now to			
<lb/>discover you’re not only a——</q></p>
            <p>He flinched, almost as if physically struck,			
<lb/>and turned white. Then his face stiffened.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 295 ]</fw>
            <pb n="296"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>His heels came together with that peculiarly			
<lb/>little military click that was characteristic of			
<lb/>him when moved. His face was masklike as			
<lb/>he stared straight at Hilda. Something in his			
<lb/>silence, some element of loneliness and help<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>lessness about this man clutched at the stormy			
<lb/>heart of the girl, and stopped the words upon			
<lb/>her lips, as her father came into the room.			
<lb/>Hilda had the strange feeling of a wild mother			
<lb/>at bay. Angry with her child, she yet was			
<lb/>ready to fight for and defend it. All uncon<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>sciously, she had covered her lips with her			
<lb/>hands to crush back the hot words that were			
<lb/>surging up to expose him to her father.</p>
            <p><q>What’s this? Why so much excitement?			
<lb/>Why all this hysterical waste of force? It car<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ried even to my office—electrical waves of			
<lb/>angry sound. No doubt could be heard across			
<lb/>at the bunkhouse or the barns. I'll make a			
<lb/>test some day. Sit down, sit down. If you			
<lb/>wish to witness our game, oblige us with			
<lb/>silence, if you please</q>.</p>
            <p>To Cheerio he said:</p>
            <p><q>Be seated, sir. You will pardon the ex-</q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 296 ]</fw>
            <pb n="297"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>citement of my daughter. Youth is life’s			
<lb/>tempestuous period—hard to govern—hard to			
<lb/>restrain, a pathological, problematical time of			
<lb/>life. Be seated, sir. My move, I believe, sir.</p>
            <p>Hilda felt weak and curiously broken. She			
<lb/>sat forward in her chair, her eyes so dark and			
<lb/>large that her face, no longer rosy, seemed now			
<lb/>peculiarly small and young.</p>
            <p>Old P. D. scratched his chin and pinched			
<lb/>his lower lip as he examined the board through			
<lb/>his glasses. Cheerio was not looking at the			
<lb/>board, his sad, somewhat stern glance was			
<lb/>pinned upon Hilda.</p>
            <p>There was a pause, and suddenly P. D.’s			
<lb/>face jerked forward. A crafty twitch of the			
<lb/>left eyebrow. He glanced up at Cheerio,			
<lb/>moved a Bishop three paces to the right.			
<lb/>Cheerio withdrew his eyes reluctantly from			
<lb/>the drooping Hilda, looked absently at the			
<lb/>board and made the obvious move. Instantly			
<lb/>P. D.’s hand shot toward his Queen. A pause,			
<lb/>and then suddenly through the room, like the			
<lb/>pop of a gun, P. D.’s shout resounded :</p>
            <p><q>Check!</q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 297 ]</fw>
            <pb n="298"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>Pause.</p>
            <p><q>Check!</q></p>
            <p>This time louder.</p>
            <p><q>Check to your King, sir! Game! Game!</q>			
<lb/>Up leaped P. D. McPherson, sprang toward			
<lb/>his opponent, smashed him upon the shoulder,			
<lb/>gripped him by both hands, and shouted:</p>
            <p><q>Beat youl! By Gad! Id rather beat you			
<lb/>than go to Chicago. Damn your hands and			
<lb/>feet, you’re a dashed damned fine player, and			
<lb/>it’s an honour to beat you, sir! Come along			
<lb/>with me, sir!</q></p>
            <p>He dragged his opponent out, and arm and			
<lb/>arm they hurried across to the bunkhouse to			
<lb/>proclaim the <q>damnfine news</q> and to order all			
<lb/>hands of the O Bar O to set out on the follow<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing morning upon that annual Fall round-up			
<lb/>which had been put off for so long. But be<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>fore Cheerio had left the room, and even while			
<lb/>her father was all but embracing him, his			
<lb/>glance had gone straight into the eyes of Hilda,			
<lb/>pale as death and slowly arising.</p>
            <p>Like one moving in sleep, feeling her way			
<lb/>as she passed, Hilda McPherson followed her</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 298 ]</fw>
            <pb n="299"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>father and Cheerio. But she could go no far<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ther than the verandah. There she sat			
<lb/>crouched down on the steps, her face in her			
<lb/>hands, overwhelmed by the unbearable pain			
<lb/>that seemed to clutch at her heart. The truth			
<lb/>had shocked Hilda into a realization of the			
<lb/>inexcusable wrong and insult that she had			
<lb/>dealt to this man. No words were needed.			
<lb/>She comprehended exactly what had happened</p>
            <p>in that room. Cheerio, she now knew, had			
<lb/>changed the men on the board for her father’s			
<lb/>advantage. And she had called him a cheat!</p>
            <p>She took her hands down from her face, and			
<lb/>spoke the words aloud:</p>
            <p><q>T called him a cheat! I called him a—			
<lb/>coward! Oh, what am I to dor</q></p>
            <p>The man who had been sitting in the swing<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing couch, and whom she had not seen, strolled			
<lb/>across the verandah and came directly down			
<lb/>the steps to where the unhappy Hilda was			
<lb/>crouched.</p>
            <p><q>Miss McPherson! Can I do anything for			
<lb/>your</q></p>
            <p>Hilda was in too much pain to feel either</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 299 J</fw>
            <pb n="300"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>surprise or resentment for the intrusion. She			
<lb/>said piteously:</p>
            <p><q>T called him a cheat! a coward!</q></p>
            <p><q>A coward—him/</q></p>
            <p>Duncan Mallison’s face darkened with an			
<lb/>almost angry red.</p>
            <p><q>You may as well know this much at least</q>,			
<lb/>he said roughly. <q>The man you called a			
<lb/>coward won the Victoria Cross for an act of			
<lb/>sublime heroism during the war</q>.</p>
            <p>Hilda stood up. She looked beaten and			
<lb/>small. She was wrenching her hands to<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>gether as she backed toward the door. Her			
<lb/>lips were quivering. She tried to speak, but			
<lb/>the words could not come, and she shook her			
<lb/>head dumbly.</p>
            <p>The reporter, who probably understood hu<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>man nature far better than the average per<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>son, was touched by the girl’s evident misery.			
<lb/>He put his hand under Hilda’s arm, and			
<lb/>guided her to the door. There he said sooth<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ingly:</p>
            <p><q>Now, don’t worry. Everything’s all right,			
<lb/>and you’re in luck. We’re going to take him</q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 300 ]</fw>
            <pb n="301"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>on the paper. Fine job. He’ll make out great.			
<lb/>So, don’t worry. First thing in the morning			
<lb/>we'll be off, and you can depend upon me to do			
<lb/>the best I can for him. He’s a darned good			
<lb/>pal.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 30 ]</fw>
            <pb n="302"/>
         </div>