<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="chapter" n="17">
            <head>Chapter XVII</head>
            <p><hi rendition="#smallcaps">THE</hi> news fled like a prairie fire. From			
<lb/>ranch to ranch, from the trading stores that			
<lb/>dotted the foothill country, up to Banff, where			
<lb/>P. D.’s packhorses were carrying the tourists			
<lb/>into the supposed wilds of the Rocky Moun<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tains and down to the cowtown of Cochrane.			
<lb/>Here the news was received with consternation			
<lb/>and amazement.</p>
            <p>P. D.’s name was a household word. His			
<lb/>cattle, his grain, so ran the legend, had made			
<lb/>this part of the country famous throughout the			
<lb/>civilized world. And as for chess: The			
<lb/>country people knew but vaguely the meaning			
<lb/>of the word; but they did know at least that			
<lb/>it was associated in some illustrious way with			
<lb/>their distinguished neighbour, P. D. McPher<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>son. He was a Chess Champion. ‘<q>Cham<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>pion</q> was a name to conjure with. It put			
<lb/>P. D.’s name upon several occasions into the			
<lb/>newspapers; in obscure parts where they</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 196 ]</fw>
            <pb n="197"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>printed riddles and conundrums and funny			
<lb/>stuff for children, but also whenever P. D.’s			
<lb/>exploits at the cattle fairs were summed up			
<lb/>in the local press, and his picture appeared			
<lb/>on the front page and he gave out interviews			
<lb/>predicting the ruin of the country or its as<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>cendancy above all other countries in the			
<lb/>world, there was always a line included about			
<lb/>P. D. being the Chess Champion of Western			
<lb/>Canada and potential champion of all of Can<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ada.</p>
            <p>Even the riders on the range and the crews			
<lb/>at the road and lumber camps stopped each			
<lb/>other to gossip about the incredulous news.</p>
            <p><q>Did you hear about P. D.?</q> one would in<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>quire.</p>
            <p><q>No, what about him?</q></p>
            <p><q>He got beat. Beat at chess</q>.</p>
            <p><q>G’wan!</q></p>
            <p><q>Sure did</q>.</p>
            <p><q>You don’t say. Who done it? Betchu			
<lb/>some Yank come on over from the States,			
<lb/>huhe</q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 197 ]</fw>
            <pb n="198"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p><q>Not on your life. One of his own men			
<lb/>done it</q>.</p>
            <p><q>G’wan! Who?</q></p>
            <p><q>Well, that English fly, the Cheerio Duke			
<lb/>they call him, the one they picked off the			
<lb/>road in July—he licked the pants off P. D</q>.</p>
            <p><q>You don’t say. Him! Why, he’s nothing			
<lb/>but a tenderfoot. He don’t know nothing</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Don’t he, though! That’s where you're off			
<lb/>your bat. What he don’t know, ain’t worth			
<lb/>knowing, believe me</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Well, you hear all sorts o’ tales about him.			
<lb/>Who is he, anyway?</q></p>
            <p><q>Dunno, and nobody else does. But one			
<lb/>thing’s sure, he licked P. D. Licked him the			
<lb/>first time they played, and he’s kept it up every			
<lb/>night since. They’s a bet on. He’s to hold			
<lb/>his job till P. D. licks him, and from the looks			
<lb/>of things, pears like he’s got a permanent job.			
<lb/>And say— I heard that the old man ses he			
<lb/>ain’t goin’ over to the States to play for cham<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>pionship there until he’s trimmed Cheerio			
<lb/>chap</q>.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 198 ]</fw>
            <pb n="199"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p><q>IT want to know! The Calgary Blizzard			
<lb/>had a whole column "bout him goin’ over to			
<lb/>the States to beat the Champion there</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Well, he’s got his hands full right here</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Guess Pll ride over and take a look-in at			
<lb/>O Bar</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Not a chance. Say, the old man’s sore			
<lb/>as a dog. Ain’t lettin’ a soul into the house.			
<lb/>Has himself shut in and ain’t taking a bite of			
<lb/>air and hardly any eats. Just gone plumb			
<lb/>crazy on that chess game. It’s something like			
<lb/>checkers, only it ain’t the same. You got to			
<lb/>use your nut to play it</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Well, here’s to old P. D. Hope he wins</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Flere’s to him, as you say, but he ain’t got			
<lb/>a chance. That Cheerio duke ain’t no ama<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>choor</q>.</p>
            <p>Alberta, as all the world is beginning to			
<lb/>know, is a gambler’s paradise. In this great			
<lb/>boom land, where every day brings its new			
<lb/>discoveries of gold, oil, coal, silver, salts, plat<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>inum and all the minerals this world of ours			
<lb/>hides within herself, one tosses a penny on life			
<lb/>itself. From all parts of the world come peo-</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 199 ]</fw>
            <pb n="200"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>ple whose lives and hopes are dependent upon			
<lb/>games of chance, be they of the board, a pack			
<lb/>of cards, the stock market, the oil fields or the			
<lb/>great gamble of the land. Gambling is in<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>stinctive and intuitive in Alberta. A chance			
<lb/>is taken on anything. The man in the city			
<lb/>and the man upon the land throwing the dice			
<lb/>of fate upon the*soil are equally concerned			
<lb/>in gambling.</p>
            <p>Cheerio’s proposition, therefore, and the			
<lb/>way in which it was rumoured he continued to			
<lb/>beat the veteran chess player appealed to the			
<lb/>sporting sense of the country. It was not long			
<lb/>before money was up and bets were on the			
<lb/>players. News of the game swept down			
<lb/>finally to Calgary, and a sporting editor dis<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>patched a reporter upon the job. The reporter			
<lb/>liked his assignment first rate, since it included			
<lb/>a trip into the foothills and an indefinite leave			
<lb/>of absence. He was not, however, received			
<lb/>with open arms at O Bar O.</p>
            <p>Hilda, when he revealed the fact that he			
<lb/>was a reporter, snapped the screen door closed,			
<lb/>and only after the most diplomatic argument</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 200 ]</fw>
            <pb n="201"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>on the part of the newspaper man finally con<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>sented to announce his presence at O Bar O			
<lb/>to her father.</p>
            <p><q>Just tell him</q>, said the reporter, <q>that I			
<lb/>only want a word or two from him, and I'll			
<lb/>not print a line that he doesn’t approve of</q>.</p>
            <p>To this perfectly amicable message, P. D.			
<lb/>(invisible but plainly heard shouting his ex<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>plosive reply) returned:</p>
            <p><q>No, G— D— it. Tl see no snooping, spy<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing, G— D— reporter. I'll have none of ’em			
<lb/>on my place. I'll have ’em thrown off. This			
<lb/>is no public place, and I’ll have no G— D—			
<lb/>reporter trespassing upon my G~— D— pri<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>vacy</q>.</p>
            <p>Hilda, back at the screen door:</p>
            <p><q>My father says he doesn’t want to see you,			
<lb/>and if I were you, I’d beat it, because we’ve			
<lb/>got some pretty husky men on this place and			
<lb/>you don’t look any too strong. There’s no			
<lb/>telling what might happen to you, you know</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Will you just ask your father, then, if he			
<lb/>will give me, through you, a statement as to			
<lb/>the chances of Canada winning the World</q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 201 ]</fw>
            <pb n="202"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>Championship, either through him or his			
<lb/>present opponent. What we are chiefly in<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>terested in—that is to say, the readers of the			
<lb/>Calgary Blizzard—is whether or not we are			
<lb/>to have the Cup for Canada. It doesn’t mat<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ter whether Mr. McPherson or his opponent			
<lb/>gets it for us.</p>
            <p><q>Oh, doesn’t it, though!</q> Hilda could have			
<lb/>hit him with pleasure. So it didn’t matter			
<lb/>to the big, heartless public whether her Dad			
<lb/>or that Englishman won or not.</p>
            <p><q>Well, would you mind asking your father			
<lb/>just that?</q></p>
            <p>Hilda, inside:</p>
            <p><q>Dad, he wants to know whether either you			
<lb/>or—him</q> (Hilda referred always to Cheerio			
<lb/>as <q>him</q> or <q>he</q>) <q>will be going to Chicago			
<lb/>for the tournament now</q>.</p>
            <p><q>You tell that bloody young news hound			
<lb/>that he’ll do well to clear off the place in a			
<lb/>damn quick hurry, or we’ll make it a damned			
<lb/>sight hotter for him than the place he’s even<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>tually headed for</q>.</p>
            <p>Hilda, back at screen door:</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 202 ]</fw>
            <pb n="203"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p><q>My father says for you to clear off the			
<lb/>place, and I advise you to, too. You’ve a			
<lb/>nerve to come here to get stuff to print against			
<lb/>my father in the paper. I'd just like to see			
<lb/>you dare to print anything about us. It’s none			
<lb/>of the newspapers’ business, and my father			
<lb/>will win, anyway</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Thank you. I’m glad to have that line on			
<lb/>the game. Did he win last night?</q></p>
            <p><q>I’m not going to answer a single question.			
<lb/>We don’t want a single thing to get in the			
<lb/>papers</q>.</p>
            <p><q>But it’s already been in the paper</q>.</p>
            <p><q>What?</q></p>
            <p><q>Here you are—half a column story</q>.</p>
            <p>Hilda came out on to the porch, and seized			
<lb/>and scanned the paper. Her face burned as			
<lb/>she read, and the hot, angry tears arose in her			
<lb/>eyes. How dared they publish for all the			
<lb/>world to read that her old dad was being			
<lb/>beaten each night by that Englishman? She			
<lb/>whirled around on the inoffensive reporter.</p>
            <p><q>Who wrote that beastly stuff? It’s a</q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 203 ]</fw>
            <pb n="204"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>damned shame. Just goes to show what your			
<lb/>old newspapers are. Did you write it?</p>
            <p><q>No, no</q>, hastily denied the reporter. <q>TI			
<lb/>was only assigned to the job to-day. That’s			
<lb/>some outside stuff telephoned in, probably by			
<lb/>one of your neighbours. I’m here to follow			
<lb/>up—to get a special story, in fact. And look			
<lb/>here, Miss McPherson—you’re Miss McPher<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>son, aren’t your—well, look here, it’s better			
<lb/>for us to get the dope directly from yourselves			
<lb/>than have to make it up. I’m here to get a			
<lb/>story, and I’m going to get it</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Well, let me tell you, you’ll have some			
<lb/>sweet time getting it</q>.</p>
            <p><q>T intend to stay here till I do</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Here on our steps? I’d like to see you</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Well, not exactly on the steps—but on the			
<lb/>job, at all events. I’l] camp down the road			
<lb/>by the river, and I can cover the story just			
<lb/>as well from there</q>.</p>
            <p>Hilda threw him a look of withering scorn.			
<lb/>Pushed the screen door open, and banged it,			
<lb/>as well as the inside door, in the reporter’s			
<lb/>face.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 204 ]</fw>
            <pb n="205"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>He stood in thought a moment on the steps			
<lb/>and then he jotted down:</p>
            <p><q>Beautiful young daughter of P. D.			
<lb/>McPherson on guard over father. In<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>herits famous disposition. Declares that			
<lb/>her father will win. Intimates that he,			
<lb/>not his hitherto victorious opponent, will			
<lb/>go to Chicago——</q></p>
            <p>At this juncture, and while he was jotting			
<lb/>down the notes anent Hilda McPherson,			
<lb/>Cheerio came up the steps and crossed the			
<lb/>verandah toward the front door, followed by			
<lb/>Sandy, who, much to the bitter indignation			
<lb/>of his sister, was once again the Englishman’s			
<lb/>satellite and admirer.</p>
            <p><q>Good evening</q>, said the reporter, cor<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>dially.</p>
            <p><q>Hello!</q> returned the unsuspicious Cheerio,			
<lb/>and returned the grip of the newspaper man’s			
<lb/>hand.</p>
            <p><q>T wonder if you could give me some infor<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>mation about this Englishman who’s playing</q></p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 205 ]</fw>
            <pb n="206"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>opposite Mr. P. D. McPherson for the West<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ern Championship and 			
<lb/><q>Wh-wh-wh-wh-wh-what f-f-for?</q> stam<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>mered Cheerio, taken aback by the question.			
<lb/><q>I’m from the Calgary Blizzard and-——</q>			
<lb/><q>G-g-g-good God!			
<lb/></q><q>Tf you know the man who——~</q>			
<lb/><q>Gee! He’s him hisself!</q> chortled Sandy.			
<lb/>Cheerio was punching the electric bell per<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>sistently. Hilda, hurrying at the summons,			
<lb/>opened the door inside, cast a haughty look			
<lb/>from the reporter to Cheerio, and then reluct<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>antly unhooked the latch and let the latter in.			
<lb/>She closed both doors again with a snap.			
<lb/>Sandy, who had not followed Cheerio into			
<lb/>the house, stood grinning up at the reporter,			
<lb/>and the latter was seized with an inspiration.			
<lb/>He returned the jeering stare of P. D.’s son			
<lb/>with a man-to-man look of confidence. Non<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>chalantly, he brought forth a cigarette case			
<lb/>and, extending it carelessly to Sandy, invited			
<lb/>him to have one. Sandy, whose young lips			
<lb/>had never touched the forbidden weed, helped</p>
            <p>himself with ostentatious carelessness and even</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 206 ]</fw>
            <pb n="207"/>
            <fw type="pageHeading">His Royal Nibs</fw>
            <p>accepted the light tendered from the other’s			
<lb/>half finished stub.</p>
            <p><q>In a hurry?</q> asked the newspaper man.</p>
            <p><q>Nope</q>.</p>
            <p><q>Suppose we sit over here</q>.</p>
            <p>The reporter indicated the steps, and Sandy			
<lb/>leaned back against the pillar with the cig<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>arette alternately between his two fingers or			
<lb/>between his young lips.</p>
            <p><q>You’re P. D. McPherson’s son, are you			
<lb/>note</q></p>
            <p><q>Veh</q>,</p>
            <p><q>Well, what about this Englishman? I</q></p>
            <p>wonder if you can tell me something about			
<lb/></p>
            <p>him.</p>
            <p><q>Sure</q>, said Sandy, ignoring a sudden quak<pc force="weak">-</pc>			
<lb/>ing at the pit of his stomach, and blowing out			
<lb/>an elaborate whiff of smoke. <q>Sure, I c’n tell			
<lb/>you all about him</q>.</p>
            <fw type="pageNum">[ 207 ]</fw>
            <pb n="208"/>
         </div>